[{"Question":"How many countries border San Marino?","CorrectAnswer":"1","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"4","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"With how many countries does the US share a land border?","CorrectAnswer":"2","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"1","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many faces has the clock on Big Ben's tower?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"1","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many hours behind Greenwich Mean Time is California?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"12","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many fountains are found in the gardens at the Palace of Versailles? ","CorrectAnswer":"1.400","Answer2":"140 ","Answer3":"14","Answer4":"14.000","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many candles were used to light the Hall of Mirrors in the Palace of Versailles?    ","CorrectAnswer":"3.000","Answer2":"300","Answer3":"33.000","Answer4":"333.000","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"On a clear day how far can one see from the observation platform of the Empire State Building?","CorrectAnswer":"130 km","Answer2":"3 km","Answer3":"30 km","Answer4":"630  km","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Peter Minuit of the Dutch West India Company bought Manhattan island from the local indians in 1626 with cloth, trinkets and beads worth the equivalent  of what?","CorrectAnswer":"24 dollars","Answer2":"24 cents","Answer3":"240 dollars","Answer4":"2,400 dollars","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which European city is Schiphol airport?","CorrectAnswer":"Amsterdam","Answer2":"Budapest","Answer3":"Warsaw","Answer4":"Athens","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where is Dam Square?","CorrectAnswer":"Amsterdam","Answer2":"Berlin","Answer3":"Copenhagen","Answer4":"Darmstadt","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city can one visit the Palace of the Popes?","CorrectAnswer":"Avignon","Answer2":"Rome","Answer3":"Nancy","Answer4":"Madrid","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The jade green waters of Lake Louise are found in which national park?","CorrectAnswer":"Banff, Canada","Answer2":"Kruger, South Africa","Answer3":"Serengeti, Tanzania","Answer4":"Yellowstone, USA","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which county can one find Luton Airport?","CorrectAnswer":"Bedfordshire","Answer2":"Hertfordshire","Answer3":"Kent","Answer4":"Essex","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"With 196 tonnes, the heaviest what ever built is found within the walls of the Kremlin?","CorrectAnswer":"bell","Answer2":"gold bar","Answer3":"cannon ball","Answer4":"statue","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Since 1981, Mumbai is the official name for which Indian city?","CorrectAnswer":"Bombay","Answer2":"Calcutta","Answer3":"Delhi","Answer4":"Bangalore","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The name of which capital city is the Latin word for a red dye wood?","CorrectAnswer":"Brasilia","Answer2":"Vienna","Answer3":"Berlin","Answer4":"Rome","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where in London can one view the Magna Carta and the Rosetta Stone?","CorrectAnswer":"British Museum","Answer2":"Tate Gallery","Answer3":"National Gallery","Answer4":"Tower of London","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"With 40 tonnes, the largest what ever built is found within the walls of the Kremlin?","CorrectAnswer":"cannon","Answer2":"crucifix","Answer3":"chandelier","Answer4":"chalice","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where is the Astronaut Hall of Fame located?","CorrectAnswer":"Cape Canaveral","Answer2":"Washington","Answer3":"Houston","Answer4":"New York","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city can one board the luxurious 'Blue Train'?","CorrectAnswer":"Cape Town","Answer2":"Edinburgh","Answer3":"Vancouver","Answer4":"Istanbul","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city does the National Assembly of Wales sit?","CorrectAnswer":"Cardiff","Answer2":"Newport","Answer3":"Swansea","Answer4":"St. Davids","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which London street does one associate with the 1960s fashion scene?","CorrectAnswer":"Carnaby","Answer2":"Fleet","Answer3":"Threadneedle","Answer4":"Pall Mall","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city is the world famous Sears Tower skyscraper located?","CorrectAnswer":"Chicago","Answer2":"New York","Answer3":"Boston","Answer4":"Detroit","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many litres of beer are consumed each year at the Oktoberfest in Munich?","CorrectAnswer":"circa 6,000,000","Answer2":" circa 60,000,000","Answer3":"circa 600,000","Answer4":"circa 60,000","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which metal was used to construct the outside hull of the Statue of Liberty?","CorrectAnswer":"copper","Answer2":"brass","Answer3":"silver","Answer4":"iron","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city is the world famous Burg Al Arab skyscraper located?","CorrectAnswer":"Dubai","Answer2":"Cairo","Answer3":"Tehran","Answer4":"Kuwait City","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which language is Afrikaans derived from?","CorrectAnswer":"Dutch","Answer2":"German","Answer3":"Spanish","Answer4":"English","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The Royal Mile is a famous street in which capital city?","CorrectAnswer":"Edinburgh","Answer2":"Ottawa","Answer3":"London","Answer4":"Dublin","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which European capital has the nickname 'The Athens of the north'?","CorrectAnswer":"Edinburgh","Answer2":"Paris","Answer3":"Berlin","Answer4":"Helsinki","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Famine in which country triggered the Band Aid Charity?","CorrectAnswer":"Ethiopia","Answer2":"Sudan","Answer3":"South Africa","Answer4":"Zimbabwe","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which country's postage stamps bear the inscription ","CorrectAnswer":"Finland","Answer2":"Sweden","Answer3":"Denmark","Answer4":"Norway","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The Uffizien museum, a feast for the eyes for lovers of Renaissance paintings, is located in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Florence","Answer2":"Rome","Answer3":"Vatican City","Answer4":"Milan","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Whose upper house of Parliament is called the Bundesrat?","CorrectAnswer":"Germany's","Answer2":"Belgium's","Answer3":"France's","Answer4":"Spain's","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the name of the film prize awarded each year at the Venice film festival?","CorrectAnswer":"Golden Lion","Answer2":"Golden Bear","Answer3":"Golden Eagle","Answer4":"Golden Star","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which country is the harbour city Mumbai?","CorrectAnswer":"India","Answer2":"China","Answer3":"Senegal","Answer4":"Japan","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city is the world famous skyscraper Petronas Towers located?","CorrectAnswer":"Kuala Lumpur","Answer2":"Shanghai","Answer3":"New York","Answer4":"Dubai","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"It is said that the residents of which European capital never sleep?","CorrectAnswer":"Madrid","Answer2":"Oslo","Answer3":"Warsaw","Answer4":"Dublin","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city is the famous Prado museum?","CorrectAnswer":"Madrid","Answer2":"St Petersburg","Answer3":"Florence","Answer4":"Vatican","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which destination for 60s hippies has been called the Paris of the Sahara?  ","CorrectAnswer":"Marrakesh","Answer2":"Tripolis","Answer3":"Cairo","Answer4":"Luxor","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The German city of Lübeck is world famous for which product?","CorrectAnswer":"marzipan","Answer2":"pickled herring","Answer3":"sauerkraut","Answer4":"Frankfurters","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"GUM is the world famous dept store in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Moscow","Answer2":"New York","Answer3":"Paris","Answer4":"Tokyo","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which famous castle was the inspiration for the Disney theme park castle?","CorrectAnswer":"Neuschwanstein Castle","Answer2":"Edinburgh Castle","Answer3":"Windsor Castle","Answer4":"Mount Saint Michel Castle","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city is the world famous Chrysler Building skyscraper located?","CorrectAnswer":"New York","Answer2":"Chicago","Answer3":"San Francisco ","Answer4":"Detroit","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city is the world famous Woolworth Building skyscraper located?","CorrectAnswer":"New York","Answer2":"London","Answer3":"Chicago","Answer4":"Boston","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which country can one find the Giant's Causeway?","CorrectAnswer":"Northern Ireland","Answer2":"Scotland","Answer3":"France","Answer4":"Canada","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The famous 'Lake Palace' in India, once a summer residence for royalty and now a luxury hotel, was the setting  for which action film? ","CorrectAnswer":"Octopussy","Answer2":"Star Wars. The Empire Strikes Back","Answer3":"Mission Impossible II","Answer4":"Crouching Tiger, Hidden Dragon","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which capital city is the Roland Garos stadium?","CorrectAnswer":"Paris","Answer2":"Prague","Answer3":"Madrid","Answer4":"Budapest","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The victory goddess Victoria and her chariot on the top of the Brandenburger Gate in Berlin spent the years between 1806 and 1814 in which capital city?","CorrectAnswer":"Paris","Answer2":"London","Answer3":"Moscow","Answer4":"Rome","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The Emperors Palace or Forbidden City is located in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Peking","Answer2":"Shanghai","Answer3":"Hong Kong","Answer4":"Xi'an","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The Cathedral of our Lady in Antwerp contains four masterpieces depicting Biblical scenes by which famous Baroque painter?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Paul Rubens","Answer2":"Vincent van Gogh","Answer3":"Raffael","Answer4":"Rembrandt","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The 'Liberty Bell' is found in which US city?","CorrectAnswer":"Philadelphia","Answer2":"Washington","Answer3":"New York","Answer4":"Boston","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which harbour city is Lord Nelson's flagship HMS Victory?","CorrectAnswer":"Portsmouth","Answer2":"Plymouth","Answer3":"Bristol","Answer4":"Liverpool","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The longest bridge built in the middleages in Europe, the Charles Bridge, is located in which capital city?","CorrectAnswer":"Prague","Answer2":"London","Answer3":"Paris","Answer4":"Oslo","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What creature appears on the Welsh national flag?","CorrectAnswer":"Red dragon","Answer2":"Yellow dafffodil","Answer3":"Green leek","Answer4":"White sheep","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which city has the nickname 'Venice of the north'?","CorrectAnswer":"St Petersburg","Answer2":"Montreal","Answer3":"Glasgow","Answer4":"Helsinki","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which famous city, sometimes called the Venice of the north, was built on 12 islands?","CorrectAnswer":"St Petersburg","Answer2":"Glasgow","Answer3":"Ottawa","Answer4":"Oslo","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the name of the famous mountain that overlooks Cape Town, South Africa?","CorrectAnswer":"Table","Answer2":"Plate","Answer3":"Chalice","Answer4":"Divan","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which famous buiding did Catherine the Great keep her private art collection?","CorrectAnswer":"The Eremitage","Answer2":"The Kremlin","Answer3":"The Summer Palace","Answer4":"The Bolshoi Theatre","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Niagara Falls Canada, where the awe inspiring Horseshoe Falls is located, has been given which nickname?    ","CorrectAnswer":"The Honeymoon City","Answer2":"The Misty City","Answer3":"The Windy City","Answer4":"The City of Lights","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which golf course is called 'the home of golf'?","CorrectAnswer":"The Royal and Ancient Golf Club St Andrews","Answer2":"Gleneagles","Answer3":"Pebble Beach","Answer4":"Sunningdale","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Hadrian's Wall was built in order to keep which wild men out of the Roman Empire?","CorrectAnswer":"The Scots","Answer2":"The Welsh","Answer3":"The Vikings","Answer4":"The Mongols","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The Potala Palace was once the winter residence for which man? ","CorrectAnswer":"The Dalai Lama","Answer2":"Pu  Li","Answer3":"Kubla Khan","Answer4":"El Cid","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which city is the CN Tower, the tallest free standing structure in the world?","CorrectAnswer":"Toronto","Answer2":"Chicago","Answer3":"Hong Kong","Answer4":"Moscow","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The 'Book of Kells', a 1,300 year old masterpiece of western calligraphy, is found in which university?","CorrectAnswer":"Trinity College, Dublin","Answer2":" Oxford","Answer3":"Cambridge","Answer4":"Sorbonne, Paris  ","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Angel Falls, the worlds highest waterfall is located in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Venezuela","Answer2":"Zambia","Answer3":"Canada","Answer4":"Switzerland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":" In which city is the famous Bridge of Sighs?","CorrectAnswer":"Venice","Answer2":"Paris","Answer3":"Rome","Answer4":"Prague","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which Canadian provincial capital is nicknamed 'Little England'?","CorrectAnswer":"Victoria","Answer2":"Toronto","Answer3":"Quebec City","Answer4":"Halifax","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The Taj Mahal was constructed with which material?","CorrectAnswer":"White Marble","Answer2":"White Granite","Answer3":"White Ivory","Answer4":"White Opals","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which US national park is the geysir named 'Old Faithful' located?","CorrectAnswer":"Yellowstone","Answer2":"Banff","Answer3":"Grand Teton","Answer4":"Bryce Canyon","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many bridges are there over the firth of fourth?","CorrectAnswer":"2","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"1","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many American states begin and end with the letter 'A'?","CorrectAnswer":"3","Answer2":"4","Answer3":"5","Answer4":"2","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many time zones are there in the USA?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"1","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the unlucky number in China?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"13","Answer3":"7","Answer4":"33","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many stories high is the Empire State building?","CorrectAnswer":"102","Answer2":"62","Answer3":"162","Answer4":"202","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the population of the Czech Rep?","CorrectAnswer":"10.3 million","Answer2":"4.5 million","Answer3":"57.6 million","Answer4":"80.2 million","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Angel Falls, the highest waterfall in the world is how many times higher than the Niagara Falls?","CorrectAnswer":"15X","Answer2":"5X","Answer3":"2X","Answer4":"25X","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How much does the Petersglocke, the worlds heaviest church bell in the Cologne Cathedral weigh ?","CorrectAnswer":"24 tonnes","Answer2":"4 tonnes","Answer3":"240 tonnes","Answer4":"124 tonnes","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"To the nearest million, what was the population of Wales in 2001?","CorrectAnswer":"3 million","Answer2":"1 million","Answer3":"5 million","Answer4":"10 million","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the cozy interior temperature in the world famous Ice Hotel in Jukkasjärvi Sweden?","CorrectAnswer":"-5° C to -8°C","Answer2":"-13°C to -16°C","Answer3":"0°C to -3°C","Answer4":"-27°C to -30°C","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the population of Iran?","CorrectAnswer":"71.4 million","Answer2":"3.8 million","Answer3":"33.5 million","Answer4":"144.5 million","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the population of Vietnam?","CorrectAnswer":"78.8 million","Answer2":"10.1 million","Answer3":"39.9 million","Answer4":"123.3 million","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Lake Assal is the lowest point on which continent?","CorrectAnswer":"Africa","Answer2":"Asia","Answer3":"Australia","Answer4":"Antarctic","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where do the largest vegetables in the US grow?","CorrectAnswer":"Alaska","Answer2":"Hawaii","Answer3":"Florida","Answer4":"New Mexico","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the name of the famous ancient temple city in the jungle of Cambodia?","CorrectAnswer":"Angkor Wat","Answer2":"Penang","Answer3":"Amanwana","Answer4":"Yogyakarta","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Chrysler Building in New York City is an example of which style of architecture?","CorrectAnswer":"Art Deco","Answer2":"Byzantine","Answer3":"Post Modernism","Answer4":"Baroque","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Sagrada Familia Cathedral in Barcelona is an example of which style of architecture?","CorrectAnswer":"Art Nouveau","Answer2":"Neo Gothic","Answer3":"Renaissance","Answer4":"Romanesque","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Lake Eyre is the lowest point on which continent?","CorrectAnswer":"Australia","Answer2":"Europe","Answer3":"North America","Answer4":"Antarctic","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Gibson desert is found in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Australia","Answer2":"South Africa","Answer3":"Canada","Answer4":"USA","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Poland?","CorrectAnswer":"Austria","Answer2":"Slovakia","Answer3":"Germany","Answer4":"Lithuania","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Palace of Versailles is an example of which style of architecture?","CorrectAnswer":"Baroque","Answer2":"Romanesque","Answer3":"Greek","Answer4":"Gothic","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"St Paul's Cathedral in London is an example of which style of architecture?","CorrectAnswer":"Baroque","Answer2":"Art Deco","Answer3":"Gothic","Answer4":"Neo Classical","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the only breed of dog that is allowed to testify in a US courtroom?","CorrectAnswer":"Bloodhound","Answer2":"Poodle","Answer3":"German Shepard","Answer4":"Collie","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Until 1763, Salvador de Bahia was the capital of which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Brazil","Answer2":"Spain","Answer3":"Mexico","Answer4":"Portugal","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Hagia Sophia in Istanbul is an example of which style of architecture?","CorrectAnswer":"Byzantine","Answer2":"Roman","Answer3":"Gothic","Answer4":"Greek","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Bay of Fundy is off the coast of which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Canada","Answer2":"Australia","Answer3":"New Zealand","Answer4":"South Africa","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The name of which capital city stems from the native word for 'meeting place'?","CorrectAnswer":"Canberra, Australia","Answer2":"Paris, France","Answer3":"Ottawa, Canada","Answer4":"Edinburgh, Scotland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the name of the 13th century spa city in the Czech Rep. that attracted the likes of Chopin, Beethoven, Bach and King Edward VII?","CorrectAnswer":"Carlsbad","Answer2":"Spa","Answer3":"Baden Baden","Answer4":"Bad Gastein","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country has only one time zone?","CorrectAnswer":"China","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"Russia","Answer4":"Brazil","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country has the largest army in the world?","CorrectAnswer":"China","Answer2":"North Korea","Answer3":"India","Answer4":"USA","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which contemporary artist wrapped up the Reichstag in Berlin with 100,000 m2 of polypropylene fabric in the summer of 1995?","CorrectAnswer":"Christo","Answer2":"Yoko Ono","Answer3":"H.R. Giger","Answer4":"Andy Warhol","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"When did the construction of the  Pyramids of Giseh first begin?  ","CorrectAnswer":"circa 2500 BC","Answer2":" circa 5500 BC","Answer3":"circa 500 BC","Answer4":"circa 50 BC","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Grand Place or main market square in Brussels hosts the 'flower carpet' festival each August. How many begonias are used?","CorrectAnswer":"circa 700,000","Answer2":"circa 7,000,000","Answer3":"circa 70,000","Answer4":"circa 7,000","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which cathedral is the Petersglocke, the worlds largest church bell?","CorrectAnswer":"Cologne","Answer2":"St Peters, Vatican City","Answer3":"Canterbury","Answer4":"Durham","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Bolivia?","CorrectAnswer":"Colombia","Answer2":"Brazil","Answer3":"Peru","Answer4":"Chile","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Greece?","CorrectAnswer":"Croatia","Answer2":"Turkey","Answer3":"Albania","Answer4":"Bulgaria","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Banana is a harbour city in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Dem Rep of Congo","Answer2":"Brazil","Answer3":"Indonesia","Answer4":"Colombia","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mount Elbrus is the highest point on which continent?","CorrectAnswer":"Europe","Answer2":"Asia","Answer3":"North America","Answer4":"Antarctic","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The world famous Oberammergau passion play in Bayern is held how often?","CorrectAnswer":"every 10 years","Answer2":"every year","Answer3":"every 50 years","Answer4":"every 2 years","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which city, famous for its ship building, was the ocean liner QE2  built?","CorrectAnswer":"Glasgow","Answer2":"Belfast","Answer3":"Southampton","Answer4":"Portsmouth","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"South Africa is the world's leading exporter of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Gold","Answer2":"Silver","Answer3":"Diamond","Answer4":"Platinum","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which railway station has the most platforms in the world?","CorrectAnswer":"Grand Central, New York","Answer2":"Waterloo, London","Answer3":"Frankfurt Main","Answer4":"Gare du Nord, Paris","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which strait seperates the Persian gulf and the gulf of Oman?","CorrectAnswer":"Hormuz","Answer2":"Bosporus","Answer3":"Malacca","Answer4":"Dardanelles","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What country does not border Afghanistan?","CorrectAnswer":"India","Answer2":"Pakistan","Answer3":"China","Answer4":"Uzbekistan","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where would you find the volcano named Krakatoa? ","CorrectAnswer":"Indonesia","Answer2":"Malaysia","Answer3":"China","Answer4":"India","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Dingle Bay is off the coast of which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Ireland","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"Australia","Answer4":"New Zealand","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which city in Turkey is located in Europe and in Asia?","CorrectAnswer":"Istanbul","Answer2":"Ankara","Answer3":"Dodomar","Answer4":"Pamukulai","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Montego Bay is off the coast of which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Jamaica","Answer2":"Barbados","Answer3":"Bermuda","Answer4":"Trinidad and Tobago","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where in New York City is the 'Canyon of Heroes', where the famous ticker tape parades take place?","CorrectAnswer":"Lower Broadway","Answer2":"Wall Street","Answer3":"Fifth Avenue","Answer4":"Times Square","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"According to the World Health Organisation which capital city has the worst air pollution?","CorrectAnswer":"Mexico City","Answer2":"London","Answer3":"Moscow","Answer4":"Cairo","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who designed the uniform worn by the Vatican City's Swiss Guard?","CorrectAnswer":"Michalangelo","Answer2":"Da Vinci","Answer3":"Raffael","Answer4":"Galileo","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Is The Most Densely Populated Country In Europe?","CorrectAnswer":"Monaco","Answer2":"Vatican City","Answer3":"Andorra","Answer4":"Luxembourg","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What do the citizens of Brussels love to eat with their frites (French fries)?","CorrectAnswer":"mussels","Answer2":"savoury sausage","Answer3":"eel","Answer4":"Brussel sprouts","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Houses Of Parliament in London is an example of which style of architecture?","CorrectAnswer":"Neo Gothic","Answer2":"Baroque","Answer3":"Gothic","Answer4":"Art Deco","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Dominion Parliament buildings in Ottawa are an example of which style of architecture?","CorrectAnswer":"Neo Gothic","Answer2":"Roman","Answer3":"Renaissance","Answer4":"Art Deco","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country is the mountain named Annapurna found?","CorrectAnswer":"Nepal","Answer2":"Argentina","Answer3":"Russia","Answer4":"Switzerland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which US state is Area 51?","CorrectAnswer":"Nevada","Answer2":"New Mexico","Answer3":"Texas","Answer4":"Arizona","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Bay of Plenty is off the coast of which country?","CorrectAnswer":"New Zealand","Answer2":"Australia","Answer3":"Canada","Answer4":"South Africa","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country is Mt Cook?","CorrectAnswer":"New Zealand","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"USA","Answer4":"Argentina","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Into which body of water does the Rhine river flow?","CorrectAnswer":"North Sea","Answer2":"Black sea","Answer3":"Caspian Sea","Answer4":"Baltic Sea","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country is there a town named 'Hell'?","CorrectAnswer":"Norway","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"Australia","Answer4":"Ireland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"On what river is the capital city of Canada?","CorrectAnswer":"Ottawa","Answer2":"Windigo","Answer3":"Winnipeg ","Answer4":"Montreal ","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The mysterious Inca city Machu Picchu is found in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Peru","Answer2":"Mexico","Answer3":"Chile","Answer4":"Colombia","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Austria?","CorrectAnswer":"Poland","Answer2":"Germany","Answer3":"Hungary","Answer4":"Czech Rep","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"With a capacity for 220,000 spectators, in which capital city is Strahov, the largest stadium in the world?","CorrectAnswer":"Prague","Answer2":" Moscow","Answer3":"Warsaw","Answer4":"Vienna","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which City would you find St. Peter's Basilica?","CorrectAnswer":"Rome","Answer2":"Madrid","Answer3":"St. Petersburg","Answer4":"Moscow","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Why was the Munich Oktoberfest cancelled in 1923 and 1924?","CorrectAnswer":"Runaway inflation","Answer2":"Civil war","Answer3":"Spanish flu","Answer4":"Brewery strike","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"When motoring west in which city does Route 66 end?","CorrectAnswer":"Santa Monica","Answer2":"LA","Answer3":"Oakland","Answer4":"San Francisco","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which city is the world famous Jin Mao skyscraper located?","CorrectAnswer":"Shanghai","Answer2":"Hong Kong","Answer3":"Beijing","Answer4":"Taipei","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which metal made the Bolivian city Potosi one of the richest cities in the world in the 17th century?","CorrectAnswer":"silver","Answer2":"gold","Answer3":"aluminium","Answer4":"copper","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country produces the most gold?","CorrectAnswer":"South Africa","Answer2":"Australia","Answer3":"Dem Rep Congo","Answer4":"Canada","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Valdes Peninsula is the lowest point on which continent?","CorrectAnswer":"South America","Answer2":"Europe","Answer3":"Antarctic","Answer4":"Australia","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mount Aconcagua is the highest point on which continent?","CorrectAnswer":"South America","Answer2":"Asia","Answer3":"Antarctic","Answer4":"Australia","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country is the harbour city Inchon?","CorrectAnswer":"South Korea","Answer2":"India","Answer3":"Brazil","Answer4":"Japan","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"50% of all the men on the Greek island Corfu have which first name?","CorrectAnswer":"Spiro","Answer2":"Achilles","Answer3":"Alexis","Answer4":"Stavros","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the name of the largest star sapphire in the world which is found in New York City's American Museum of Natural History?","CorrectAnswer":"Star of India","Answer2":"Star of Africa ","Answer3":"Star of Cairo","Answer4":"Star of Bethleham","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Luxembourg?","CorrectAnswer":"Switzerland","Answer2":"Germany","Answer3":"France","Answer4":"Belgium","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country is the mountain named Jungfrau found?","CorrectAnswer":"Switzerland","Answer2":"Italy","Answer3":"France","Answer4":"New Zealand  ","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country does not border South Africa?","CorrectAnswer":"Tanzania","Answer2":"Namibia","Answer3":"Swaziland","Answer4":"Lesotho","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Younge Street, the longest street in the world, begins in which Canadian city?","CorrectAnswer":"Toronto","Answer2":"Montreal","Answer3":"Vancouver","Answer4":"Quebec City","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The ruins of ancient Carthage are found in the suburbs of which modern city?","CorrectAnswer":"Tunis","Answer2":"Cairo","Answer3":"Tripolis","Answer4":"Beirut","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which African country is not a monarchy?","CorrectAnswer":"Tunisia","Answer2":"Morocco","Answer3":"Swaziland","Answer4":"Lesotho","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country is Mt Ararat?","CorrectAnswer":"Turkey","Answer2":"Russia","Answer3":"Nepal","Answer4":"Switzerland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Turkey?","CorrectAnswer":"Turkmenistan","Answer2":"Bulgaria","Answer3":"Iran","Answer4":"Iraq","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where does a Halbardier Gaurdsman work?","CorrectAnswer":"Vatican","Answer2":"Tower of London","Answer3":"Mt Olympus","Answer4":"Swiss Border","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The oldest film festival in the world takes place in which European city?","CorrectAnswer":"Venice","Answer2":"Cannes","Answer3":"Berlin","Answer4":"Edinburgh","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which goddess of victory is riding a chariot on the Brandenberger Gate in Berlin?","CorrectAnswer":"Victoria","Answer2":"Athena","Answer3":"Nike","Answer4":"Brunhilda","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is Europe's longest river? ","CorrectAnswer":"Volga","Answer2":"Danube","Answer3":"Rhine","Answer4":"Rhone","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which countries name stems from the Germanic word for foreign?","CorrectAnswer":"Wales","Answer2":"Spain","Answer3":"Germany","Answer4":"Poland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"With 1,000 plus rooms, what is the largest inhabited castle in the world?","CorrectAnswer":"Windsor Castle","Answer2":"The Alhambra","Answer3":"Warwich Castle","Answer4":"Edinburgh Castle","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"During a WWII air raid the firemen in Freiburg im Breisgau used what to put out the fire in the historic Kaufhaus after they ran out of water?","CorrectAnswer":"wine","Answer2":"schnapps","Answer3":"beer","Answer4":"milk","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many months does the average American spend in a lifetime waiting at a red light?","CorrectAnswer":"6","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"12","Answer4":"18","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many countries lie between Mexico and Colombia?","CorrectAnswer":"7","Answer2":"10","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"5","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many hours a month does the average American spend in a shopping mall?","CorrectAnswer":"12","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"24","Answer4":"48","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many countries border Russia?","CorrectAnswer":"14","Answer2":"8","Answer3":"25","Answer4":"19","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many countries border China?","CorrectAnswer":"16","Answer2":"10","Answer3":"26","Answer4":"7","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many people live on Ellesmere Island, the 10th largest island in the world?","CorrectAnswer":"106","Answer2":"1.106","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"10.106","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many rooms are there in the White House?","CorrectAnswer":"132","Answer2":"32","Answer3":"72","Answer4":"272","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many lakes are there in Finland?","CorrectAnswer":"187.880","Answer2":"8.880","Answer3":"87.880","Answer4":"887.880","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"According to the UN how many people in the world are starving?","CorrectAnswer":"820,000,000","Answer2":"1.5 billion","Answer3":"82,000,000","Answer4":"420,000,000","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Most sources claim that Route 66 is how many miles all the way?","CorrectAnswer":"2,448 miles","Answer2":"2,848 miles","Answer3":"1,848 miles","Answer4":"3,448 miles","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"To the nearest thousand square kilometres what is the land area of Wales?","CorrectAnswer":"21,000 sq km","Answer2":"5,000 sq km","Answer3":"51,000 sq km","Answer4":"100,100 sq km","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the population of Saudi Arabia?","CorrectAnswer":"22.million","Answer2":"123.3 million","Answer3":"3.2 million","Answer4":"65.2 million","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The salt content in the Dead Sea which enables a swimmer to float like a cork is how many times higher than that of the Atlantic ocean?","CorrectAnswer":"7X","Answer2":"2X","Answer3":"22X","Answer4":"77x","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The Bridge of Sighs in Venice connected  the Doge's Palace with what?","CorrectAnswer":"A state prison and place of execution","Answer2":"A tax office","Answer3":"A hospital","Answer4":"A Turkish bath house","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which European city is nicknamed the 'Granite City'?","CorrectAnswer":"Aberdeen","Answer2":"The Vatican","Answer3":"Lisbon","Answer4":"Munich","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The crown of the Empire State building was originally built for which purpose?","CorrectAnswer":"airship dock","Answer2":"firemans lookout","Answer3":"flag pole","Answer4":"weather station","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The Vinson Massive is the highest point on which continent?","CorrectAnswer":"Antarctic","Answer2":"Europe","Answer3":"Australia","Answer4":"South America","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country is the mountain named Aconcagua found?","CorrectAnswer":"Argentina","Answer2":"Mexico","Answer3":"Nepal","Answer4":"Switzerland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country produces the most opals?","CorrectAnswer":"Australia","Answer2":"India","Answer3":"USA","Answer4":"Russia","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Mount Kosciusko is the highest point on which continent?","CorrectAnswer":"Australia","Answer2":"Europe","Answer3":"Antarctic","Answer4":"Africa","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Red, as in Red Square, was the old Slavic synonym for what?","CorrectAnswer":"beauty","Answer2":"power","Answer3":"wealth","Answer4":"death","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Into which body of water does the Danube river flow?","CorrectAnswer":"Black Sea","Answer2":"North Sea","Answer3":"Baltic Sea","Answer4":"Caspian Sea","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country does not have a bird on its flag?","CorrectAnswer":"Brazil","Answer2":"Mexico","Answer3":"Eygpt","Answer4":"Dominican Rep","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which county is chequers, the prime ministers country residence?","CorrectAnswer":"Buckinghamshire","Answer2":"Surrey","Answer3":"Middlesex","Answer4":"Oxfordshire","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Lake Tahoe is on the border of Nevada and which other US state?","CorrectAnswer":"California","Answer2":"Arizona","Answer3":"Oregon","Answer4":"Utah","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The Gothic Chartes Cathedral in France has famous stained glass windows which produce which unique colour? ","CorrectAnswer":"Chartes Blue","Answer2":"Chartes Green","Answer3":"Chartes Red","Answer4":"Chartes White","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country is the port of Odense?","CorrectAnswer":"Denmark","Answer2":"Sweden","Answer3":"Norway","Answer4":"Finland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country's name means Sunday?","CorrectAnswer":"Dominica","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"Russia","Answer4":"Australia ","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The highest mountain in Japan is Mount Fuji. What does Fuji mean? ","CorrectAnswer":"fire","Answer2":"snow","Answer3":"beauty","Answer4":"harmony","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The only person with 5 stars for excellence on the Hollywood Boulevard Walk Of Fame?","CorrectAnswer":"Gene Autry","Answer2":"Diana Ross","Answer3":"Bing Crosby","Answer4":"George Burns","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Slovakia?","CorrectAnswer":"Germany","Answer2":"Hungary","Answer3":"Austria","Answer4":"Poland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country does the volcano Unzen grumble?","CorrectAnswer":"Japan","Answer2":"Indonesia","Answer3":"Philippines","Answer4":"Iceland","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the Hollywood star who used his nose rather than hands or feet to make an impression in the sidewalk in front of 'Grauman's Chinese'?  ","CorrectAnswer":"Jimmy Durante","Answer2":"Lassie","Answer3":"Bob Hope","Answer4":"Karl Malden","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country does the volcano Mt Pelee grumble?","CorrectAnswer":"Martinique","Answer2":"Iceland","Answer3":"USA","Answer4":"Italy","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country produces the most silver?","CorrectAnswer":"Mexico","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"USA","Answer4":"Brazil","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country does the volcano Popocatepetl grumble?","CorrectAnswer":"Mexico","Answer2":"Colombia","Answer3":"Indonesia","Answer4":"Greece","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Libya?","CorrectAnswer":"Morocco","Answer2":"Tunisia","Answer3":"Algeria","Answer4":"Eygpt","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the most populated city north of the arctic circle?","CorrectAnswer":"Murmansk","Answer2":"Ottawa","Answer3":"Aberdeen","Answer4":"Fairbanks","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country does the volcano Ruapehu grumble?","CorrectAnswer":"New Zealand","Answer2":"USA","Answer3":"Indonesia","Answer4":"Japan","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"According to the 'Global Peace Index' what is the safest country in the world?","CorrectAnswer":"Norway","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"Switzerland","Answer4":"Australia","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The Taj Mahal. Taj means 'crown', what does Mahal mean?","CorrectAnswer":"palace","Answer2":"king","Answer3":"queen","Answer4":"crypt","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which street in London takes its name from a croquet like game once played by Charles I ?","CorrectAnswer":"Pall Mall","Answer2":"Threadneedle","Answer3":"Portobello","Answer4":"Piccadilly","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which 'street' in London takes its name from the ornamental collars once made by the  17th century tailor Robert Baker?","CorrectAnswer":"Piccadilly","Answer2":"Pall Mall","Answer3":"Threadneedle","Answer4":"Carnaby","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country produces the most amber?","CorrectAnswer":"Poland","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"India","Answer4":"China","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The largest industrial complex in the world in the 19th century was found in which English harbour city?","CorrectAnswer":"Portsmouth","Answer2":"Liverpool","Answer3":"Newcastle","Answer4":"Dover","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country is not on the shores of Lake Victoria?","CorrectAnswer":"Rwanda","Answer2":"Uganda","Answer3":"Kenya","Answer4":"Tanzania","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The most visited city in Brittany has the highest ratio of sea food restaurants in Europe. Which port city is it?","CorrectAnswer":"Saint Malo","Answer2":"Rennes","Answer3":"Lannion","Answer4":"Brest","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"A native indian legend claims that the scored marks that run down the side of Devil's Tower in Wyoming were gouged by a giant bear that was trying to reach what?","CorrectAnswer":"Seven stranded young maidens","Answer2":"The honey coloured sun ","Answer3":"His own shadow","Answer4":"The other end of the rainbow","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What are the winds called below the latitude 60 degrees south?","CorrectAnswer":"Shrieking 60s","Answer2":"Screaming 60s","Answer3":"Scary 60s","Answer4":"Sullen 60s","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Saint is not a US Virgin Island?","CorrectAnswer":"St Vincent","Answer2":"St John","Answer3":"St Croix","Answer4":"St Thomas","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country does not border Syria?","CorrectAnswer":"Sudan","Answer2":"Isreal","Answer3":"Lebanon","Answer4":"Turkey","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which South American country would you find the city New Amsterdam?","CorrectAnswer":"Surinam","Answer2":"Brazil","Answer3":"Ecuador","Answer4":"Guyana","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is found on the flag of Rwanda?","CorrectAnswer":"The letter 'R'","Answer2":"A Star","Answer3":"A Half Moon","Answer4":"An Assualt Rifle","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country does the volcano Kilauea grumble?","CorrectAnswer":"USA","Answer2":"Japan","Answer3":"Iceland","Answer4":"Spain","Category":"Geography","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many seats did the Spitfire fighter plane have?","CorrectAnswer":"1","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"None","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many wives did Henry VIII have?","CorrectAnswer":"6","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"4","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":" How many years did the '21 Year War'  between Sweden and Russia last? ","CorrectAnswer":"21","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"55","Answer4":"103","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many pennies were there in a pre decimal pound?","CorrectAnswer":"240","Answer2":"100","Answer3":"200","Answer4":"140","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which year was the Gunpowder Plot?","CorrectAnswer":"1605","Answer2":"1705","Answer3":"1805","Answer4":"1505","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What year saw Adolph Hitler committing suicide?","CorrectAnswer":"1945","Answer2":"1944","Answer3":"1946","Answer4":"1947","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which year did JFK get assassinated?","CorrectAnswer":"1963","Answer2":"1966","Answer3":"1968","Answer4":"1960","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In what year was the Falkland war?","CorrectAnswer":"1982","Answer2":"1984","Answer3":"1980","Answer4":"1978","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which year did a US-led coalition invade Iraq?","CorrectAnswer":"2003","Answer2":"2001","Answer3":"2005","Answer4":"1999","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which country did the USSR invade in 1979?","CorrectAnswer":"Afghanistan","Answer2":"Iraq","Answer3":"Iran","Answer4":"China","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was banned in USA in January 1920?","CorrectAnswer":"Alcohol","Answer2":"Gambling","Answer3":"Strikes","Answer4":"Smoking","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"One of the ancient world wonders, the 'Hanging Gardens', was found in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Babylon","Answer2":"Alexandria","Answer3":"Rome","Answer4":"Athens","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was named after a hydrogen bomb test?","CorrectAnswer":"Bikini","Answer2":"Hoola Hoop","Answer3":"Frisbee","Answer4":"Matchbox","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Robben Island was a prison near which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Cape Town","Answer2":"San Francisco","Answer3":"Athens","Answer4":"Exeter","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Iceland and the Uk were caught up in which war?","CorrectAnswer":"Cod","Answer2":"Herring","Answer3":"Salmon","Answer4":"Lobster","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"King William the Bastard was also known by which other name?","CorrectAnswer":"Conqueror","Answer2":"Rufus","Answer3":"Orange","Answer4":"Young King","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Of which country was Greenland a colony until 1981?","CorrectAnswer":"Denmark","Answer2":"Sweden","Answer3":"Russia","Answer4":"Iceland","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The patron saint of England is famous for killing which type of creature?","CorrectAnswer":"Dragon","Answer2":"Unicorn","Answer3":"Angel","Answer4":"Devil","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"William Kemmler, back in 1890, was the first person to be killed using what lethal method?","CorrectAnswer":"Electric Chair","Answer2":"Lethal Injection","Answer3":"Death by Firing Squad","Answer4":"Radiation","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was special about Louise Brown, born July 25, 1978 in England?","CorrectAnswer":"First test tube baby","Answer2":"First surrogate mother","Answer3":"First surviving separated Siamese twin","Answer4":"First surviving 20 week old foetus","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"During the second world war in Germany it was forbidden to give a horse which name?","CorrectAnswer":"Hitler","Answer2":"Stalin","Answer3":"Mussolini","Answer4":"Winston","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who shot Lee Harvey Oswald?","CorrectAnswer":"Jack Ruby","Answer2":"Jack Diamond","Answer3":"Jack Emerald","Answer4":"Jack Sapphire","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the first name of the US President known by the nickname JFK?","CorrectAnswer":"John","Answer2":"Joe","Answer3":"Jerry","Answer4":"Jack","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which explorer was the first to circumnavigate the globe?","CorrectAnswer":"Magellan","Answer2":"Drake","Answer3":"Marco Polo","Answer4":"Columbus","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What species were Benjy and Laska, who were sent into space in 1958?","CorrectAnswer":"Mice","Answer2":"Rats","Answer3":"Monkeys","Answer4":"Cats","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which European country is ruled by The House of Orange?","CorrectAnswer":"Netherlands","Answer2":"Belgium","Answer3":"Sweden","Answer4":"Norway","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the name of Christopher Columbus' smallest  ship?","CorrectAnswer":"Nina","Answer2":"Tina","Answer3":"Gina","Answer4":"Mina","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What nationality was Roald Amundsen, the first man to reach the South Pole?","CorrectAnswer":"Norwegian","Answer2":"Swedish","Answer3":"Dutch","Answer4":"Belgian","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In what industry did John Davidson Rockefeller get rich?","CorrectAnswer":"Oil","Answer2":"Motor","Answer3":"Music","Answer4":"Movie","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who was Pakistan's President in 2006?","CorrectAnswer":"Pervez Musharraf","Answer2":"Pratibha Patil","Answer3":"Nawaz Sharif","Answer4":"Benazir Bhutto","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which organisation was awarded the Nobel Peace Prize in 1917?","CorrectAnswer":"The Red Cross","Answer2":"The Boy Scouts","Answer3":"The Police","Answer4":"Fathers for Justice","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was 10th century English king Ethelred's nickname?","CorrectAnswer":"The Unready","Answer2":"The Unlucky","Answer3":"The Unshaven","Answer4":"The Unsweetened","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Queen Elizabeth I of England was also known by which name?","CorrectAnswer":"The virgin queen","Answer2":"The ginger queen","Answer3":"The Richmond queen","Answer4":"Bloody queen Elizabeth","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What weather phenomenon was the Norse god Thor thought to control? ","CorrectAnswer":"Thunder","Answer2":"Lightening","Answer3":"Typhoon","Answer4":"Earthquakes","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"King Henry VII of England was a member of which royal house?","CorrectAnswer":"Tudor","Answer2":"York","Answer3":"Lancaster","Answer4":"Stuart","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which Swedish motor vehicle manufacturer acquired the Dutch company DAF in the mid-1970s?","CorrectAnswer":"Volvo","Answer2":"Saab","Answer3":"Ford","Answer4":"Dacia","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where did Napoleon Bonaparte suffer his last defeat? ","CorrectAnswer":"Waterloo","Answer2":"Rome","Answer3":"Elba","Answer4":"Leipzig","Category":"History","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many baths did Louis XIV take in his lifetime?","CorrectAnswer":"3","Answer2":"0","Answer3":"51","Answer4":"1","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many brothers and sisters did John F. Kennedy have?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"0","Answer4":"2","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many days were there in one week in ancient Roman times?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"7","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"10","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Out of every 10 women in Scotland, how many were pregnant on their wedding day, according to a Royal Commission of 1868?","CorrectAnswer":"9","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"0","Answer4":"2","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many kings of England have been named Edward? ","CorrectAnswer":"9","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"7","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many people are there in a US Grand Jury?","CorrectAnswer":"23","Answer2":"12","Answer3":"11","Answer4":"17","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"An estimated how many Popes have been murdered?","CorrectAnswer":"26","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"13","Answer4":"46","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many days was William Harrison President of the United States?","CorrectAnswer":"32","Answer2":"64","Answer3":"16","Answer4":"8","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many years were there between the Silver Jubilees of George V and Elizabeth II? ","CorrectAnswer":"42","Answer2":"32","Answer3":"52","Answer4":"62","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many km long was the Berlin Wall?","CorrectAnswer":"42","Answer2":"22","Answer3":"82","Answer4":"12","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"For how many years did Queen Victoria reign?","CorrectAnswer":"63","Answer2":"53","Answer3":"43","Answer4":"73","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In Roman Numerals what does LXX stand for?","CorrectAnswer":"70","Answer2":"120","Answer3":"60","Answer4":"1200","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many pilgrims left Plymouth for America on the Mayflower?","CorrectAnswer":"104","Answer2":"202","Answer3":"64","Answer4":"264","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many years did the 'One Hundred Years War' last?","CorrectAnswer":"114","Answer2":"100","Answer3":"99","Answer4":"144","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many minutes did Neil Armstrong spend on the moon?","CorrectAnswer":"152","Answer2":"62","Answer3":"1.162","Answer4":"12","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"According to Forbes new Rich List for 2009, how many billionares are there in the world? ","CorrectAnswer":"793","Answer2":"241","Answer3":"2.355","Answer4":"5.205","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did King Richard the 'lionhearted' die?","CorrectAnswer":"1199","Answer2":"99","Answer3":"599","Answer4":"1599","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did Henry VIII die?","CorrectAnswer":"1547","Answer2":"1597","Answer3":"1647","Answer4":"1507","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What number on Pennsylvania Avenue would you find the white house?","CorrectAnswer":"1600","Answer2":"1200","Answer3":"1800","Answer4":"2000","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was St Pauls cathedral completed?","CorrectAnswer":"1711","Answer2":"1611","Answer3":"1811","Answer4":"1911","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was the revolver invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1835","Answer2":"1888","Answer3":"1788","Answer4":"1802","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Spanish Dublone was legal tender in the USA until which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1857","Answer2":"1777","Answer3":"1657","Answer4":"1927","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did electricity replace steam powered locomotives in the London Underground?","CorrectAnswer":"1890","Answer2":"1910","Answer3":"1850","Answer4":"1930","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was the Tower Bridge in London completed?","CorrectAnswer":"1894","Answer2":"1794","Answer3":"1811","Answer4":"1911","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What year did the infamous San Francisco earthquake take place?","CorrectAnswer":"1906","Answer2":"1916","Answer3":"1896","Answer4":"1926","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was the first successful Channel crossing by an airplane?","CorrectAnswer":"1909","Answer2":"1903","Answer3":"1913","Answer4":"1897","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did the Titanic sink?","CorrectAnswer":"1912","Answer2":"1909","Answer3":"1915","Answer4":"1905","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was the infamous 'black sox' scandal?","CorrectAnswer":"1919","Answer2":"1909","Answer3":"1929","Answer4":"1939","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In what year was Mahatma Gandhi assassinated?","CorrectAnswer":"1948","Answer2":"1950","Answer3":"1942","Answer4":"1938","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was the first successful heart transplant performed?","CorrectAnswer":"1967","Answer2":"1957","Answer3":"1977","Answer4":"1947","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was Prince Charles invested as The Prince of Wales?","CorrectAnswer":"1969","Answer2":"1979","Answer3":"1959","Answer4":"1989","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did the Rainbow Warrior sink?","CorrectAnswer":"1985","Answer2":"1986","Answer3":"1987","Answer4":"1984","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was Rajiv Gandhi assassinated?","CorrectAnswer":"1991","Answer2":"1981","Answer3":"1971","Answer4":"2001","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was the EURO TUNNEL officially opened?","CorrectAnswer":"1994","Answer2":"1990","Answer3":"1998","Answer4":"1986","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the worlds population in AD 1?","CorrectAnswer":"200,000,000","Answer2":"500,000,000","Answer3":"25,000,000","Answer4":"1 billion","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which amendment of the US constitution abolished slavery?","CorrectAnswer":"13th","Answer2":"18th","Answer3":"9th","Answer4":"10th","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"For how long did Queen Jane rule England?","CorrectAnswer":"9 days","Answer2":"9 years","Answer3":"9 weeks","Answer4":"9 months","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"According to an old legend, who can't shed more than 3 tears?","CorrectAnswer":"a witch","Answer2":"a King","Answer3":"a lawyer","Answer4":"a bride ","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the 2nd man in space?","CorrectAnswer":"Alan Shepard","Answer2":"John Glenn","Answer3":"Virgil Grissom","Answer4":"Scott Carpenter","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"King Zog ruled which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Albania","Answer2":"Russia","Answer3":"Prussia","Answer4":"Persia","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the research ship Charles Darwin travelled with?","CorrectAnswer":"Beagle","Answer2":"Eagle","Answer3":"Mermaid","Answer4":"Turtle","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Charles Darwin was a passenger on which research ship?","CorrectAnswer":"Beagle","Answer2":"Dolphin","Answer3":"Eagle","Answer4":"Albatross","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which city was the Titanic built?","CorrectAnswer":"Belfast","Answer2":"Southampton","Answer3":"Glasgow","Answer4":"Liverpool","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was not the mayor of a US town?","CorrectAnswer":"Bruce Willis","Answer2":"Sony Bono","Answer3":"Anthony Hopkins","Answer4":"Clint Eastwood","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which ship was the first to arrive and rescue Titanic survivors?","CorrectAnswer":"Carpathia","Answer2":"Arizona","Answer3":"George Washington","Answer4":"Bremen","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year?","CorrectAnswer":"Cat","Answer2":"Dragon","Answer3":"Pig","Answer4":"Rooster","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the first wife of King Henry VIII?","CorrectAnswer":"Catherine of Aragon","Answer2":"Anne Boleyn","Answer3":"Jane Seymour","Answer4":"Anne of Cleeves","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English Monarch succeeded James I?","CorrectAnswer":"Charles I","Answer2":"James II","Answer3":"William III","Answer4":"Mary II","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Gregorian Calendar was adopted by which country in 1912?","CorrectAnswer":"China","Answer2":"Persia","Answer3":"India","Answer4":"Ireland","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country was not a Portugese colony?","CorrectAnswer":"Colombia","Answer2":"Brazil","Answer3":"Angola","Answer4":"Mozambique","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which word from the inaugural address by Barack Obama was cut out of the speech whilst being broadcast in China?","CorrectAnswer":"Communism","Answer2":"Chinese","Answer3":"Tibet","Answer4":"Earthquakes","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of Wellington's horse?","CorrectAnswer":"Copenhagen","Answer2":"Paris","Answer3":"Rome","Answer4":"Washington","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Florence Nightingale achieved fame during which war?","CorrectAnswer":"Crimean","Answer2":"First World War","Answer3":"Boer War","Answer4":"100 Years War","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year?","CorrectAnswer":"Crow","Answer2":"Ox","Answer3":"Pig","Answer4":"Monkey","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year? ","CorrectAnswer":"Dolphin","Answer2":"Dog","Answer3":"Monkey","Answer4":"Goat","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English King died in 1553 at the age of 15?","CorrectAnswer":"Edward VI","Answer2":"Edward V","Answer3":"Edward VII","Answer4":"Edward IV","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The crown of which New York City landmark was originally built as an airship dock?","CorrectAnswer":"Empire State Building","Answer2":"Chrysler Building","Answer3":"Statue of Liberty","Answer4":"Trump Tower","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the 1969 war between El Salvador and Honduras called?","CorrectAnswer":"football","Answer2":"cod","Answer3":"cola","Answer4":"postage stamp","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English King bought Buckingham Palace?","CorrectAnswer":"George III","Answer2":"George II","Answer3":"Charles I","Answer4":"Charles II","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which language did King George I speak?","CorrectAnswer":"German","Answer2":"Latin","Answer3":"French","Answer4":"Russian","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which King Harold died during the battle of Hastings?","CorrectAnswer":"Godwinson","Answer2":"Harefoot","Answer3":"the Elder","Answer4":"Ironside","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which ancient world wonder was found in Giza?","CorrectAnswer":"Great Pyramid","Answer2":"Lighthouse","Answer3":"Temple Of Artemis","Answer4":"Statue Of Zeus","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was Ehrich Weiss better known as?","CorrectAnswer":"Harry Houdini","Answer2":"Charlie Chaplin","Answer3":"The Great Suprendo","Answer4":"David Copperfield ","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"On which island was Capt Cook killed in 1779?","CorrectAnswer":"Hawaii","Answer2":"Australia","Answer3":"New Zealand","Answer4":"Moluccan Islands","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The falsely accused WW I spy Mata Hari was from which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Holland","Answer2":"France","Answer3":"India","Answer4":"Italy","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country founded the West India Company?","CorrectAnswer":"Holland","Answer2":"France","Answer3":"Germany","Answer4":"Spain","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Diana was the Roman goddess of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Hunting","Answer2":"Passion","Answer3":"Beauty","Answer4":"War","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What country provided the birthplace of Christopher Columbus?","CorrectAnswer":"Italy","Answer2":"Spain","Answer3":"Portugal","Answer4":"France","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English Monarch was the first from the House of Stuart?","CorrectAnswer":"James I","Answer2":"Charles I","Answer3":"Henry VII","Answer4":"Edward IV","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English Monarch was succeeded by William III of Orange?","CorrectAnswer":"James II","Answer2":"James I","Answer3":"Charles II","Answer4":"Mary II","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English Monarch succeeded Charles II?","CorrectAnswer":"James II","Answer2":"James I","Answer3":"William III","Answer4":"Mary II","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who hosted the music radio program The Perfumed Garden?","CorrectAnswer":"John Peel","Answer2":"Noel Edmunds","Answer3":"Kenny Everett","Answer4":"Vernon Kay","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Joseph Stalin twice ordered the KGB to assassinate which US actor?","CorrectAnswer":"John Wayne","Answer2":"Humphrey Bogart","Answer3":"Bob Hope","Answer4":"James Cagney","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Mau Mau were terrorists in which country late 50s early 60s?","CorrectAnswer":"Kenya","Answer2":"Sudan","Answer3":"Malaysia","Answer4":"Ghana","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the atom bomb dropped on Hiroshima?","CorrectAnswer":"Little Boy","Answer2":"Bad Boy","Answer3":"Fat Boy","Answer4":"Good Boy","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which explorers expedition was the first to circumnavigate the earth?","CorrectAnswer":"Magellan","Answer2":"Cook","Answer3":"de Gama","Answer4":"Cartier","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English Monarch succeeded William III of Orange?","CorrectAnswer":"Mary II","Answer2":"James II","Answer3":"James I","Answer4":"Charles II","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which famous outlaws last words were ","CorrectAnswer":"Ned Kelly","Answer2":"Al Capone","Answer3":"Dick Turpin","Answer4":"Billy the Kid","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which month of 1987 was weatherman Michael Fish embarrassed for failing to give warning of severe gales?","CorrectAnswer":"October","Answer2":"September","Answer3":"December","Answer4":"August","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which English Monarch was also known as Old Ironsides","CorrectAnswer":"Oliver Cromwell","Answer2":"Richard Cromwell","Answer3":"Charles I","Answer4":"Charles II","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"From which country did Bangladesh claim its independence?","CorrectAnswer":"Pakistan","Answer2":"India","Answer3":"China","Answer4":"Britain","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where did the 30 years war start and finish?","CorrectAnswer":"Prague","Answer2":"Berlin","Answer3":"London","Answer4":"Paris","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which member of the British Royal Family was made Deputy Sheriff of Harris County, Texas in 1960?","CorrectAnswer":"Prince Philip","Answer2":"Prince Charles","Answer3":"The Queen","Answer4":"Prince Andrew","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who directly succeeded King Edward VI as Monarch of England?","CorrectAnswer":"Queen Jane","Answer2":"Queen Mary I","Answer3":"Queen Elizabeth I","Answer4":"King James I","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Seti I was the father of which Egyptian?","CorrectAnswer":"Ramesses II","Answer2":"Tutankhamun","Answer3":"Nefertiti","Answer4":"Cleopatra","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The crossing of which river started a civil war?","CorrectAnswer":"Rubicon","Answer2":"St. Lawrence","Answer3":"Avon","Answer4":"Danube","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What kind of march did Gandhi lead?","CorrectAnswer":"Salt","Answer2":"Pepper","Answer3":"Sugar","Answer4":"Flower","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which city was destroyed by an earthquake in 1906?","CorrectAnswer":"San Francisco","Answer2":"Naples","Answer3":"Lisbon","Answer4":"Havana","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the flu that killed an estimated 40 million people in 1918?","CorrectAnswer":"Spanish","Answer2":"Asian","Answer3":"Hong Kong","Answer4":"European","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Olaf Palme was assassinated in 1986. Of which country was he the prime minister?","CorrectAnswer":"Sweden","Answer2":"Norway","Answer3":"Finland","Answer4":"Denmark","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was sometimes used as currency in 18th century Siberia?","CorrectAnswer":"Tea","Answer2":"Coffee","Answer3":"Snow","Answer4":"Tulips","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did Captain Cook call the Islands of Tonga?","CorrectAnswer":"The Friendly Islands","Answer2":"The Scary Islands","Answer3":"The Tongan Islands","Answer4":"The Cook Islands","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of these radio programmes did John Peel once present?","CorrectAnswer":"The perfumed garden","Answer2":"The poisoned garden","Answer3":"The tendered garden","Answer4":"The Musical garden","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which major British newspaper closed down for almost a year in 1978?","CorrectAnswer":"The Times","Answer2":"The Sun","Answer3":"The Telegraph","Answer4":"The Mirror","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which ancient world wonder was found in Alexandria?","CorrectAnswer":"The Lighthouse","Answer2":"Hanging Gardens","Answer3":"Temple Of Artemis","Answer4":"Great Pyramid","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Rainbow Warrior was what form of transport?","CorrectAnswer":"Trawler","Answer2":"Cruise Ship","Answer3":"Tugboat","Answer4":"Oil Tanker","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the cat that survived the sinking of the Bismark, HMS Cossack and the HMS Ark Royal in WW II ?","CorrectAnswer":"Unsinkable Sam","Answer2":"Unsinkable Molly Brown","Answer3":"Wet Willy","Answer4":"Kit Cat","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Marco Polo was a citizen of which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Venice","Answer2":"Rome","Answer3":"Florence","Answer4":"Naples","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which animal is not a Chinese year?","CorrectAnswer":"Whale","Answer2":"Snake","Answer3":"Hare","Answer4":"Tiger","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In history, the highwayman Dick Turpin was hanged in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"York","Answer2":"London","Answer3":"Leeds","Answer4":"Portsmouth","Category":"History","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many wheels had a hansom cab?","CorrectAnswer":"2","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"5","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many seconds did it take Napoleons surgeon Baron Dominique Larrey to amputate a leg?","CorrectAnswer":"14","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"32","Answer4":"60","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many swings of the axe did it take to remove Maria Stuarts head?","CorrectAnswer":"15","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"35","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many dollars did the first settlers pay the native Indians for Manhattan Island?","CorrectAnswer":"24","Answer2":"4","Answer3":"48","Answer4":"96","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Concubines excluded, how many wives did a Chinese Emperor have?","CorrectAnswer":"40","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"13","Answer4":"88","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"According to legend, how many bears did Davy Crockett kill in 7 months? ","CorrectAnswer":"105","Answer2":"7","Answer3":"77","Answer4":"705","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How old was the Biblical figure Methusalem?","CorrectAnswer":"969","Answer2":"844","Answer3":"622","Answer4":"369","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year were the Salem witchcraft trials?","CorrectAnswer":"1692","Answer2":"1581","Answer3":"1744","Answer4":"1519","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the last legal execution of a witch in Scotland?","CorrectAnswer":"1727","Answer2":"1827","Answer3":"1927","Answer4":"1627","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the lightning rod invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1752","Answer2":"1322","Answer3":"1825","Answer4":"1901","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did New York become a US state?","CorrectAnswer":"1788","Answer2":"1819","Answer3":"1792","Answer4":"1837","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did the first steam ship cross the Atlantic?","CorrectAnswer":"1819","Answer2":"1910","Answer3":"1859","Answer4":"1780","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The age of the railway began in which year with the introduction of the Liverpool-Manchester line?","CorrectAnswer":"1830","Answer2":"1800","Answer3":"1860","Answer4":"1770","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did the first passenger die in a rail accident?","CorrectAnswer":"1830","Answer2":"1850","Answer3":"1780","Answer4":"1870","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year were postage stamps introduced?","CorrectAnswer":"1840","Answer2":"1899","Answer3":"1745","Answer4":"1650","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did Texas become a US state?","CorrectAnswer":"1845","Answer2":"1912","Answer3":"1959","Answer4":"1861","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The first weather report in a newspaper appeared in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1848","Answer2":"1788","Answer3":"1871","Answer4":"1902","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year were blue jeans invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1874","Answer2":"1836","Answer3":"1902","Answer4":"1580","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the light bulb invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1880","Answer2":"1901","Answer3":"1825","Answer4":"1911","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did Oklahoma become a US state?","CorrectAnswer":"1907","Answer2":"1889","Answer3":"1850","Answer4":"1819","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did New Mexico become a US state?","CorrectAnswer":"1912","Answer2":"1867","Answer3":"1959","Answer4":"1788","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year were false eyelashes invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1916","Answer2":"1925","Answer3":"1939","Answer4":"1888","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did Charles Lindbergh fly solo across the Atlantic?","CorrectAnswer":"1927","Answer2":"1937","Answer3":"1917","Answer4":"1907","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was nylon invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1935","Answer2":"1885","Answer3":"1906","Answer4":"1951","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the transistor invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1947","Answer2":"1844","Answer3":"1902","Answer4":"1975","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the microwave oven invented?","CorrectAnswer":"1947","Answer2":"1977","Answer3":"1921","Answer4":"1982","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did the hula hoop craze first circle the world?","CorrectAnswer":"1958","Answer2":"1963","Answer3":"1952","Answer4":"1966","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the Berlin wall built?","CorrectAnswer":"1961","Answer2":"1958","Answer3":"1946","Answer4":"1965","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was Nelson Mandela sentenced to life in prison?","CorrectAnswer":"1964","Answer2":"1972","Answer3":"1956","Answer4":"1978","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did the mini skirt first turn heads?","CorrectAnswer":"1964","Answer2":"1968","Answer3":"1958","Answer4":"1961","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the first 'Great Blackout' in the eastern United States and Canada?","CorrectAnswer":"1965","Answer2":"1975","Answer3":"1955","Answer4":"1985","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the 747 Jumbo jet introduced?","CorrectAnswer":"1970","Answer2":"1964","Answer3":"1978","Answer4":"1984","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Timber selected from how many fully grown oak trees were needed to build a large 3 decker Royal Navy battle ship in the 18th century?","CorrectAnswer":"3.500","Answer2":"50","Answer3":"500","Answer4":"1.500","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In 1970 the 'Blue Flame' became the first car to break which speed barrier?","CorrectAnswer":"1,000 km hr","Answer2":"250 km hr","Answer3":"500 km hr","Answer4":"1,500 km hr","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The 'football' or briefcase with the nuclear codes must always be within how many metres of the US President?","CorrectAnswer":"12 m","Answer2":"6 m","Answer3":"2 m","Answer4":"24 m","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How long did the Apollo 11 mission last?","CorrectAnswer":"195 hours 18 min","Answer2":"95 hours 18 min","Answer3":"295 hours 18 min","Answer4":"495 hours 18 min","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the average life expectancy of an Englishman in the middle ages?","CorrectAnswer":"33 years","Answer2":"13 years","Answer3":"21 years","Answer4":"41 years","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How long was the war between GB  and Zansibar in 1896?","CorrectAnswer":"38 min","Answer2":"38 sec","Answer3":"38 hours","Answer4":"38 days","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How long did the Wright Brothers first flight last?","CorrectAnswer":"59 sec","Answer2":"12 sec","Answer3":"3 sec   ","Answer4":"24 sec","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the cargo on board the HMS Bounty?","CorrectAnswer":"Breadfruit","Answer2":"Grapefruit","Answer3":"Sauerkraut","Answer4":"Watermelon","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was Patrick Stewart's best man at his wedding?","CorrectAnswer":"Brent Spiner","Answer2":"William Shatner","Answer3":"LeVar Burton","Answer4":"Johnathan Frakes","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Off the coast of which country did the Edmund Fitzgerald sink?","CorrectAnswer":"Canada","Answer2":"Ireland","Answer3":"Scotland","Answer4":"Australia","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The press coined which famous pilot 'The Flying Fool' in 1927?","CorrectAnswer":"Charles Lindbergh","Answer2":"Baron von Richtofen","Answer3":"Orville Wright","Answer4":"Amelia Earhart","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country did an earthquake kill an estimated 650,000 people in 1976?","CorrectAnswer":"China","Answer2":"Pakistan","Answer3":"Mexico","Answer4":"Japan","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Punch editor A P Herbert once wrote a cheque on the side of a what?","CorrectAnswer":"cow","Answer2":"bus","Answer3":"taxi","Answer4":"egg","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The USA bought the Virgin islands from which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Denmark","Answer2":"GB","Answer3":"Holland","Answer4":"France","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which city was never the capital of the USA?","CorrectAnswer":"Detroit","Answer2":"New York ","Answer3":"Baltimore","Answer4":"Philadelphia","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Tollbooth was an infamous 18th century prison in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Edinburgh","Answer2":"Halifax","Answer3":"London","Answer4":"Bristol","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which queen at one time banned the use of mirrors?","CorrectAnswer":"Elizabeth I ","Answer2":"Elizabeth II ","Answer3":"Mary","Answer4":"Freddie Mercury","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How often does Airforce One undergo a complete overhaul or D-Check?","CorrectAnswer":"every 154 days","Answer2":"every 54 days","Answer3":"every 254 days","Answer4":"every 354 days","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In the 1930s, what was the 'Phalange'?","CorrectAnswer":"Fascist movement in Spain","Answer2":"Secret police in Italy","Answer3":"Abstract art movement","Answer4":"Dance craze","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The NAZIS declared war on which country 3 March 1945?","CorrectAnswer":"Finland","Answer2":"Japan","Answer3":"France","Answer4":"Italy","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What did the Roman Catholic church condemned in the 16th century?","CorrectAnswer":"fork","Answer2":"spoon","Answer3":"corkscrew","Answer4":"knife","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Off the coast of which country did the Amoco Cadiz sink?","CorrectAnswer":"France","Answer2":"USA","Answer3":"Spain","Answer4":"South Africa","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The Roman province Aquitania was found in which modern day country?","CorrectAnswer":"France","Answer2":"Scotland","Answer3":"Portugal","Answer4":"Austria","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which explorer first entered San Francisco Bay in 1579?","CorrectAnswer":"Francis Drake","Answer2":"Juan Ponce de Leon","Answer3":"Henry Hudson","Answer4":"Amerigo Vespucci","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Baby Doc Duvalier was the dictator of which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Haiti","Answer2":"Senegal","Answer3":"Vietnam","Answer4":"Algeria","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Herodotus is known as the father of what?","CorrectAnswer":"History","Answer2":"Medicine","Answer3":"Theatre","Answer4":"Music","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Between which two countries was the 1969 'Football War'?","CorrectAnswer":"Honduras and El Salvador","Answer2":"Brazil and Argentina","Answer3":"Algeria and Tunisia","Answer4":" Chile and Peru ","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Off the coast of which country did the QE I sink?","CorrectAnswer":"Hong Kong","Answer2":"USA","Answer3":"Brazil","Answer4":"Spain","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which ship sank in the Denmark Strait?","CorrectAnswer":"Hood","Answer2":"Bismark","Answer3":"Titanic","Answer4":"Exon Valdez","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which country invented Venetian Blinds?","CorrectAnswer":"Japan","Answer2":"Italy","Answer3":"France","Answer4":"USA","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the captain of PT 109?","CorrectAnswer":"JFK","Answer2":"Ronald Reagan","Answer3":"George Bush sr","Answer4":"Gerald Ford","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was William Shatner's best man at his wedding?","CorrectAnswer":"Leonard Nimoy","Answer2":"Brent Spiner","Answer3":"DeForest Kelley","Answer4":"James Doohan","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which magazine first published photos of a human embryo in 1965?","CorrectAnswer":"Life","Answer2":"Time","Answer3":"Newsweek","Answer4":"Cosmopolitan ","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which PM played a role in the development of soft ice cream?","CorrectAnswer":"Margret Thatcher ","Answer2":"Tony Blair","Answer3":"Winston Churchill ","Answer4":"William Pitt","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Botany Bay was the first penal colony in which Australian state?","CorrectAnswer":"New South Wales","Answer2":"Tasmania","Answer3":"South Australia","Answer4":"Queensland","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which kind of animal did Florence Nightingale often carry around in her pocket?     ","CorrectAnswer":"Owl","Answer2":"Snake","Answer3":"Puppy","Answer4":"Kitten","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which is the oldest airline in the English-speaking world?","CorrectAnswer":"Quantas","Answer2":"British Airways","Answer3":"American Airlines","Answer4":"Air Lingus","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What kind of animal was the germanic goddess of the spring?","CorrectAnswer":"rabbit","Answer2":"fox","Answer3":"bluebird","Answer4":"wolf","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Between 1807 and 1821 the capital of Portugal was found in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Rio de Janeiro","Answer2":"London","Answer3":"Madrid","Answer4":"Goa","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was Australia's longest serving Prime Minister?","CorrectAnswer":"Robert Menzies","Answer2":"John Howard","Answer3":"Gough Whitlam","Answer4":"Bob Hawke","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first man to claim he reach the North Pole in 1909?","CorrectAnswer":"Robert Peary","Answer2":"Roald Amundsen","Answer3":"Robert Scott","Answer4":"Admiral Halsey","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The Roman province Lusitania was found in which modern day country?","CorrectAnswer":"Spain","Answer2":"France","Answer3":"Ireland","Answer4":"Germany","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Sunday newspaper, in 1924, published the first crossword to appear in a British Newspaper?","CorrectAnswer":"Sunday Express","Answer2":"Sunday Times","Answer3":"The Observer","Answer4":"Sunday Mirror","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Prime Minister helped invent soft ice-cream?","CorrectAnswer":"Thatcher","Answer2":"Wilson","Answer3":"Major","Answer4":"Callaghan","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was TIME magazines man of the year in 1982?","CorrectAnswer":"The Computer ","Answer2":"The Red Cross","Answer3":"The Automobile","Answer4":"NASA","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which of the Seven Wonders of the Ancient World was found in Halicarnassus?","CorrectAnswer":"The Mausoleum","Answer2":"The Temple of Artemis","Answer3":"The Hanging Gardens","Answer4":"The Lighthouse","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Off the coast of which country did the USS Arizona sink?","CorrectAnswer":"USA","Answer2":"Australia","Answer3":"Ireland","Answer4":"Canada","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What name did the Vikings give to present day Newfoundland?","CorrectAnswer":"Vinland","Answer2":"Graceland","Answer3":"No mans Land","Answer4":"Ice Land","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which US state did Sir Walter Raleigh name?","CorrectAnswer":"Virginia","Answer2":"Massachusetts","Answer3":"Rhode Island","Answer4":"Florida","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was Ronald Reagan's best man at his wedding?","CorrectAnswer":"William Holden","Answer2":"Cary Grant","Answer3":"Charlie Chaplin","Answer4":"Humphrey Bogart","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Thomas was executed alongside Guy Fawkes in November 1605?","CorrectAnswer":"Winter","Answer2":"May","Answer3":"Summer","Answer4":"March","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which general defeated the French in Canada?","CorrectAnswer":"Wolfe","Answer2":"Hawke","Answer3":"Lambe","Answer4":"Hogge","Category":"History","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many ghosts visit Scrooge in A Christmas Carol?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"5","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which female novelist wrote the book Black Beauty?","CorrectAnswer":"Anna Sewell","Answer2":"Barbara Cartland","Answer3":"Enid Blyton","Answer4":"Dorothy L Sayers","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the name of Roy Rogers' pet dog?","CorrectAnswer":"Bullet","Answer2":"Fido","Answer3":"Lightening","Answer4":"Dog Rogers","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'a clockwork orange'?","CorrectAnswer":"Anthony Burgess","Answer2":"Arnold Burgess","Answer3":"Anthony Hopkins","Answer4":"Arnold Hopkins","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was Eric Blair’s pen name?","CorrectAnswer":"George Orwell","Answer2":"H.G. Wells","Answer3":"John Steinbeck","Answer4":"Charles Dickens","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the name of the dog of Dennis the menace?","CorrectAnswer":"Gnasher","Answer2":"Basher","Answer3":"Thrasher","Answer4":"Smasher","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which is the longest of Shakespeare’s plays?","CorrectAnswer":"Hamlet","Answer2":"MacBeth","Answer3":"2 Gentlemen of Verona","Answer4":"Romeo and Juliet","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of the following is not a Romance author?","CorrectAnswer":"Harold Robbins","Answer2":"Barbara Cartland","Answer3":"Danielle Steel","Answer4":"Jackie Collins","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What John Spyri story is about a girl who lives in the Alps?","CorrectAnswer":"Heidi","Answer2":"Annie","Answer3":"Emily","Answer4":"Carmen","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which month did Samuel Pepys begin his famous diary?","CorrectAnswer":"January","Answer2":"March","Answer3":"May","Answer4":"July","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"At which railway station does one board the 'Hogwarts Express'?","CorrectAnswer":"Kings Cross","Answer2":"Waterloo","Answer3":"Victoria","Answer4":"Charing Cross","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of the following is not a childrens author?","CorrectAnswer":"Michael Crichton","Answer2":"Dr. Seuss","Answer3":"Enid Blyton","Answer4":"Roger Hargreaves","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the name of Sherlock Holmes house keeper?","CorrectAnswer":"Mrs Hudson","Answer2":"Mrs Sippi","Answer3":"Miss Mayweather","Answer4":"Mrs Wilson","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Michael Bond was the creator of which bear?","CorrectAnswer":"Paddington","Answer2":"Yogi","Answer3":"Pooh","Answer4":"Baloo","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Whose nose grew when he told a lie?","CorrectAnswer":"Pinocchio","Answer2":"Dumbo","Answer3":"Jeffrey Archer","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Carlo Collodi created which famous children's character?","CorrectAnswer":"Pinocchio","Answer2":"Dumbo","Answer3":"Snow White","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is Dick Grayson better known as?","CorrectAnswer":"Robin","Answer2":"Batman","Answer3":"Joker","Answer4":"Alfred","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where was William Shakespeare born?","CorrectAnswer":"Stratford Upon Avon","Answer2":"Bath","Answer3":"Bradford","Answer4":"Kingston Upon Thames","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the subtitle of Peter Pan?","CorrectAnswer":"The Boy Who Wouldn’t Grow Up","Answer2":"The Boy With The Growing Nose","Answer3":"The Puppet That Came Alive","Answer4":"The Boy Who Lied","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of the following is the best-selling fiction author of all time?","CorrectAnswer":"William Shakespeare","Answer2":"Agatha Christie","Answer3":"Barbara Cartland","Answer4":"Harold Robbins","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many Bronte sisters were there?","CorrectAnswer":"3","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"5","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many children were in Enid Blytons the famous five?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"3","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Winston Smith is the central character in which book?","CorrectAnswer":"1984","Answer2":"The Time Machine","Answer3":"Dune","Answer4":"The Day Of The Triffids","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many rode into Tennyson's 'valley of death'?","CorrectAnswer":"600","Answer2":"1000","Answer3":"6000","Answer4":"100","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How old was Adrian Mole?","CorrectAnswer":"13 and 3 quarters","Answer2":"13 and a half","Answer3":"13 and 3 fifths","Answer4":"13 and 2 thirds","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of inn in Treasure Island?","CorrectAnswer":"Admiral Benbow","Answer2":"Captain Benbow","Answer3":"Corporal Benbow","Answer4":"Officer Benbow","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote ","CorrectAnswer":"Aesop","Answer2":"Shakespeare","Answer3":"Ben  Franklin","Answer4":"Chaucer","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following is the second best-selling fiction author of all time?","CorrectAnswer":"Agatha Christie","Answer2":"William Shakespeare","Answer3":"Barbara Cartland","Answer4":"Harold Robbins","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'The Count of Monte Christo'?","CorrectAnswer":"Alexandre Dumas","Answer2":"Victor Hugo","Answer3":"Nathaniel Hawthorne","Answer4":"Herman Melville","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which name is not a Steven King book?","CorrectAnswer":"Cacy","Answer2":"Carrie","Answer3":"Cujo ","Answer4":"Christine","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following is not visited by Gulliver in Gulliver's Travels?","CorrectAnswer":"China","Answer2":"Japan","Answer3":"Lilliput","Answer4":"Laputa","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Moll Flanders'?","CorrectAnswer":"Daniel DeFoe","Answer2":"Johnathan Swift","Answer3":"Voltaire","Answer4":"Henry Fielding","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote In The Beginning I Used To Be An Animal But I'm Alright Now?","CorrectAnswer":"Eric Burdon","Answer2":"Wayne Rooney","Answer3":"Scary Spice","Answer4":"Vinnie Jones","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the complete title of Mary Shelley's Frankenstein?","CorrectAnswer":"Frankenstein or The modern Prometheus","Answer2":"Frankenstein or The modern genesis","Answer3":"Frankenstein or The modern satan","Answer4":"Frankenstein or The modern phoenix","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Pygmalion'?","CorrectAnswer":"G B Shaw","Answer2":"Mark Twain","Answer3":"Tolstoj","Answer4":"Emily Bronte","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of these writers died in 1400?","CorrectAnswer":"Geoffrey Chaucer","Answer2":"William Shakespeare","Answer3":"Daniel DeFoe","Answer4":"Samuel Johnson","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was Mary Ann Evans pen name?","CorrectAnswer":"George Eliot","Answer2":"George Orwell","Answer3":"George Sand","Answer4":"George Bernard Shaw","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Tom Jones'?","CorrectAnswer":"Henry Fielding","Answer2":"Johnathan Swift","Answer3":"Daniel DeFoe","Answer4":"Herman Melville","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Aldous Huxley's book Brave New World was banned in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Ireland","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"South Africa","Answer4":"USA","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'I Robot'?","CorrectAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","Answer2":"Jules Verne","Answer3":"H G Wells","Answer4":"Douglas Adams","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was Rowena's husband?","CorrectAnswer":"Ivanhoe","Answer2":"Robin Hood","Answer3":"Dick Turpin","Answer4":"Macbeth","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Peter Pan'?","CorrectAnswer":"J M Barrie","Answer2":"Rudyard Kipling","Answer3":"Lewis Carroll","Answer4":"Carlo Collodi","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote the book The Last Of The Mohicans?","CorrectAnswer":"James Fenimore Cooper","Answer2":"H.G. Wells","Answer3":"Jules Verne","Answer4":"Sir Walter Scott","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'The Spy Who Came In From The Cold'?","CorrectAnswer":"John le Carre","Answer2":"Ian Fleming","Answer3":"Henning Mankell","Answer4":"Arthur Conan Doyle","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mother Raksha is a character in which childrens book?","CorrectAnswer":"Jungle Book","Answer2":"The Wonderful Wizard Of Oz","Answer3":"The Wind in the Willows","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Uther Pendragon was which mans father?","CorrectAnswer":"King Arthur","Answer2":"Dick Turpin","Answer3":"Robin Hood","Answer4":"Ivanhoe","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Oliver Mellors is a central character in which novel?","CorrectAnswer":"Lady Chatterley's Lover","Answer2":"The Great Gatsby","Answer3":"Animal Farm","Answer4":"The World According To Garp","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Totally Frank is which Frank's autobiography?","CorrectAnswer":"Lampard","Answer2":"Sinatra","Answer3":"Zappa","Answer4":"Howard","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote the popular Simon Templar books?","CorrectAnswer":"Leslie Charteris","Answer2":"Dorothy L Sayers","Answer3":"John le Carre","Answer4":"Raymond Chandler","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What were the cities in Dickens’s A Tale Of Two Cities?","CorrectAnswer":"London and Paris","Answer2":"Rome and Florence","Answer3":"Venice and Rome","Answer4":"Paris and Florence","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who is a bat in Jungle Book?","CorrectAnswer":"Mang","Answer2":"Hang","Answer3":"Bang","Answer4":"Fang","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'The Mists of Avalon'?","CorrectAnswer":"Marion Zimmer Bradley","Answer2":"J R R Tolkien","Answer3":"Joanne K Rowling","Answer4":"Terry Pratchett","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was Samuel Langhorne Clemens pen name?","CorrectAnswer":"Mark Twain","Answer2":"Novalis","Answer3":"Jack London","Answer4":"Joseph Conrad","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the paranoid android in Hitch Hikers Guide to the Galaxy?","CorrectAnswer":"Marvin","Answer2":"Gort","Answer3":"Wayne","Answer4":"Robby","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Count of Monte Christo was in love with which woman?","CorrectAnswer":"Mercedes","Answer2":"Porsche","Answer3":"Lancia","Answer4":"Cadillac","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What are the cannibalistic beasts called in H.G. Wells book The Time Machine?","CorrectAnswer":"Morlocks","Answer2":"Warlocks","Answer3":"Yahoos","Answer4":"Triffids","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Whose autobiography was entitled 'The Long Walk To Freedom'?","CorrectAnswer":"Nelson Mandela","Answer2":"Mahatma Gandhi","Answer3":"Lenin","Answer4":"Martin Luther King","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who does Mr Brownlow rescue?","CorrectAnswer":"Oliver Twist","Answer2":"Tom Jones","Answer3":"Huckleberry Finn","Answer4":"Tom Brown","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which nationality is best-selling author Paulo Coelho?","CorrectAnswer":"Portuguese","Answer2":"Spanish","Answer3":"French","Answer4":"Italian","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is comic book hero Roy of the Rovers' surname?","CorrectAnswer":"Race","Answer2":"Run","Answer3":"Rave","Answer4":"Rover","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Adams wrote Watership Down?","CorrectAnswer":"Richard","Answer2":"Douglas","Answer3":"Tony","Answer4":"Morticia","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Treasure Island'?","CorrectAnswer":"Robert Louis Stevenson","Answer2":"H G Wells","Answer3":"Jack London","Answer4":"Sir Walter Scott","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote the book 'Dr Jekyll and Mr Hyde'?","CorrectAnswer":"Robert Louis Stevenson","Answer2":"Sir Walter Scott","Answer3":"Iian Banks","Answer4":"Alister Maclean","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What Was the Title Of Alex Haleys Most Famous Work?","CorrectAnswer":"Roots","Answer2":"Boots","Answer3":"Coots","Answer4":"Toots","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What school does Tom attend in Tom Brown’s school days?","CorrectAnswer":"Rugby","Answer2":"Eton","Answer3":"Harrow","Answer4":"Dulwich","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote the play 'Waiting for Godot'?","CorrectAnswer":"Samuel Beckett","Answer2":"George Bernard Shaw","Answer3":"Andrew Lloyd Webber","Answer4":"Vladimir Nabokov","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The jealous Athena turned Arachne into which kind of animal?","CorrectAnswer":"spider","Answer2":"snake","Answer3":"donkey","Answer4":"rat","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the title of George Bernard Shaw’s play about Joan of Arc?","CorrectAnswer":"St Joan","Answer2":"Joan of Arc","Answer3":"Joan D'arc","Answer4":"Our Joan","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following authors are not in the top ten best-selling literature authors of all time?","CorrectAnswer":"Stephen King","Answer2":"Agatha Christie","Answer3":"Danielle Steel","Answer4":"Gilbert Patten","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Holden Caulfield is the main character in which book?","CorrectAnswer":"The Catcher In The Rye","Answer2":"Catch 22","Answer3":"Moby Dick","Answer4":"1984","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Shylock is a character in which Shakespeare play?","CorrectAnswer":"The Merchant Of Venice","Answer2":"Measure For Measure","Answer3":"Othello","Answer4":"The Comedy Of Errors","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In The Lord of the Rings, what is the name of the inn in Bree?","CorrectAnswer":"The Prancing Pony","Answer2":"The Red Stallion","Answer3":"The Merry Mare","Answer4":"The Spotted Gelding","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which book would one find the childlike human species named Elois?","CorrectAnswer":"The Time Machine","Answer2":"Day Of The Triffids","Answer3":"Brave New World","Answer4":"Dune","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which book would one find the trog like human species named Morlocks?","CorrectAnswer":"The Time Machine","Answer2":"Dune","Answer3":"Brave New World","Answer4":"The Day Of The Triffids","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'The Hunchback of Notre Dame'?","CorrectAnswer":"Victor Hugo","Answer2":"Gustave Flaubert","Answer3":"Voltaire","Answer4":"Alexandre Dumas","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Mrs Dalloway'?","CorrectAnswer":"Virginia Woolf","Answer2":"James Joyce","Answer3":"D H Lawrence","Answer4":"Graham Greene","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'The Lord of the Flies'?","CorrectAnswer":"William Golding","Answer2":"George Orwell","Answer3":"Aldous Huxley","Answer4":"Joseph Conrad","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many tasks did Hercules have to fulfill?","CorrectAnswer":"12","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"24","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How long did Robinson Crusoe spend on the island?","CorrectAnswer":"28 years, 2 months and 19 days","Answer2":"2 years, 8 months and 12 days","Answer3":"55 years, 4 months and 3 days","Answer4":"7 years, 9 months and 22 days","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was 'The Once and Future King'?","CorrectAnswer":"Arthur","Answer2":"Elvis","Answer3":"Idi Amin","Answer4":"Arargon","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which sport is referred to in ‘Antony and Cleopatra’?","CorrectAnswer":"Billiards","Answer2":"Snooker","Answer3":"Pool","Answer4":"Darts","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who is not one of King Lears daughters?","CorrectAnswer":"Celia","Answer2":"Cordelia","Answer3":"Goneril","Answer4":"Regan","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Lewis Carroll's book Alice's Adventures in Wonderland was banned in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"China","Answer2":"USA","Answer3":"France","Answer4":"Ireland","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In Which Dickens Novel Does Mr Micawber Appear?","CorrectAnswer":"David Copperfield","Answer2":"Oliver Twist","Answer3":"A Christmas carol","Answer4":"Great Expectations","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who wrote the book The Moons A Balloon?","CorrectAnswer":"David Niven","Answer2":"H.G. Wells","Answer3":"Jules Verne","Answer4":"Julie Andrews","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was Casanova's first name?","CorrectAnswer":"Giacoma","Answer2":"Alberto","Answer3":"Benito","Answer4":"Francesco","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which book would one find the character named 'Pip'?","CorrectAnswer":"Great Expectations","Answer2":"Wind in the Willows","Answer3":"Jurassic Park","Answer4":"Rob Roy","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the name of the cat in Shakespeare's Macbeth?","CorrectAnswer":"Greymalkin","Answer2":"Tybalt","Answer3":"Tao","Answer4":"Kitty","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Finnegan's Wake'?","CorrectAnswer":"James Joyce","Answer2":"Bram Stocker","Answer3":"W B Yeats","Answer4":"Samuel Beckett","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What are the names of the two main characters in Diana Gabaldon's highland saga novels?","CorrectAnswer":"Jamie and Claire","Answer2":"Fergus and Fiona","Answer3":"Rab and Elizabeth","Answer4":"Hamish and Maggie","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who wrote The Day of the Triffids?","CorrectAnswer":"John Wyndam","Answer2":"Stephen King","Answer3":"Douglas Adams","Answer4":"Jules Verne","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Dan Brown's book The Da Vinci Code was banned in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Lebanon","Answer2":"Ireland","Answer3":"Poland","Answer4":"Italy","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who lives at Number Four Privat Drive?","CorrectAnswer":"Mr and Mrs Dursley","Answer2":"Toad of Toad Hall","Answer3":"Mary Poppins","Answer4":"Winnie-The-Pooh","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the name of the man servant in 'Around the world in 80 days'?","CorrectAnswer":"Pas Partout","Answer2":"Cato","Answer3":"Giles","Answer4":"Machu Picchu","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the name of the ship in 'Moby Dick'?","CorrectAnswer":"Pequod","Answer2":"Essex","Answer3":"Boston","Answer4":"Surprise","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Mr Darcy is an arrogant gentleman in which novel?","CorrectAnswer":"Pride and Prejudice","Answer2":"A Passage to India","Answer3":"Animal Farm","Answer4":"The Great Gatsby","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who wrote the poem A Red Red Rose?","CorrectAnswer":"Robert Burns","Answer2":"Shakespeare","Answer3":"Dante","Answer4":"Stephen King","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the name of Don Quixote's horse?","CorrectAnswer":"Rosinate","Answer2":"Betty","Answer3":"Isabella","Answer4":"Theresa","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who wrote the poem The Lady of the Lake?","CorrectAnswer":"Sir Walter Scott","Answer2":"T.S. Eliot","Answer3":"King Henry VIII","Answer4":"Shakespeare","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which town did Tom Sawyer live?","CorrectAnswer":"St Petersburg","Answer2":"Bern","Answer3":"Hamburg","Answer4":"Rome","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which cartoonist created Spider Man?","CorrectAnswer":"Steve Ditko","Answer2":"Walt Disney","Answer3":"Gary Larson","Answer4":"Bob Montana","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The title of which Pink Floyd album is also a chapter in 'The Wind In The Willows'?","CorrectAnswer":"The Piper At The Gates Of Dawn","Answer2":"Wish You Were Here","Answer3":"Meddle","Answer4":"Animals","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who wrote 'Utopia' in 1516?","CorrectAnswer":"Thomas More","Answer2":"William Shakespeare","Answer3":"Christopher Marlowe","Answer4":"Francis Bacon","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which book is there an inn called Admiral Benbow?","CorrectAnswer":"Treasure Island","Answer2":"Peter Pan","Answer3":"Lord of the Rings","Answer4":"Gullivers Travels","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In the book The Last Of The Mohicans what was the name of Chingachgook's only son?","CorrectAnswer":"Uncas","Answer2":"Mingo","Answer3":"Lightfoot","Answer4":"Magua","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which Italian city do Romeo and Juliet live?","CorrectAnswer":"Verona","Answer2":"Naples","Answer3":"Milano","Answer4":"Pisa","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which two men are waiting for Godot?","CorrectAnswer":"Vladimir and Estragon","Answer2":"Bob and Ted","Answer3":"Benno and Babe","Answer4":"Pumpkin and Honey Bunny","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which former conservative leader wrote a biography on William Wilberforce in 2007?","CorrectAnswer":"William Hague","Answer2":"John Major","Answer3":"Iain Duncan Smith","Answer4":"Michael Howard","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Prime Minister won a Nobel prize for literature?","CorrectAnswer":"Winston Churchill","Answer2":"William Pitt","Answer3":"Margret Thatcher","Answer4":"Tony Blair","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The jellyfish consists of how much water?","CorrectAnswer":"95%","Answer2":"85%","Answer3":"75%","Answer4":"65%","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many moons does Earth have?","CorrectAnswer":"1","Answer2":"0","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"8","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many atoms are there in a molecule of water?","CorrectAnswer":"3","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"1","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Cows have how many stomachs?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"3","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many wisdom teeth does the average adult have?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"2","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The octal numbering system consistes of how many digits?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"6","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many legs does a spider have?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"12","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many sides does a Nonogon have?","CorrectAnswer":"9","Answer2":"19","Answer3":"0","Answer4":"99","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which year did Pfizer Inc introduce it's Viagra drug to the market?","CorrectAnswer":"1997","Answer2":"1987","Answer3":"1977","Answer4":"2007","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The binary system of numbers uses which two digits?","CorrectAnswer":"1 and 0","Answer2":"1 and 2","Answer3":"1 and 10","Answer4":"10 and 100","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many millimetres are there in one inch?","CorrectAnswer":"25.4 mm","Answer2":"10.4 mm","Answer3":"250.4 mm","Answer4":"100.4 mm","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which scientist was born in Germany in 1879, became a Swiss citizen in 1901 and later became a US citizen in 1940?","CorrectAnswer":"Albert Einstein","Answer2":"Max Planck","Answer3":"Niels Bohr","Answer4":"Ludwig Boltzmann","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What lives in a Formicarium?","CorrectAnswer":"Ants","Answer2":"Turtles","Answer3":"Apes","Answer4":"Butterflies","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is removed during an appendectomy?","CorrectAnswer":"Appendix","Answer2":"Bone Marrow","Answer3":"Kidney","Answer4":"Tonsils","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who first argued that the world was not flat? ","CorrectAnswer":"Aristotle","Answer2":"Columbus","Answer3":"Archimedes","Answer4":"Magellan","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where did the dingo originate?","CorrectAnswer":"Australia","Answer2":"Africa","Answer3":"Asia","Answer4":"Europe","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of the following colours would make you appear the slimest? ","CorrectAnswer":"Black","Answer2":"White","Answer3":"Pink","Answer4":"Orange","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is classified by the A B O system?","CorrectAnswer":"Blood","Answer2":"Skin Colour","Answer3":"Fingerprints","Answer4":"Genetics","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the loudest animal on earth?","CorrectAnswer":"Blue whale","Answer2":"Cricket","Answer3":"Human","Answer4":"Howler monkey","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the name of the small tracking file left by websites on your computer?","CorrectAnswer":"Cookie","Answer2":"Worm","Answer3":"Spider","Answer4":"Trojan","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What can't a Giraffe do?","CorrectAnswer":"cough","Answer2":"run","Answer3":"sleep","Answer4":"hear","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"An Aberdeen Angus is a type of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Cow","Answer2":"Dog","Answer3":"Pig","Answer4":"Plant","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the chemical symbol for Chromium?","CorrectAnswer":"Cr","Answer2":"Ch","Answer3":"Kr","Answer4":"Cm","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the name of the supercomputer that defeated chess master Garri Kasparov in 1997?","CorrectAnswer":"Deep Blue","Answer2":"Deep Thought","Answer3":"Deep Waters","Answer4":"Deep End","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of the following animals is believed to be the first to be domesticated?","CorrectAnswer":"Dog","Answer2":"Cat","Answer3":"Cow","Answer4":"Rabbit","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What does a Joule unit measure?","CorrectAnswer":"Energy","Answer2":"Work","Answer3":"Pressure","Answer4":"Light","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"A tortoiseshell cat is most likely what?","CorrectAnswer":"Female","Answer2":"Deaf","Answer3":"Blind","Answer4":"Male","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Pyrophobia is the fear of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Fire","Answer2":"Thunder","Answer3":"Skyscrapers","Answer4":"Plastic","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"According to Newton, mass times acceleration is equal to what?","CorrectAnswer":"Force","Answer2":"Power","Answer3":"Velocity","Answer4":"Torque","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What does a Hertz unit measure?","CorrectAnswer":"Frequency","Answer2":"Energy","Answer3":"Pressure ","Answer4":"Radioactivity","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"If you had rubella what would you have caught?","CorrectAnswer":"German measles","Answer2":"Chicken Pox","Answer3":"Whooping cough","Answer4":"Mumps","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which country introduced the worlds first diesel locomotive in 1912?","CorrectAnswer":"Germany","Answer2":"United Kingdom","Answer3":"Unites States","Answer4":"France","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of the following is a metal that will not rust?","CorrectAnswer":"Gold","Answer2":"Silver","Answer3":"Nickel","Answer4":"Zinc","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Alopecia describes a person with a lack of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Hair","Answer2":"Red blood cells","Answer3":"teeth","Answer4":"Memory","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Christopher Cockerel invented what?","CorrectAnswer":"Hovercraft","Answer2":"Cats Eyes on the road","Answer3":"Helecopter","Answer4":"Catamaran  ","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which is the largest planet in our solar system?","CorrectAnswer":"Jupiter","Answer2":"Saturn","Answer3":"Uranus","Answer4":"Earth","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where in your body is your patella?","CorrectAnswer":"Knee","Answer2":"Elbow","Answer3":"Neck","Answer4":"Foot","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where in the body is the Patella?","CorrectAnswer":"Knee","Answer2":"Shoulder","Answer3":"Hip","Answer4":"Skull","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of the following metals is in a liquid state at room temperature","CorrectAnswer":"Mercury","Answer2":"Uranium","Answer3":"Sodium","Answer4":"Tungsten","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the chemical symbol for Sodium?","CorrectAnswer":"Na","Answer2":"N","Answer3":"So","Answer4":"S","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which is the most common gas in the atmosphere?","CorrectAnswer":"Nitrogen","Answer2":"Oxygen","Answer3":"Helium","Answer4":"Carbon Dioxide","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the most common blood type in humans?","CorrectAnswer":"O","Answer2":"A","Answer3":"A+","Answer4":"A-","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is not a primary colour?","CorrectAnswer":"orange","Answer2":"red","Answer3":"yellow","Answer4":"blue","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What do botanists study?","CorrectAnswer":"Plants","Answer2":"Biology","Answer3":"Dentistry","Answer4":"Fossils","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"K is the chemical symbol for which element?","CorrectAnswer":"Potassium","Answer2":"Chromium","Answer3":"Sodium","Answer4":"Carbon","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What plant does the Colorado beetle attack?","CorrectAnswer":"Potato","Answer2":"Carrot","Answer3":"Cabbage","Answer4":"Lettuce","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Mammals of the Order Marsupialia have what unique feature?","CorrectAnswer":"Pouches","Answer2":"Night vision","Answer3":"Webbed feet","Answer4":"Powerful legs","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What does a Pascal unit measure?","CorrectAnswer":"Pressure","Answer2":"Light","Answer3":"Radioactivity","Answer4":"Heat","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Na is the chemical symbol for which element?","CorrectAnswer":"Sodium","Answer2":"Nitrogen","Answer3":"Potassium","Answer4":"Neon","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"With which name do we refer to a male cat?","CorrectAnswer":"Tomcat","Answer2":"Bobcat","Answer3":"Topcat","Answer4":"Fleabag","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"John Logie Baird is credited with which invention?","CorrectAnswer":"TV","Answer2":"Radio","Answer3":"Telephone","Answer4":"Gramaphone","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the hottest planet in our solar system?","CorrectAnswer":"Venus","Answer2":"Mercury","Answer3":"Mars","Answer4":"Earth","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Tim Berners-Lee is known as the inventor of what?","CorrectAnswer":"World Wide Web","Answer2":"Apple Computers","Answer3":"Computer Mouse","Answer4":"Email","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which plant gives absynthe its hallucinogenic properties?","CorrectAnswer":"wormwood","Answer2":"holly","Answer3":"mistletoe","Answer4":"juniper","Category":"Science","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which temperature has the same value in degrees in both centigrade and Fahrenheit?","CorrectAnswer":"-40","Answer2":"0","Answer3":"37","Answer4":"-273","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many moons does Venus have?","CorrectAnswer":"0","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"3","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What percentage of US dogs are overweight?","CorrectAnswer":"40%","Answer2":"80%","Answer3":"60%","Answer4":"10%","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many feet in a fathom?","CorrectAnswer":"6","Answer2":"8","Answer3":"12","Answer4":"36","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In computing how many bits make one byte?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"16","Answer3":"12","Answer4":"4","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many arms does a squid have?","CorrectAnswer":"10","Answer2":"8","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"12","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many sides does a dodecagon have?","CorrectAnswer":"12","Answer2":"10","Answer3":"20","Answer4":"22","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the number of the last Apollo mission?","CorrectAnswer":"17","Answer2":"13","Answer3":"29","Answer4":"14","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many moons does Saturn have?","CorrectAnswer":"18","Answer2":"8","Answer3":"28","Answer4":"48","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"On average, how many hours a day does a Koala bear spend sleeping?","CorrectAnswer":"22","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"12","Answer4":"8","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many miles must one walk in order to burn off a pound of fat?","CorrectAnswer":"34","Answer2":"4","Answer3":"14","Answer4":"64","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"According to Guinness what is the record number of children borne by one woman?","CorrectAnswer":"69","Answer2":"26","Answer3":"43","Answer4":"88","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many nuclear power plants are there in the USA?","CorrectAnswer":"109","Answer2":"59","Answer3":"209","Answer4":"509","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many chemical elements are there?","CorrectAnswer":"112","Answer2":"212","Answer3":"312","Answer4":"412","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many litres are there in a barrel of oil?","CorrectAnswer":"159","Answer2":"59","Answer3":"29","Answer4":"189","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The first robot was introduced in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1921","Answer2":"1941","Answer3":"1951","Answer4":"1891","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Bikini was a concept by Louis Réard, but in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1946","Answer2":"1966","Answer3":"1926","Answer4":"1906","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The first working computer mouse was developed by Douglas Engelbart in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1963","Answer2":"1973","Answer3":"1983","Answer4":"1993","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The LCD or Liquid Crystal Display was first developed by James Fergason in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1971","Answer2":"1981","Answer3":"1961","Answer4":"1951","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The world's firsr pocket calculator was invented by the Sharp Corporation in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1971","Answer2":"1981","Answer3":"1991","Answer4":"1961","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did Ernő Rubik invent the Rubik's cube?","CorrectAnswer":"1974","Answer2":"1964","Answer3":"1984","Answer4":"1954","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The first Mobile phone was invented by Bell Labs in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1977","Answer2":"1987","Answer3":"1982","Answer4":"1972","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Compact Disc was first developed by Philips Electronics and Sony Corp and released in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1980","Answer2":"1985","Answer3":"1990","Answer4":"1975","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"DNA fingerprinting was first explained to the world by Alec Jeffreys in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1985","Answer2":"1975","Answer3":"1965","Answer4":"1995","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year was the satellite Galileo launched?","CorrectAnswer":"1989","Answer2":"1979","Answer3":"1999","Answer4":"1969","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did Tim Berners-Lee introduce the phrase World Wide Web?","CorrectAnswer":"1990","Answer2":"1985","Answer3":"1995","Answer4":"1980","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many muscles are there in an elephants trunk?","CorrectAnswer":"40.000","Answer2":"4.000","Answer3":"400","Answer4":"40","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many feet long was the largest Blue Whale ever seen?","CorrectAnswer":"110 ft","Answer2":"55 ft","Answer3":"210 ft","Answer4":"550 ft","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What speed can a human reach in free fall?","CorrectAnswer":"155 miles per hr","Answer2":"225 miles per hr","Answer3":"55 miles per hour","Answer4":"355 miles per hour","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The first ballpoint pen was invented by Laszlo Biro in which decade?","CorrectAnswer":"1930s","Answer2":"1950s","Answer3":"1960s","Answer4":"1910s","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The world's first microwave oven was built and demonstrated by Percy Spencer in which decade?","CorrectAnswer":"1940s","Answer2":"1960s","Answer3":"1970s","Answer4":"1980s","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which decade did the World Health Organisation declare Smallpox eradicated?","CorrectAnswer":"1970s","Answer2":"1960s","Answer3":"1980s","Answer4":"1950s","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What generation is the so-called EDGE technology?","CorrectAnswer":"2.75G","Answer2":"2.5G","Answer3":"2G","Answer4":"3G","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"On average, how long does a giraffe sleep each day?","CorrectAnswer":"20 min","Answer2":"2 min","Answer3":"2 hours","Answer4":"20 hours","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How much taller is the Eiffel tower in the summertime?","CorrectAnswer":"6 inches","Answer2":"6 feet","Answer3":"6 yards","Answer4":"0 inches","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the sum of the internal angles in a hexagon?","CorrectAnswer":"720 degrees","Answer2":"360 degrees","Answer3":"1080 degrees","Answer4":"540 degrees","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"For how long is a dog pregnant?","CorrectAnswer":"9 Weeks","Answer2":"9 Days","Answer3":"9 Months","Answer4":"9 Fortnights","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What are Lanthanides?","CorrectAnswer":"A block of elements in the periodic table","Answer2":"Mountains on Earth","Answer3":"Mountains on the Moon","Answer4":"Bacterium","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which continent did the ostrich originate?","CorrectAnswer":"Africa","Answer2":"Australia","Answer3":"North America","Answer4":"Asia","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following insects requires no sleep?","CorrectAnswer":"Ant","Answer2":"Cockroach","Answer3":"Termite","Answer4":"Bee","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What part of the body does a turtle use to breathe?","CorrectAnswer":"Anus","Answer2":"Belly","Answer3":"Shell","Answer4":"Mouth","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What can you see with Kirlian photography?","CorrectAnswer":"aura","Answer2":"bones","Answer3":"blood cells","Answer4":"atoms","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Animals of the Ursidae family are what?","CorrectAnswer":"Bears","Answer2":"Dogs","Answer3":"Apes","Answer4":"Horses","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What colour skin does a polar bear have?","CorrectAnswer":"Black","Answer2":"White","Answer3":"Pink","Answer4":"Grey","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is an Ishihara test used for? ","CorrectAnswer":"Blindness","Answer2":"Pregnancy","Answer3":"Diabetes","Answer4":"Deafness","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Cats are born with which colour eyes?","CorrectAnswer":"Blue","Answer2":"Grey","Answer3":"Brown","Answer4":"Red","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What colour of tongue does the chow breed of dog have?","CorrectAnswer":"Blue","Answer2":"Red","Answer3":"Pink","Answer4":"Black","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What colour is lobster blood?","CorrectAnswer":"Blue","Answer2":"Red","Answer3":"Clear","Answer4":"Yellow","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What colour is octopus blood?","CorrectAnswer":"blue","Answer2":"red","Answer3":"green","Answer4":"yellow","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What are bactrians and dromedaries?","CorrectAnswer":"Camels","Answer2":"Elephants","Answer3":"Bears","Answer4":"Sloths","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which element is present in all organic compounds?","CorrectAnswer":"Carbon","Answer2":"Calcium","Answer3":"Copper","Answer4":"Californium","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What type of animal is considered good luck to have living at a theatre?","CorrectAnswer":"Cat","Answer2":"Dog","Answer3":"Bird","Answer4":"Mouse","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"A blue Orpington is a breed of which animal?","CorrectAnswer":"Chicken","Answer2":"Cat","Answer3":"Cow","Answer4":"Horse","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following animals has the best memory?","CorrectAnswer":"Chimpanzee","Answer2":"Elephant","Answer3":"Donkey","Answer4":"Rhino","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did John Harrison invent in 1757?","CorrectAnswer":"chronometer","Answer2":"parking meter","Answer3":"taxi meter","Answer4":"thermometer","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was not the name of a US space mission?","CorrectAnswer":"Colombus","Answer2":"Galileo","Answer3":"Cassini","Answer4":"Magellan","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which beetle loves potatoes?","CorrectAnswer":"Colorado","Answer2":"Florida","Answer3":"Utah","Answer4":"Oregon","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did Douglas Engelbart invent in 1963?","CorrectAnswer":"Computer Mouse","Answer2":"Pocket Calculator","Answer3":"Email","Answer4":"Mobile Phone","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What makes up 99.9% of the universe?","CorrectAnswer":"dark energy","Answer2":"H2O","Answer3":"stars","Answer4":"quarks","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"When cats have blue eyes they are also most likely what?","CorrectAnswer":"Deaf","Answer2":"Female","Answer3":"Male","Answer4":"Blind","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"A wapiti is a what?","CorrectAnswer":"Deer","Answer2":"Monkey","Answer3":"Bat","Answer4":"Rat","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What kind of animal is a Lurcher?","CorrectAnswer":"Dog","Answer2":"Reptile","Answer3":"Fish","Answer4":"Bird","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Cynophobia is the fear of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Dogs","Answer2":"China","Answer3":"The Dark","Answer4":"Spiders","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following insects can fly at a speed of around 60 mph?","CorrectAnswer":"Dragonfly","Answer2":"Mosquito","Answer3":"Hornet","Answer4":"Bee","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following mammals cannot jump?","CorrectAnswer":"Elephant","Answer2":"Giraffe","Answer3":"Hippo","Answer4":"Rhino","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the first digital computer?","CorrectAnswer":"ENIAC","Answer2":"MANIAC","Answer3":"PONTIAC","Answer4":"NICKNACK","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where in your body would you find the rods and cones?","CorrectAnswer":"Eyes","Answer2":"Ears","Answer3":"Fingers","Answer4":"Lungs","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which European country has the most nuclear power plants?","CorrectAnswer":"France","Answer2":"Russia","Answer3":"GB","Answer4":"Germany","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which type of bomb was invented by Edward Teller and Stanislaw Ulam in 1952?","CorrectAnswer":"Fusion","Answer2":"Fission","Answer3":"Bouncing","Answer4":"Napalm","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which European country has sent the most people into space?","CorrectAnswer":"Germany","Answer2":"United Kingdom","Answer3":"Italy","Answer4":"Bulgaria","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where in Europe is the Barbary ape most likely found?","CorrectAnswer":"Gibralta","Answer2":"Greece","Answer3":"Bulgaria","Answer4":"Portugal","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following animals are not rodents?","CorrectAnswer":"Hedgehogs","Answer2":"Rats","Answer3":"Gophers","Answer4":"Chipmunks","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What does a 'Hippophagic' eat?","CorrectAnswer":"horse meat","Answer2":"dog meat","Answer3":"cat meat","Answer4":"whale meat","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Ir is the chemical symbol for which element?","CorrectAnswer":"Iridium","Answer2":"Iron","Answer3":"Iodine","Answer4":"Iritum","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is a bird’s ‘gizzard’?","CorrectAnswer":"It’s second stomach","Answer2":"It's beak","Answer3":"It's tail feather","Answer4":"It's distinctive colour","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the chemical symbol for Potassium?","CorrectAnswer":"K","Answer2":"P","Answer3":"Po","Answer4":"Ka","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What are young squirrels called?","CorrectAnswer":"Kittens","Answer2":"Pups","Answer3":"Kids","Answer4":"Ankle biters","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What are baby beavers called?","CorrectAnswer":"Kittens","Answer2":"Pups","Answer3":"Cubs","Answer4":"Pests","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mg is the chemical symbol for which element?","CorrectAnswer":"Magnesium","Answer2":"Manganese","Answer3":"Molybdenum","Answer4":"Tungsten","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mn is the chemical symbol for which element?","CorrectAnswer":"Manganese","Answer2":"Magnesium","Answer3":"Molybdenum","Answer4":"Tungsten","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the scientific name for laughing gas?","CorrectAnswer":"Nitrous oxide","Answer2":"Carbon dioxide","Answer3":"Sulphur dioxide","Answer4":"Nitrous dioxide","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What colour is an aircraft's black box?","CorrectAnswer":"Orange","Answer2":"Red","Answer3":"White","Answer4":"Black","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"With which name do we refer to a female cat?","CorrectAnswer":"Queen","Answer2":"Doe","Answer3":"Bitch","Answer4":"Kitty","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What does a Becquerel unit measure?","CorrectAnswer":"Radioactivity","Answer2":"Energy","Answer3":"Pressure","Answer4":"Frequency","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following animals can last the longest without water?","CorrectAnswer":"Rat","Answer2":"Camel","Answer3":"Human","Answer4":"Goat","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The common cold is what kind of virus?","CorrectAnswer":"Rhino","Answer2":"Leo","Answer3":"Avian","Answer4":"Pisces","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the chemical symbol for Antimony?","CorrectAnswer":"Sb","Answer2":"Ti","Answer3":"T","Answer4":"Sn","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following is a theory in physics?","CorrectAnswer":"Schrodinger's Cat","Answer2":"Schrodinger's Rat","Answer3":"Schrodinger's Hat","Answer4":"Schrodinger's Bat","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was not the name of a US space mission?","CorrectAnswer":"Scout","Answer2":"Mariner","Answer3":"Ranger","Answer4":"Pioneer","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did Otto Frederick Rohwedder invent in 1928 that changed the world forever?","CorrectAnswer":"Sliced bread","Answer2":"RADAR","Answer3":"The refrigerator","Answer4":"The television","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What does an OLF unit measure?","CorrectAnswer":"smell","Answer2":"taste","Answer3":"light ","Answer4":"heat","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the chemical symbol for Tin?","CorrectAnswer":"Sn","Answer2":"Ti","Answer3":"T","Answer4":"Sb","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"On the Mohs scale the hardest substance is diamond - what's the softest?","CorrectAnswer":"Talcum Powder","Answer2":"Wheat Flour","Answer3":"Sugar","Answer4":"Skin dust","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the chemical symbol for Titanium?","CorrectAnswer":"Ti","Answer2":"Sn","Answer3":"T","Answer4":"Sb","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Ti is the chemical symbol for which element?","CorrectAnswer":"Titanium","Answer2":"Tin","Answer3":"Thorium","Answer4":"Thulium","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which part of the human body contains the most gold?","CorrectAnswer":"Toenails","Answer2":"Fingernails","Answer3":"Hair","Answer4":"Skin","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"W is the chemical symbol for which element?","CorrectAnswer":"Tungsten","Answer2":"Magnesium","Answer3":"Molybdenum","Answer4":"Manganese","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which planet in the Solar System is closest in size to Earth? ","CorrectAnswer":"Venus","Answer2":"Mercury","Answer3":"Mars","Answer4":"Uranus","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of Jurij Gagarin's space capsule?","CorrectAnswer":"Vostok I","Answer2":"MIR","Answer3":"Sojus II","Answer4":"Sputnik I","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Ergasiophobia is the fear of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Work","Answer2":"Flatulence","Answer3":"Odour","Answer4":"Belching","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which plant gives absinthe its hallucinogenic properties?","CorrectAnswer":"wormwood","Answer2":"mandrake","Answer3":"agara","Answer4":"belladonna","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What kind of star is our sun?","CorrectAnswer":"Yellow Dwarf","Answer2":"Red Giant","Answer3":"Brown Dwarf","Answer4":"White Dwarf","Category":"Science","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many stomachs does a moth have?","CorrectAnswer":"0","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"32","Answer4":"102","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which percentage of the worlds population has an I.Q. of 120 or more ?","CorrectAnswer":"12.50%","Answer2":"1.20%","Answer3":"25.50%","Answer4":"48.50%","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many hearts does an earthworm have?","CorrectAnswer":"5","Answer2":"0","Answer3":"1","Answer4":"250","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many 'arms' does a snowflake have?","CorrectAnswer":"6","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"9","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many minutes does it take rays from the sun to reach the earth","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"12","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many people have walked on the moon? ","CorrectAnswer":"12","Answer2":"9","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"3","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many inches to a cubit?","CorrectAnswer":"18","Answer2":"16","Answer3":"12","Answer4":"21","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many brains does a leech have?","CorrectAnswer":"32","Answer2":"0","Answer3":"1","Answer4":"102","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many gallons of water can a camel drink in 10 minutes?","CorrectAnswer":"35","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"15","Answer4":"25","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many muscles does it take to move your hand?","CorrectAnswer":"35","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"15","Answer4":"65","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many cubic feet are there in three cubic yards?","CorrectAnswer":"81","Answer2":"9","Answer3":"144","Answer4":"27","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many years is 1,000,000 hours?","CorrectAnswer":"114","Answer2":"111","Answer3":"211","Answer4":"214","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many sq metres was ENIAC, the worlds first electronic computer?","CorrectAnswer":"170","Answer2":"70","Answer3":"7","Answer4":"770","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the ball point pen introduced?","CorrectAnswer":"1938","Answer2":"1958","Answer3":"1888","Answer4":"1908","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Ray Tomlinson sent the world's first email in which year?","CorrectAnswer":"1971","Answer2":"1981","Answer3":"1991","Answer4":"2001","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year was the first black tulip cultivated?","CorrectAnswer":"1986","Answer2":"1896","Answer3":"2006","Answer4":"1926","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many hairs does the average human head have?","CorrectAnswer":"100.000","Answer2":"1,000,000","Answer3":"10.000","Answer4":"1.000","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Roughly how many glasses of milk can one cow produce in one year?","CorrectAnswer":"120.000","Answer2":"520.000","Answer3":"20.000","Answer4":"720.000","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the highest ever recorded temperature in the Libyan desert?","CorrectAnswer":"136 degrees Fahrenheit","Answer2":"180 degrees Fahrenheit","Answer3":"156 degrees Fahrenheit","Answer4":"236 degrees Fahrenheit","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the speed of light?","CorrectAnswer":"186,272 miles per second","Answer2":"84,272 miles per second","Answer3":"286,272 miles per second","Answer4":"1,188 ,272 miles per second","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In 1776 what was the average height of an Englishman?","CorrectAnswer":"5 ft 7 inches","Answer2":"5 ft 4 inches","Answer3":"6 foot","Answer4":"5 ft 1 inch","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How long does the light from the sun take to reach the earth?","CorrectAnswer":"8.5 min","Answer2":"8.5 hours","Answer3":"8.5 sec","Answer4":"8.5 days","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Bamboo plants can grow how many cm per day?","CorrectAnswer":"90cm","Answer2":"10cm","Answer3":"30cm","Answer4":"170cm","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the most common blood group in Europe?","CorrectAnswer":"A +","Answer2":"A -","Answer3":"B +","Answer4":"O -","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What does a nidoligist study?","CorrectAnswer":"Bird Nests","Answer2":"Waves","Answer3":"Clouds","Answer4":"Caves","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which of these elements is the heaviest?","CorrectAnswer":"Caesium","Answer2":"Rubidium","Answer3":"Potassium","Answer4":"Sodium","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many earths would fit inside the sun?","CorrectAnswer":"circa 1,000,000","Answer2":"circa 1,000","Answer3":"circa 10,000","Answer4":"circa 100,000","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Hypermetropic people are what?","CorrectAnswer":"far sighted","Answer2":"obese","Answer3":"underfed","Answer4":"moody","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Fredrick Sanger invented which life saver?","CorrectAnswer":"Insulin","Answer2":"Safety Pin","Answer3":"Inflatable Life Raft","Answer4":"Aspirin","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which of the following is a bird AND a fruit?","CorrectAnswer":"Kiwi","Answer2":"Juju","Answer3":"Mango","Answer4":"Pear","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which planet has the tallest mountain?","CorrectAnswer":"Mars","Answer2":"Earth","Answer3":"Jupiter","Answer4":"Venus","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What does the medical term dolent mean?","CorrectAnswer":"pain","Answer2":"fever","Answer3":"numb","Answer4":"internal","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which of these is a name of a fish?","CorrectAnswer":"Parr","Answer2":"Aragon","Answer3":"Boleyn","Answer4":"Seymour","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the only food a cockroach wont eat?","CorrectAnswer":"pickle","Answer2":"snail","Answer3":"marshmellow","Answer4":"porridge","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What won't a cockroach eat?","CorrectAnswer":"pickles","Answer2":"porridge","Answer3":"curry","Answer4":"marmite","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which planet has the most eccentric orbit?","CorrectAnswer":"Pluto","Answer2":"Mercury","Answer3":"Earth","Answer4":"Venus","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is a Flemish Giant?","CorrectAnswer":"Rabbit","Answer2":"Star","Answer3":"Sprout","Answer4":"Mountain","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"A 'bind' is a group of what?","CorrectAnswer":"salmon","Answer2":"crows","Answer3":"zebras","Answer4":"cobras","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which planet has the most moons?","CorrectAnswer":"Saturn","Answer2":"Jupiter","Answer3":"Neptune","Answer4":"Uranus","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which bird has a record 25,000 feathers?","CorrectAnswer":"Swan","Answer2":"Goose","Answer3":"Albatross","Answer4":"Stork","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Somatology is the study of what?","CorrectAnswer":"The Body","Answer2":"The Cosmos","Answer3":"Insects","Answer4":"Somalia","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who invented the sub-machine gun in 1920?","CorrectAnswer":"Thompson","Answer2":"Gattling","Answer3":"Colt","Answer4":"Winchester","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Brontophobia is the fear of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Thunder","Answer2":"Skyscrapers","Answer3":"Elephants","Answer4":"The Dark","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which VW auto was not named after a wind?","CorrectAnswer":"Touran","Answer2":"Passat","Answer3":"Scirocco","Answer4":"Bora","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"A Blue Whale has a heart roughly the size of a what?","CorrectAnswer":"VW Beetle","Answer2":"Basketball","Answer3":"Grapefruit","Answer4":"Peanut","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Anemophobia is the fear of what?","CorrectAnswer":"Wind","Answer2":"Spiders","Answer3":"The Dark","Answer4":"Fire","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the more usual name for Roentgen Rays?","CorrectAnswer":"X Rays","Answer2":"Gamma Rays","Answer3":"Ultra Violet Rays","Answer4":"Magnetic Resonance","Category":"Science","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many holes are there on a ten pin bowling ball?","CorrectAnswer":"3","Answer2":"4","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"5","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many rings on the Olympic flag?","CorrectAnswer":"5","Answer2":"4","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"7","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many Olympic gold medals did mark Spitz win in Munich in 1972?","CorrectAnswer":"7","Answer2":"8","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"5","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many lanes does an Olympic swimming pool have?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"12","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many rounds are there in a professional boxing title contest?","CorrectAnswer":"12","Answer2":"10","Answer3":"20","Answer4":"8","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In badminton, how many points win a single game?","CorrectAnswer":"15","Answer2":"20","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"19","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which 1982 World Cup team featured the talents of Zico, Socrates and Falcao?","CorrectAnswer":"Brazil","Answer2":"Italy","Answer3":"Spain","Answer4":"Argentina","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which swimming stroke was not introduced to the Olympics until 1956?","CorrectAnswer":"Butterfly","Answer2":"Freestyle","Answer3":"Breaststroke","Answer4":"Doggy Style","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which country has Zinedine Zidane played for?","CorrectAnswer":"France","Answer2":"Italy","Answer3":"Spain","Answer4":"Brazil","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In tennis, what name is given to winning the four major tournaments in a season?","CorrectAnswer":"Grand Slam","Answer2":"Outright","Answer3":"World Champion","Answer4":"Major Slam","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which of these is another name for a golf course?","CorrectAnswer":"Links","Answer2":"Pitch","Answer3":"Steps","Answer4":"Suite","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which tennis players nickname was 'The Rocket'?","CorrectAnswer":"Rod Laver","Answer2":"Fred Perry","Answer3":"Pete Sampras","Answer4":"John Newcombe","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which sport is played in Roland Garros?","CorrectAnswer":"tennis","Answer2":"rugby","Answer3":"football","Answer4":"polo","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which superstar was named 'The Great One'?","CorrectAnswer":"Wayne Gretsky","Answer2":"Rod Laver","Answer3":"Eddie Edwards","Answer4":"Dixie Dean","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What type of sportsman was the toy Stretch Armstrong dressed as?","CorrectAnswer":"Wrestler","Answer2":"Boxer","Answer3":"Archer","Answer4":"Cricketer","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many Gold Medals did Jesse Owens win in the 1936 Berlin Olympics? ","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"5","Answer4":"6","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many hulls are there on a Catamaran?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"1","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many balls are used in a game of croquet?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"1","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many players are there in a polo team?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"16","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many times did cyclist Miguel Indurain win the Tour de France in the 1990s?","CorrectAnswer":"5","Answer2":"9","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"None","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many games make up a match in squash?","CorrectAnswer":"5","Answer2":"10","Answer3":"12","Answer4":"8","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many players of an ice hockey team can be on the ice at the same time?","CorrectAnswer":"6","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"7","Answer4":"8","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many disciplines make up the men’s gymnastics competition at the Olympics?","CorrectAnswer":"6","Answer2":"8","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"4","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the minimum number of points needed to win a game of squash?","CorrectAnswer":"9","Answer2":"10","Answer3":"20","Answer4":"15","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many players in a baseball team?","CorrectAnswer":"9","Answer2":"11","Answer3":"15","Answer4":"7","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What number shirt did Pele usually wear when playing for Brazil?","CorrectAnswer":"10","Answer2":"9","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"1","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many players are there in a Hockey team?","CorrectAnswer":"11","Answer2":"15","Answer3":"9","Answer4":"10","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In American Football, how many players from one team are allowed on the grid at any one time?","CorrectAnswer":"11","Answer2":"15","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"12","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many minutes of play are there in an American football match?","CorrectAnswer":"60","Answer2":"90","Answer3":"120","Answer4":"150","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which year did tennis legend 'Rocket' Rod Laver win his last Grand Slam?","CorrectAnswer":"1969","Answer2":"1977","Answer3":"1981","Answer4":"1958","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which city hosted the 1992 summer Olympic games?","CorrectAnswer":"Barcelona","Answer2":"Atlanta","Answer3":"Moscow","Answer4":"Seoul","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did the dog named Pickles find?","CorrectAnswer":"Coupe Jules Rimet","Answer2":"Davis Cup","Answer3":"Federation Cup","Answer4":"F.A. Cup","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The ugliest salad bowl in the world","CorrectAnswer":"Davis Cup","Answer2":"F.A. Cup","Answer3":"Ryder Cup","Answer4":"Football World Cup","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Wayne Gretzky was a superstar in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"ice hochey","Answer2":"golf","Answer3":"tennis","Answer4":"boxing","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which tennis player has not lost four Wimbledon singles finals?","CorrectAnswer":"Ivan Lendl","Answer2":"Jimmy Connors","Answer3":"Boris Becker","Answer4":"Ken Rosewall","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the only tennis player to have won the US OPEN on three different surfaces?","CorrectAnswer":"Jimmy Conners ","Answer2":"Roger Federer ","Answer3":"Big Bill Tilden     ","Answer4":"Andre Agassi","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mika Hakkinen was Formula 1 champion in 1998 and 1999 in which car?","CorrectAnswer":"McLaren-Mercedes","Answer2":"Ferrari","Answer3":"Renault","Answer4":"Benetton Ford","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"'El tri' is the nickname for which national football team? ","CorrectAnswer":"Mexico","Answer2":"Brazil","Answer3":"Spain","Answer4":"Switzerland","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which summer Olympic Games were boycotted by most African countries?","CorrectAnswer":"Montreal 76","Answer2":"Moscow 80","Answer3":"Munich 72","Answer4":"USA 84","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Jacky Ickx was a superstar in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"motor racing","Answer2":"cycling","Answer3":"soccer","Answer4":"tennis","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Every player in the Bulgarian national team at the 1994 Football World Cup had a name ending in which letters?","CorrectAnswer":"ov","Answer2":"ki","Answer3":"us","Answer4":"an","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country has won a record four World Championships in mens field hockey?","CorrectAnswer":"Pakistan","Answer2":"Germany","Answer3":"Holland","Answer4":"Ireland","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"80% of all the footballs in the world are made in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Pakistan","Answer2":"USA","Answer3":"Mexico","Answer4":"Australia","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the last man to win the Grand Slam in tennis?","CorrectAnswer":"Rod Laver","Answer2":"Bjorn Borg","Answer3":"Roger Federer","Answer4":"Ivan Lendl","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which stadium is named after a WW I flying ace?","CorrectAnswer":"Roland Garros","Answer2":"Giuseppe Meazza","Answer3":"Fratton Park","Answer4":"Bernabeu","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which city saw Steffi Graf win Olympic gold?","CorrectAnswer":"Seoul","Answer2":"Barcelona","Answer3":"Los Angeles","Answer4":"Moscow","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"'Wedel' is a term in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"Skiing","Answer2":"Darts","Answer3":"Chess","Answer4":"Formula One","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In golf what name is given to the No 3 wood?","CorrectAnswer":"Spoon","Answer2":"Knife","Answer3":"Fork","Answer4":"Ladel","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which woman thrashed her opponent 6-0 6-0 in the 1988 French Open final?","CorrectAnswer":"Stefi Graf","Answer2":"Venus Williams","Answer3":"Billy Jean King","Answer4":"Virginia Wade","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What weighs 4lb 6oz at the Olympics?","CorrectAnswer":"The Discuss","Answer2":"The Javelin","Answer3":"The Olympic Torch","Answer4":"The Medals (Gold, Silver, Bronze)","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which football world cup had the highest average attendance figures?","CorrectAnswer":"USA 94","Answer2":"Brazil 50","Answer3":"England 66","Answer4":"Italy 90","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"If a golf hole is 130 yards long, what would its par be?","CorrectAnswer":"3","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"5","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many laps are completed towin a speedway race?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"10","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many baseball gloves can be made with the leather from one cow?","CorrectAnswer":"5","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"25","Answer4":"55","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How old was Boris Becker when he won his first Wimbledon singles title?","CorrectAnswer":"17","Answer2":"16","Answer3":"15","Answer4":"18","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many Wimbledon titles did Billie Jean King win?","CorrectAnswer":"20","Answer2":"30","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"5","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many laps are run in a 10000-metre track race?","CorrectAnswer":"25","Answer2":"20","Answer3":"30","Answer4":"35","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year were the summer olympic games in Berlin? ","CorrectAnswer":"1936","Answer2":"1932","Answer3":"1942","Answer4":"1948","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year were the summer olympic games in Montreal? ","CorrectAnswer":"1976","Answer2":"1980","Answer3":"1974","Answer4":"1978","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year were the summer olympic games in Moscow?","CorrectAnswer":"1980","Answer2":"1982","Answer3":"1978","Answer4":"1976","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Countries from which continent boycotted the 1976 summer olympics in Montreal?","CorrectAnswer":"Africa","Answer2":"Europe","Answer3":"Asia","Answer4":"South  America","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first black woman to win both the US Open and Wimbledon?","CorrectAnswer":"Althea Gibson","Answer2":"Venus Williams","Answer3":"Shirley Fry","Answer4":"Serena Williams","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who is not an accomplished fencer?","CorrectAnswer":"Arnold Schwarzenegger","Answer2":"Gene Wilder","Answer3":"Elijah Wood","Answer4":"Antonio Banderas","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which sport do the Minnesota Twins play?","CorrectAnswer":"Baseball","Answer2":"Ice Hiockey","Answer3":"Basketball","Answer4":"Football","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first american to win the mens singles title at Wimbledon?","CorrectAnswer":"Big Bill Tilden","Answer2":"Donald Budge","Answer3":"Jack Kramer","Answer4":"Bobby Riggs","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which NHL superstar had the nickname 'The Golden Jet'?","CorrectAnswer":"Bobby Hull","Answer2":"Bobby Orr","Answer3":"Gordie Howe","Answer4":"Stan Mikita","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Figure skating champion Elvis Stojko was from which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Canada","Answer2":"Russia","Answer3":"USA","Answer4":"Bulgaria","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the captain of Brazil when they won the 1970 football world cup?","CorrectAnswer":"Carlos Alberto","Answer2":"Pele","Answer3":"Romario","Answer4":"Socrates","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Eddy Merckx was a superstar in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"cycling","Answer2":"soccer","Answer3":"tennis","Answer4":"baseball","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who has a black belt in judo?","CorrectAnswer":"David Lee Roth","Answer2":"Bill Gates","Answer3":"David Beckham","Answer4":"Prince Charles","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Nine time Olympic gold medal winner Paavo Nurmi was from which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Finland","Answer2":"Russia","Answer3":"India","Answer4":"Hungary","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Juan Manuel Fangio was a superstar in which sport in the 1950s?","CorrectAnswer":"formula one","Answer2":"tennis","Answer3":"baseball","Answer4":"soccer","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which sport does one compete for the Stanley Cup?","CorrectAnswer":"ice hockey","Answer2":"polo","Answer3":"golf","Answer4":"squash","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which poem greets contestants to centre court Wimbledon?","CorrectAnswer":"If","Answer2":"All the worlds a stage","Answer3":"The road not taken","Answer4":"A dream within a dream","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who does not have a black belt in karate?","CorrectAnswer":"Jennifer Lopez","Answer2":"Sharon Stone","Answer3":"Chuck Norris","Answer4":"Guy Ritchie","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the name of the mascot bear at the 1980 summer Olympic games in Moscow?","CorrectAnswer":"Mischa","Answer2":"Olga","Answer3":"Igor","Answer4":"Nikita","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which NHL hockey team has won the most Stanley Cups?","CorrectAnswer":"Montreal Canadiens","Answer2":"Toronto Maple Leafs","Answer3":"Boston Bruins","Answer4":"New York Rangers","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"At which Formula One circuit would one find the 'Lesmo Bend'?","CorrectAnswer":"Monza","Answer2":"Circuit Gilles Villeneuve","Answer3":"Hockenheimring","Answer4":"Silverstone","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Speed skating originated in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Netherlands","Answer2":"Canada","Answer3":"Norway","Answer4":"Russia","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which professional sport awards the Lady Byng Memorial Trophy each year for the 'Most Gentlemanly Player'?","CorrectAnswer":"NHL","Answer2":"NFL","Answer3":"PGA","Answer4":"NBA","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"'Nati' is the nickname for which countrys football team?","CorrectAnswer":"Switzerland","Answer2":"South Korea","Answer3":"Holland","Answer4":"Mexico","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Gossima was the original name for which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"Table Tennis","Answer2":"Lawn Tennis","Answer3":"Badminton","Answer4":"Snooker","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Lew Hoad was a superstar in which sport in the 1950s?","CorrectAnswer":"tennis","Answer2":"ice hockey","Answer3":"baseball","Answer4":"soccer","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"A 'Miller' is a move in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"Trampolining","Answer2":"Diving","Answer3":"Chess","Answer4":"Ice Hockey","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which superstar wore the number 99 ?","CorrectAnswer":"Wayne Gretzky","Answer2":"Zidane","Answer3":"Dixie Dean","Answer4":"Sebastian Coe","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the main solid ingredient of Alphabet soup?","CorrectAnswer":"Pasta","Answer2":"Rice","Answer3":"Potato","Answer4":"Egg","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many cups of tea does the average English person drink a day?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"16","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many frogs does the average Frenchmen eat a year?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"24","Answer4":"88","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Since the late 1980s what is the newest Smartie colour?","CorrectAnswer":"blue","Answer2":"pink","Answer3":"yellow","Answer4":"green","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The name of which island is also an orange liquor?","CorrectAnswer":"Curacao","Answer2":"Ibiza","Answer3":"Grenada","Answer4":"Anguilla","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country does 'Pivo' mean beer?","CorrectAnswer":"Czech Rep","Answer2":"Portugal","Answer3":"Greece","Answer4":"France","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which four letters on a bottle of French wine indicate it is sweet?","CorrectAnswer":"DOUX","Answer2":"VOUX","Answer3":"FOUX","Answer4":"SOUX","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where is the cordon bleu school of cooking?","CorrectAnswer":"Paris","Answer2":"Lyon","Answer3":"Brussels","Answer4":"Amsterdam","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The letters TGFOP can be found on what?","CorrectAnswer":"tea","Answer2":"cigars","Answer3":"silver","Answer4":"caviar","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many coffee beans are said to be in every cup of Nescafe?","CorrectAnswer":"43","Answer2":"33","Answer3":"53","Answer4":"63","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many bottles of wine does the average Frenchman drink a year?","CorrectAnswer":"140","Answer2":"240","Answer3":"70","Answer4":"370","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which food means 'immortal' when translated?","CorrectAnswer":"ambrosia","Answer2":"curry","Answer3":"pizza","Answer4":"nectar","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which drink is named after a royal family?","CorrectAnswer":"Bourbon","Answer2":"Vodka","Answer3":"Rum","Answer4":"Tequila","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which country does 'Sor' mean beer?","CorrectAnswer":"Hungary","Answer2":"Portugal","Answer3":"Greece","Answer4":"Czech Rep","Category":"Food & Drink","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many summer Olympic games were cancelled because of World War 2?","CorrectAnswer":"2","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"0","Answer4":"3","Category":"Games","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many games must you win to win a normal set in tennis?","CorrectAnswer":"6","Answer2":"8","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"5","Category":"Games","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How long is a regulation soccer game?","CorrectAnswer":"90 Minutes","Answer2":"60 Minutes","Answer3":"120 Minutes","Answer4":"30 Minutes","Category":"Games","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which game are ","CorrectAnswer":"Chess","Answer2":"Poker","Answer3":"Cribbage","Answer4":"Bridge","Category":"Games","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"If you are playing Southern Cross, you are playing a form of which game?","CorrectAnswer":"Poker","Answer2":"Cribbage","Answer3":"Bridge","Answer4":"Backgammon","Category":"Games","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which game might a person have a ","CorrectAnswer":"Poker","Answer2":"Cribbage","Answer3":"Bridge","Answer4":"Backgammon","Category":"Games","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many stones does a backgammon player have?","CorrectAnswer":"15","Answer2":"12","Answer3":"13","Answer4":"17","Category":"Games","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"If you ","CorrectAnswer":"Cribbage","Answer2":"Bridge","Answer3":"Backgammon","Answer4":"Chess","Category":"Games","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following is not one of the train stations on a Monopoly board?","CorrectAnswer":"Paddington","Answer2":"Fenchurch Street ","Answer3":"Marylebone Street","Answer4":"Kings Cross","Category":"Games","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"If you're killing a goomba, what game are you playing?","CorrectAnswer":"Super Mario","Answer2":"Doom","Answer3":"Sonic the Hedgehog","Answer4":"Quake","Category":"Games","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many Jack's eyes are visible in a standard pack of playing cards?","CorrectAnswer":"12","Answer2":"16","Answer3":"8","Answer4":"4","Category":"Games","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many eyes are there in a deck of cards?","CorrectAnswer":"42","Answer2":"36","Answer3":"38","Answer4":"40","Category":"Games","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many white dots in a traditional Pacman arcade game ?","CorrectAnswer":"240","Answer2":"200","Answer3":"140","Answer4":"100","Category":"Games","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Complete the saying: Every dog has his ___","CorrectAnswer":"Day","Answer2":"Week","Answer3":"Bone","Answer4":"Night","Category":"Language","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The names of the days of the week in English have their origins with Pagan gods from which mythology?","CorrectAnswer":"Norse","Answer2":"Celtic","Answer3":"Greek","Answer4":"Roman","Category":"Language","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many letters does the longest word in the English language have?","CorrectAnswer":"45","Answer2":"25","Answer3":"75","Answer4":"115","Category":"Language","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What colour is viridian?","CorrectAnswer":"green","Answer2":"yellow","Answer3":"red","Answer4":"blue","Category":"Language","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the most commonly used word in English conversation?","CorrectAnswer":"I","Answer2":"it","Answer3":"you","Answer4":"at","Category":"Language","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is kept in a grimoire?","CorrectAnswer":"magic spells","Answer2":"butterflies","Answer3":"cigars","Answer4":"stamps","Category":"Language","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following is not a surname in the USA?","CorrectAnswer":"Q","Answer2":"J","Answer3":"F","Answer4":"W","Category":"Language","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the opposite of the orient?","CorrectAnswer":"the occident","Answer2":"the ocrident","Answer3":"the oricrent","Answer4":"the arient","Category":"Language","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many letters are there in the Hawaiin alphabet?","CorrectAnswer":"12","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"26","Answer4":"126","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many different languages were spoken in the former Soviet Union?","CorrectAnswer":"149","Answer2":"49","Answer3":"29","Answer4":"229","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Voetbal means football in which European language?","CorrectAnswer":"Dutch","Answer2":"German","Answer3":"Polish","Answer4":"Bulgarian","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Jalkapallo means football in which European language?","CorrectAnswer":"Finnish","Answer2":"Albanian","Answer3":"Hungarian","Answer4":"Greek","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Podos Fairo means football in which European language?","CorrectAnswer":"Greek","Answer2":"Italian","Answer3":"Spanish","Answer4":"Portugese","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is a Big Mac called in Japan?","CorrectAnswer":"Makudonaldo","Answer2":"Big Mac","Answer3":"Mikadomako","Answer4":"Bigimaki","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Pilka Nozna means football in which European language?","CorrectAnswer":"Polish","Answer2":"Russian","Answer3":"Swedish","Answer4":"Portugese","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How does one communicate in the language called Todomo?","CorrectAnswer":"touching","Answer2":"words","Answer3":"sign language","Answer4":"whistling","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How does one communicate in the language called Gogo?","CorrectAnswer":"words","Answer2":"touching","Answer3":"whistling","Answer4":"sign language","Category":"Language","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many self portraits did Rembrandt paint?","CorrectAnswer":"62","Answer2":"462","Answer3":"12","Answer4":"262","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many paintings did Van Gogh sell in his lifetime?","CorrectAnswer":"1","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"11","Category":"Literature","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many times a day does the average American open the fridge door?","CorrectAnswer":"22","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"44","Answer4":"99","Category":"Miscellaneous","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many articles of clothing does the average American male buy for himself each year?","CorrectAnswer":"35","Answer2":"15","Answer3":"5","Answer4":"55","Category":"Miscellaneous","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many instruments accompany someone singing a cappella?","CorrectAnswer":"0","Answer2":"1","Answer3":"2","Answer4":"3","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many ways did Paul Simon claim there were to leave your lover?","CorrectAnswer":"50","Answer2":"40","Answer3":"30","Answer4":"20","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which year did the original Woodstock Festival take place?","CorrectAnswer":"1969","Answer2":"1972","Answer3":"1966","Answer4":"1978","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which year is a Prince album?","CorrectAnswer":"1999","Answer2":"1984","Answer3":"2001","Answer4":"1969","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'The Living Daylights'?","CorrectAnswer":"A-Ha","Answer2":"Duran Duran","Answer3":"Wings","Answer4":"Tina Turner","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which animal was a hit for Fleetwood Mac?","CorrectAnswer":"Albatross","Answer2":"Butterfly","Answer3":"Hyena","Answer4":"Giraffe","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Madness?","CorrectAnswer":"Baggy Trousers","Answer2":"Jeans On","Answer3":"Angst In My Pants","Answer4":"Necktie","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which way was a hit for Gerry Rafferty?","CorrectAnswer":"Baker Street","Answer2":"Boulevard of broken dreams","Answer3":"2120 South Michigan Avenue","Answer4":"Thunder Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which singer was born Robert Zimmerman?","CorrectAnswer":"Bob Dylan","Answer2":"Eric Clapton","Answer3":"Simon Le Bon","Answer4":"Bob Seger","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Nobody Does It Better'?","CorrectAnswer":"Carly Simon","Answer2":"Sheena Easton","Answer3":"Tina Turner","Answer4":"Nancy Sinatra","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which girl was a Simon and Garfunkel hit?","CorrectAnswer":"Cecilia","Answer2":"Roxanne","Answer3":"Gloria","Answer4":"Angie","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was a hit for the Police?","CorrectAnswer":"De Do Do Do, De Da Da Da","Answer2":"Da Doo Ron Ron","Answer3":"Zip A Dee Doo Dah","Answer4":"Do Wah Diddy Diddy ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'A View To A Kill'?","CorrectAnswer":"Duran Duran","Answer2":"A-Ha","Answer3":"Garbage","Answer4":"Tom Jones","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is Marshall Mathers stage name?","CorrectAnswer":"Eminem","Answer2":"Ice-T","Answer3":"Ice Cube","Answer4":"Grandmaster Flash","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What were the Beatles called in the early 1960s?","CorrectAnswer":"Fab Four","Answer2":"Four Tops","Answer3":"Pre Fabs","Answer4":"Four Seasons","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the title of the Beatles first number one hit in the UK?","CorrectAnswer":"From me to you","Answer2":"Help","Answer3":"Yesterday","Answer4":"A hard days night","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which famous brothers are members of the band Oasis?","CorrectAnswer":"Gallagher","Answer2":"Everly","Answer3":"Moore","Answer4":"Reid","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who released the best selling album 'American Idiot' in 2005?","CorrectAnswer":"Green Day","Answer2":"Mariah Carey","Answer3":"Madonna","Answer4":"Coldplay","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What  was a hit for Neil Young?","CorrectAnswer":"Heart of Gold","Answer2":"Silver Bird","Answer3":"Golden Years","Answer4":"Hi-Ho Silver Lining","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which hotel was a hit for Elvis?","CorrectAnswer":"Heartbreak Hotel","Answer2":"Hotel California","Answer3":"Handog Hotel Room","Answer4":"Holiday Inn","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who fought the law (and the law won)?","CorrectAnswer":"I","Answer2":"You","Answer3":"We","Answer4":"They","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who had a hit with 'Lust For Life'?","CorrectAnswer":"Iggy Pop","Answer2":"The Police","Answer3":"Poco","Answer4":"Prince","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Where were Alphaville ","CorrectAnswer":"In Japan","Answer2":"In Sweden","Answer3":"In the USA","Answer4":"In New York","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What time was a hit for Wilson Pickett?","CorrectAnswer":"In the Midnight Hour","Answer2":"After Midnight","Answer3":"Midnight Special","Answer4":"Midnight in Chelsea","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which question did Duran Duran ask in 1983?","CorrectAnswer":"Is there something I should know?","Answer2":"Is she really going out with him?","Answer3":"How will I know?","Answer4":"How long?","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the title of the Rolling Stones first number one hit in the UK?","CorrectAnswer":"It's all over now","Answer2":"Ruby Tuesday","Answer3":"Get off my cloud","Answer4":"Angie","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who composed three number one UK hits in 1981?","CorrectAnswer":"John Lennon","Answer2":"Freddy Mercury","Answer3":"Michael Jackson","Answer4":"Julio Iglesias","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who's band was The Quarrymen?","CorrectAnswer":"John Lennon","Answer2":"Elvis Costello","Answer3":"Barry Gibb","Answer4":"Mick Jagger","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang 'Don't Go Breaking My Heart' with Elton John in 1976?","CorrectAnswer":"Kiki Dee","Answer2":"Lulu","Answer3":"Nancy Sinatra","Answer4":"Sheena Easton","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which metal band had a hit with ' Whole Lotta Love'?","CorrectAnswer":"Led Zeppelin","Answer2":"Black Sabbath","Answer3":"Deep Purple","Answer4":"Ten Years After","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which rock star married All Saints singer Nicole Appleton in 2008?","CorrectAnswer":"Liam Gallagher","Answer2":"Bono","Answer3":"Mick Jagger","Answer4":"Jarvis Cocker","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who managed the punk group The Sex Pistols?","CorrectAnswer":"Malcolm McClaren","Answer2":"John Lydon","Answer3":"Sid Vicious","Answer4":"They were unmanagable","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Barry Manilow had a hit with which song?","CorrectAnswer":"Mandy","Answer2":"Randy","Answer3":"Candy","Answer4":"Dandy","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which band is fronted by James Dean Bradfield?","CorrectAnswer":"Manic Street Preachers","Answer2":"The Stereophonics","Answer3":"The Alarm","Answer4":"Goldie Lookin Chain","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which state was a hit for the Bee Gees?","CorrectAnswer":"Massachusetts","Answer2":"Alaska","Answer3":"California","Answer4":"Vermont","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which day was a hit for the Mamas and Papas?","CorrectAnswer":"Monday Monday","Answer2":"Ruby Tuesday","Answer3":"Wednesday Morning 3 am","Answer4":"Friday on my mind","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which Mr. was a hit for ELO ?","CorrectAnswer":"Mr. Blue Sky","Answer2":"Mr. Bojangles","Answer3":"Mr. Tambourine Man","Answer4":"Mr. Cabdriver ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which Mrs. was a hit for Simon and Garfunkel?","CorrectAnswer":"Mrs. Robinson","Answer2":"Mrs. Brown, You've got a lovely daughter","Answer3":"Mrs. Vanderbilt","Answer4":"Mrs. Sippi","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which Beatle often played his instrument upside down?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul","Answer2":"John","Answer3":"George","Answer4":"Ringo","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Stevie Wonder and Michael Jackson have both recorded duets with which former Beatle?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul McCartney","Answer2":"Ringo Starr","Answer3":"John Lennon","Answer4":"George Harrison","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Falco?","CorrectAnswer":"Rock me Amadeus","Answer2":"Roll over Beethoven","Answer3":"Mozart lives upstairs","Answer4":"Stravinky's shoes","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was Herbie Hancocks's spacey hit in 1984?","CorrectAnswer":"Rockit","Answer2":"Space Oddity","Answer3":"Major Tom","Answer4":"Rocket Man","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which day was a hit for the Rolling Stones?","CorrectAnswer":"Ruby Tuesday","Answer2":"Fridays Child","Answer3":"Monday Monday","Answer4":"Friday on my mind","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was Louis Armstrong's nickname?","CorrectAnswer":"Satchmo","Answer2":"Bird","Answer3":"Godfather of Soul","Answer4":"Boss","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Diamonds Are Forever'?","CorrectAnswer":"Shirley Bassey","Answer2":"Matt Munro","Answer3":"Nancy Sinatra","Answer4":"Sheena Easton","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Goldfinger'?","CorrectAnswer":"Shirley Bassey","Answer2":"Lulu","Answer3":"Nancy Sinatra","Answer4":"Tom Jones","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Moonraker'?","CorrectAnswer":"Shirley Bassey","Answer2":"Nancy Sinatra","Answer3":"Tom Jones","Answer4":"Matt Munro","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was a hit song for Lulu?","CorrectAnswer":"Shout","Answer2":"Scream","Answer3":"Cry","Answer4":"Yell","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is Eric Clapton's nickname?","CorrectAnswer":"Slow Hand","Answer2":"The Boss","Answer3":"Plonk","Answer4":"His Ericness","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"David Bowie had a spacey hit with which song?","CorrectAnswer":"Space Oddity","Answer2":"Rocket Man","Answer3":"Mercury Rising","Answer4":"2000 Light Years From Home","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Julio Iglesias is a singer from which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Spain","Answer2":"Portugal","Answer3":"Brazil","Answer4":"Peru","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who had a number one UK hit with Jack Your Body in 1987?","CorrectAnswer":"Steve 'Silk' Hurley","Answer2":"Steve 'Satin' Hurley","Answer3":"Steve 'Cotton' Hurley","Answer4":"Steve 'Woolly' Hurley","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang 'No More Heroes'?","CorrectAnswer":"Stranglers","Answer2":"Bowie","Answer3":"Leonard Cohen","Answer4":"Tina Turner","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was a hit for the Archies?","CorrectAnswer":"Sugar Sugar","Answer2":"Sugar Me","Answer3":"Brown Sugar","Answer4":"Sugar and Spice","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was a hit for the Eurythmics?","CorrectAnswer":"Sweet Dreams","Answer2":"Dream On","Answer3":"Dream Lover","Answer4":"Dreams Of The Everyday Housewife","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Goldeneye'?","CorrectAnswer":"Tina Turner","Answer2":"Madonna","Answer3":"Sheryl Crow","Answer4":"Lulu","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which band had an instrumental hit with 'Telstar'?","CorrectAnswer":"Tornadoes","Answer2":"Shadows","Answer3":"Dakotas","Answer4":"Ventures","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which city was a hit for Ultravox?","CorrectAnswer":"Vienna","Answer2":"Barcelona","Answer3":"Tokyo","Answer4":"Bangkok","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which tube station was a hit for the Kinks?","CorrectAnswer":"Waterloo Sunset","Answer2":"Vauxhall to Lambeth Bridge","Answer3":"Possibly Parson's Green","Answer4":"No sleep till Hammersmith","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Seasons in the Sun","CorrectAnswer":"Westlife","Answer2":"Boyzone","Answer3":"Take That","Answer4":"East 17","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Live And Let Die'?","CorrectAnswer":"Wings","Answer2":"Herb Alpert","Answer3":"Tom Jones","Answer4":"Matt Munro","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the first free rock festival, held over 3 days in 1969?","CorrectAnswer":"Woodstock","Answer2":"Glastonbury","Answer3":"Reading","Answer4":"Love Parade","Category":"Music","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many operas did Beethoven compose?","CorrectAnswer":"1","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"4","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many foot pedals does a concert grand piano have?","CorrectAnswer":"3","Answer2":"2","Answer3":"0","Answer4":"4","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"For every seven white keys on a piano, how many black keys are there?","CorrectAnswer":"5","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"3","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many keys are there on a piano?","CorrectAnswer":"88","Answer2":"64","Answer3":"66","Answer4":"86","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What number was not a Boy Band?","CorrectAnswer":"711","Answer2":"East 17","Answer3":"Heaven 17","Answer4":"112","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"'Sunday Girl' was Blondie's second number one.  In what year was this?","CorrectAnswer":"1979","Answer2":"1981","Answer3":"1977","Answer4":"1983","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What time is it in the song Manic Monday?","CorrectAnswer":"6 o'clock","Answer2":"12 o'clock","Answer3":"3 o'clock","Answer4":"5 o'clock","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did Leo Sayer wear to promote the song ‘I won’t let the show go on‘?","CorrectAnswer":"A clown costume","Answer2":"A police uniform","Answer3":"A straightjacket","Answer4":"A sherif's uniform","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"A Hard Day's Night","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"Yellow Submarine","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"A Hard Day's Night","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"Yellow Submarine","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who broke his ankle tripping over a stuffed toy that was thrown on stage by a fan?","CorrectAnswer":"A New Kid on the Block","Answer2":"A Backstreet Boy","Answer3":"A Beach Boy","Answer4":"A Boyszone Boy","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Festfolk was the original name for which group ?","CorrectAnswer":"ABBA","Answer2":"Motorhead","Answer3":"Simon and Garfunkel","Answer4":"The Beach Boys","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Abbey Road","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Yellow Submarine","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Abbey Road","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Yellow Submarine","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the first Brit with a number one hit single in the USA?","CorrectAnswer":"Acker Bilk","Answer2":"Beatles","Answer3":"Petula Clark","Answer4":"Herman's Hermits","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The Beatles had a spacey hit with which song?","CorrectAnswer":"Across the Universe","Answer2":"Space Oddity","Answer3":"Rocket Man","Answer4":"Milky Way","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What time was a hit for Eric Clapton?","CorrectAnswer":"After Midnight","Answer2":"Midnight in Moscow","Answer3":"Midnight Special","Answer4":"Midnite Dynamos","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Both Lenny Kravitz and The Guess Who had a hit with which woman?","CorrectAnswer":"American","Answer2":"Kentucky","Answer3":"Hard Headed","Answer4":"Super","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a Pink Floyd album?","CorrectAnswer":"Animals","Answer2":"Humans","Answer3":"Aliens","Answer4":"Dinosaurs","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which ABBA member was not born in Sweden?","CorrectAnswer":"Anni-Frid","Answer2":"Bjorn ","Answer3":"Benny","Answer4":"Agnetha","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Mike and the Mechanics?","CorrectAnswer":"Another cup of coffee","Answer2":"Black coffee in bed","Answer3":"Espresso","Answer4":"Coffee table song","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Rock band AC/DC come from which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Australia","Answer2":"United Kingdom","Answer3":"USA","Answer4":"Canada","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit song for ACDC?","CorrectAnswer":"Back in Black","Answer2":"Mean in Green","Answer3":"Knight in White","Answer4":"Stay in Grey","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Carl and the Passions changed band name to what?","CorrectAnswer":"Beach Boys","Answer2":"The Turtles","Answer3":"The Animals","Answer4":"The Chipmunks","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which 'Dog' was a hit for Led Zeppelin?","CorrectAnswer":"Black Dog","Answer2":"Hey Bulldog","Answer3":"Diamond Dogs","Answer4":"Me and you and a dog named  Boo","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which metal band had a hit with 'Paranoid'?","CorrectAnswer":"Black Sabbath","Answer2":"Deep Purple","Answer3":"Uriah Heep","Answer4":"Motorhead","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who released the best selling album 'Monkey Business' in 2005?","CorrectAnswer":"Blackeyed Peas","Answer2":"Coldplay","Answer3":"50 Cent","Answer4":"Green Day","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a chirpy hit with 'Rockin Robin' in the 60s?","CorrectAnswer":"Bobby Day","Answer2":"Bobby Vinton","Answer3":"Bobby Rydell","Answer4":"Bobby Vee ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a colourful hit with 'Roses are Red'?","CorrectAnswer":"Bobby Vinton","Answer2":"Bobby Vee","Answer3":"Bobby Darin","Answer4":"Bobby Rydell","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Jayne Torvill and Christopher Dean won olympic gold in 1984 dancing to which music?","CorrectAnswer":"Bolero","Answer2":"Carmen","Answer3":"Ballroom Blitz","Answer4":"Lady in Red","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"With which song did Lulu win the Eurovision song contest?","CorrectAnswer":"Boom Bang A Bang","Answer2":"Ding A Dong","Answer3":"A Ba Ni Bi","Answer4":"Diggi Loo Diggi Ley","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which book title was a hit for Toyah?","CorrectAnswer":"Brave New World","Answer2":"Romeo And Juliet","Answer3":"Islands In The Stream","Answer4":"Tom Sawyer","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did Elvis have 26 of?","CorrectAnswer":"Cadillacs","Answer2":"Thunderbirds","Answer3":"Mustangs","Answer4":"Corvettes","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a sweet hit song with 'Lollipop' in the 60s?","CorrectAnswer":"Chordettes","Answer2":"Ronettes","Answer3":"Velvelettes","Answer4":"Jaynettes","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which celebrity appeared in the Westlife music video Uptown Girl?","CorrectAnswer":"Claudia Schiffer","Answer2":"Billy Joel","Answer3":"Angelina Jolie","Answer4":"Diana Dors","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was a hit for Gorillaz?","CorrectAnswer":"Clint Eastwood","Answer2":"James Dean","Answer3":"Charlton Heston","Answer4":"Bruce Willis","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had an instrumental hit with 'Take 5'?","CorrectAnswer":"Dave Brubeck","Answer2":"Hot Butter","Answer3":"Duane Eddy","Answer4":"Herb Alpert","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a David Bowie album?","CorrectAnswer":"Diamond Dogs","Answer2":"Copper  Cats","Answer3":"Golden Geldings","Answer4":"Platinum Ponys","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which song was not a 70s disco hit?","CorrectAnswer":"Disco Disco","Answer2":"Disco Duck","Answer3":"Disco Inferno","Answer4":"Disco Lady","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Aerosmith?","CorrectAnswer":"Dream On","Answer2":"I Have A Dream  ","Answer3":"Dream Police","Answer4":"Sweet Dreams","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which band is not from 'Oz'?","CorrectAnswer":"Echo and the Bunnymen","Answer2":"INXS","Answer3":"Cold Chisel","Answer4":"Split Enz","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which pie is a Paul McCartney album?","CorrectAnswer":"Flaming","Answer2":"Humble","Answer3":"Cream","Answer4":"Pumpkin","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which book title was a hit for Metallica?","CorrectAnswer":"For Whom The Bell Tolls","Answer2":"Brave New World","Answer3":"Slaughterhouse Five","Answer4":"Taming Of The Shrew","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which son was a hit for Creedence Clearwater Revival?","CorrectAnswer":"Fortunate Son","Answer2":"Matthew and Son","Answer3":"Son of a Preacher man","Answer4":"Fathers and Sons","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the first person to have a number one album?","CorrectAnswer":"Frank Sinatra","Answer2":"Benny Hill","Answer3":"Acker Bilk","Answer4":"Richard Harris","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What  was a hit for Debbie Harry?","CorrectAnswer":"French Kissin","Answer2":"It's in his kiss","Answer3":"Kissess Sweeter Than Wine","Answer4":"Kissin in the back row of the movies","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'The World Is Not Enough'?","CorrectAnswer":"Garbage","Answer2":"A-Ha","Answer3":"Duran Duran","Answer4":"Rita Coolidge","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the nickname of Terrance Butler of Black Sabbath fame?","CorrectAnswer":"Geezer","Answer2":"Teezer","Answer3":"Beezer","Answer4":"Breezer","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did Ray Charles have ","CorrectAnswer":"Georgia","Answer2":"Virginia","Answer3":"Kentucky","Answer4":"Mississippi","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Licence To Kill'?","CorrectAnswer":"Gladys Knight","Answer2":"A-Ha","Answer3":"Duran Duran","Answer4":"Nancy Sinatra","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Welsh group had a hit with 'Guns Don't Kill People - Rappers Do'?","CorrectAnswer":"Goldie Lookin Chain","Answer2":"Manic Street Preachers","Answer3":"The Alarm","Answer4":"Catatonia","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Ry Cooder is famous for playing which instrument?","CorrectAnswer":"Guitar","Answer2":"Keyboards","Answer3":"Drums","Answer4":"Saxophone","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which moon is a Neil Young album?","CorrectAnswer":"Harvest","Answer2":"Blue","Answer3":"Crescent","Answer4":"Full","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What part of the body was a number one UK hit for the Pet Shop Boys in 1988?","CorrectAnswer":"Heart","Answer2":"Brain","Answer3":"Soul","Answer4":"Lips","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which reclusive band sold more singles than the Beatles in 1965?","CorrectAnswer":"Herman's Hermits","Answer2":"The Animals","Answer3":"The Zombies","Answer4":"Pink Floyd","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which 'Dog' was a hit for the Beatles?","CorrectAnswer":"Hey Bulldog","Answer2":"Black Dog","Answer3":"How much is that doggie in the window","Answer4":"I wanna be your dog","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which way was a hit for Bob Dylan?","CorrectAnswer":"Highway 61","Answer2":"Dead-End Street","Answer3":"Baker Street","Answer4":"Gasoline Alley","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which 'Cat' was a hit for Elton John?","CorrectAnswer":"Honky Cat","Answer2":"Year of the Cat","Answer3":"Cat's in the Cradle","Answer4":"Stray Cat Strut","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had an instrumental hit with 'Popcorn'?","CorrectAnswer":"Hot Butter","Answer2":"Apollo 100","Answer3":"Paul Mauriat","Answer4":"Surfaris","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which band was not from Liverpool?","CorrectAnswer":"Hothouse Flowers","Answer2":"Swinging Blue Jeans","Answer3":"Big in Japan","Answer4":"A Flock of Seagulls","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which animal was a hit for R.E.M. ?","CorrectAnswer":"Hyena","Answer2":"Butterfly","Answer3":"Albatross","Answer4":"Giraffe","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for the Bee Gees?","CorrectAnswer":"I.O.I.O","Answer2":"Da Da Da","Answer3":"Oo Oo Ee","Answer4":"C.O.D.","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Iron Butterfly?","CorrectAnswer":"In A Gadda Da Vida","Answer2":"Giddy Up A Ding Dong","Answer3":"Rama Lama Ding Dong","Answer4":"Sha La La La Lee","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Cliff Richard was born in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"India","Answer2":"Zanzibar","Answer3":"Germany","Answer4":"South Africa","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which book title was a hit for Dolly Parton?","CorrectAnswer":"Islands In The Stream","Answer2":"Pride And Prejudice","Answer3":"Gone With The Wind","Answer4":"A Midsummers Night's Dream","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which city was a hit for Johnny Cash?","CorrectAnswer":"Jackson","Answer2":"El Paso","Answer3":"Detroit","Answer4":"Galvaston","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who are the Glimmer Twins?","CorrectAnswer":"Jagger and Richards","Answer2":"Lennon and McCartney","Answer3":"Simon and Garfunkel","Answer4":"Chaz and Dave","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had three number one UK hits in 1989?","CorrectAnswer":"Jason Donovan","Answer2":"New Kids on the Block","Answer3":"Simple Minds","Answer4":"Bangles","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which reggae star had a hit with 'Vietnam'?","CorrectAnswer":"Jimmy Cliff","Answer2":"Bob Marley","Answer3":"Peter Tosh","Answer4":"Desmond Dekker","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the leader of The Quarrymen?","CorrectAnswer":"John Lennon","Answer2":"Elvis Costello","Answer3":"Elton John","Answer4":"Eric Clapton","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who were The Carpenters?","CorrectAnswer":"Karen and Richard","Answer2":"Karen and Todd","Answer3":"Karen and John","Answer4":"Karen and Joseph","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had an instrumental hit with 'Midnight in Moscow'?","CorrectAnswer":"Kenny Ball","Answer2":"Tornadoes","Answer3":"Duane Eddy","Answer4":"Ventures","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which football player had a top 10 hit in Germany with 'Head over heels in love'?","CorrectAnswer":"Kevin Keegan","Answer2":"Franz Beckenbauer","Answer3":"Gazza","Answer4":"Gary Neville","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Keith Emerson is famous for playing which instument?","CorrectAnswer":"Keyboards","Answer2":"Drums","Answer3":"Guitar","Answer4":"Saxophone","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which band was not a trio?","CorrectAnswer":"Kinks","Answer2":"Cream","Answer3":"Stray Cats","Answer4":"Police","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What kind of Lady was a hit for Uriah Heep?","CorrectAnswer":"Lady in Black","Answer2":"Lady in Red","Answer3":"Lady in Lace","Answer4":"Lady in the Red Hat","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who composed the music for West Side Story?","CorrectAnswer":"Leonard Bernstein","Answer2":"A Lloyd Webber","Answer3":"Cole Porter","Answer4":"Irving Berlin","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a hit with 'It's My Party'?","CorrectAnswer":"Lesley Gore","Answer2":"Little Eva","Answer3":"Dee Dee Sharp","Answer4":"Shelley Fabares","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a top 10 hit for Chubby Checker?","CorrectAnswer":"Let's Twist Again","Answer2":"Twist And Shout","Answer3":"Twistin The Night Away","Answer4":"Hey, Let's Twist","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which band is not Irish?","CorrectAnswer":"Little River Band","Answer2":"Thin Lizzy","Answer3":"Chieftans","Answer4":"Them","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was Jim Morrison's nickname?","CorrectAnswer":"Lizard King","Answer2":"Bird","Answer3":"Slowhand","Answer4":"Van the Man","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Kinks song was banned by the BBC?","CorrectAnswer":"Lola","Answer2":"Waterloo Sunset","Answer3":"You Really Got Me","Answer4":"Sunny Afternoon","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which city was the famous 'Marquee' music club?","CorrectAnswer":"London","Answer2":"New York","Answer3":"Glasgow","Answer4":"L.A.","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Dire Straits? ","CorrectAnswer":"Love Over Gold","Answer2":"Band Of Gold","Answer3":"Fool's Gold","Answer4":"Gold","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Donna Summer song was banned by the BBC?","CorrectAnswer":"Love To Love You","Answer2":"I Feel Love","Answer3":"On The Radio","Answer4":"Last  Dance","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'The Man With The Golden Gun'?","CorrectAnswer":"Lulu","Answer2":"Tom Jones","Answer3":"Sheena Easton","Answer4":"Tina Turner","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Fun Boy Three ?","CorrectAnswer":"Lunatics have taken over the asylum","Answer2":"19th nervous breakdown","Answer3":"Paranoid","Answer4":"They're coming to take me away, Ha-Haa !","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which mother was a hit for Boney M ?","CorrectAnswer":"Ma Baker","Answer2":"Mama told me not to come","Answer3":"Your Mother should know","Answer4":"What have they done to my song, Ma","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Sean Moore and Nicky Jones are members of which famous band?","CorrectAnswer":"Manic Street Preachers","Answer2":"The Stereophonics","Answer3":"The Alarm","Answer4":"Goldie Lookin Chain","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In Elton John's song Rocket Man which planet is ","CorrectAnswer":"Mars","Answer2":"Venus","Answer3":"Pluto","Answer4":"Saturn","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the first song ever recorded?","CorrectAnswer":"Mary had a little lamb","Answer2":"Happy Birthday","Answer3":"A bicycle built for two","Answer4":"God save the King","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which son was a hit for Cat Stevens?","CorrectAnswer":"Matthew and Son","Answer2":"Son of a preacher man","Answer3":"Fortunate Son","Answer4":"Fathers and Sons","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which spice girl comes from Leeds?","CorrectAnswer":"Mel B","Answer2":"Mel C","Answer3":"Gerry Halliwell","Answer4":"Emma Bunton","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which mother was a hit for Paul Simon ?","CorrectAnswer":"Mother and child reunion","Answer2":"Motherless children","Answer3":"Your mother should know","Answer4":"Mama told me not to come","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a Red Hot Chli Peppers album?","CorrectAnswer":"Mothers Milk","Answer2":"Mothers Ruin","Answer3":"Mothers Little Helper","Answer4":"Mothers of Invention","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'You Only Live Twice'?","CorrectAnswer":"Nancy Sinatra","Answer2":"Lulu","Answer3":"Shirley Bassey","Answer4":"Gladys Knight","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which US state was the 1969 Woodstock Festival?","CorrectAnswer":"New York","Answer2":"Ohio","Answer3":"Vermont","Answer4":"California","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which tube station was a hit for Motorhead?","CorrectAnswer":"No sleep till Hammersmith","Answer2":"The Guns of Brixton","Answer3":"Jeffrey Goes To Leicester Square","Answer4":"King's Cross Ladies","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which band is not from Wales?","CorrectAnswer":"OMD","Answer2":"Manic Street Preachers","Answer3":"Stereophonics","Answer4":"Amen Corner","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What number was not a Boy Band?","CorrectAnswer":"One Town","Answer2":"All-4-One","Answer3":"East 17","Answer4":"Heaven 17","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a heartbreaking hit with 'Lonely Boy'?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul Anka","Answer2":"Fabian","Answer3":"Bobby Vee","Answer4":"Frankie Avalon","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who is the vocalist in 'Mike and the Mechanics'?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul Carrack","Answer2":"Mike Rutherford","Answer3":"Phil  Collins","Answer4":"Boy George","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What kind of train was a hit for Cat Stevens?","CorrectAnswer":"Peace Train","Answer2":"Love Train","Answer3":"Runaway Train","Answer4":"Soul Train","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which song from The Stranglers was banned by the BBC?","CorrectAnswer":"Peaches","Answer2":"96 Tears","Answer3":"No More Heroes","Answer4":"Always The Sun","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the lead singer for The Herman's Hermit's?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Noone","Answer2":"Peter Day","Answer3":"Peter March","Answer4":"Peter Munday","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of Pink Floyds first album?","CorrectAnswer":"Piper at the gates of dawn","Answer2":"Sandman at the gates of twilight","Answer3":"Ferryman at the gates of Hades","Answer4":"Pauper at the gates of heaven","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of these Beatles albums was released first?","CorrectAnswer":"Please Please Me ","Answer2":"With the Beatles","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night","Answer4":"Beatles for Sale","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Please, Please Me","Answer2":"Yellow Submarine","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Frederick Bulsara was the lead singer for which group?","CorrectAnswer":"Queen","Answer2":"Cream","Answer3":"OMD","Answer4":"Small Faces","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the narrator on the album War Of The Worlds?","CorrectAnswer":"Richard Burton","Answer2":"Orson Wells","Answer3":"Anthony Hopkins","Answer4":"Spike Milligan","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which member of the Manic Street Preachers went missing and has never been found?","CorrectAnswer":"Richard Edwards","Answer2":"Sean Moore","Answer3":"Nicky Jones","Answer4":"James Dean Bradfield","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following artists have not sold over 500 million records worldwide?","CorrectAnswer":"Rolling Stones","Answer2":"The Beatles","Answer3":"Bing Crosby","Answer4":"Michael Jackson","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which book title was a hit for Dire Sraits?","CorrectAnswer":"Romeo And Juliet","Answer2":"Brave New World","Answer3":"Catch 22","Answer4":"For Whom The Bell Tolls","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a hit song with 'Be My Baby' in the 60s?","CorrectAnswer":"Ronettes","Answer2":"Chordettes","Answer3":"Jaynettes","Answer4":"Velvelettes","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"According to Blur, ","CorrectAnswer":"Rubbish","Answer2":"Trash","Answer3":"Garbage","Answer4":"Waste","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which girl was a hit for Starship in 1986?","CorrectAnswer":"Sara","Answer2":"Roxanne","Answer3":"Eloise","Answer4":"Cecilia","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which band is not from Scotland?","CorrectAnswer":"Saw Doctors","Answer2":"Simple Minds","Answer3":"Nazareth","Answer4":"Stone the Crows","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which soundtrack album did the Bee Gees release?","CorrectAnswer":"Sgt. Pepper's Lonely Hearts Club Band","Answer2":"Abbey Road","Answer3":"Help","Answer4":"Yellow Submarine","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a hit song with 'Leader Of The Pack'?","CorrectAnswer":"Shangri-Las","Answer2":"Ronettes","Answer3":"Shirelles","Answer4":"Chiffons","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'For Your Eyes Only'?","CorrectAnswer":"Sheena Easton","Answer2":"Madonna","Answer3":"Nancy Sinatra","Answer4":"Carly Simon","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In the song Waltzing Matilda, what is a Jumbuck?","CorrectAnswer":"Sheep","Answer2":"Goat","Answer3":"Horse","Answer4":"Kangaroo","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Tomorrow Never Dies'?","CorrectAnswer":"Sheryl Crow","Answer2":"Tina Turner","Answer3":"Rita Coolidge","Answer4":"Madonna","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who did Nick Berry play in Eastenders at the time of his first number one hit? ","CorrectAnswer":"Simon Wicks","Answer2":"Himself","Answer3":"Brian Wicks","Answer4":"Kevin Wicks","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which ship was a hit for the Beach Boys?","CorrectAnswer":"Sloop John B.","Answer2":"Proud Mary","Answer3":"Mississippi Quenn","Answer4":"Rainbow Warrior","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which book title was a hit for the Doors?","CorrectAnswer":"Spy In The House Of Love","Answer2":"Taming Of The Shrew","Answer3":"Quiet Days In Clichy","Answer4":"Faust","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who appeared a record 106 times on Top Of The Pops?","CorrectAnswer":"Status Quo","Answer2":"Adam and the Ants","Answer3":"T-Rex","Answer4":"The England World Cup Squad","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for the Pretenders?","CorrectAnswer":"Stop your sobbing","Answer2":"Crying in the rain","Answer3":"Tears on my pillow","Answer4":"Tears of a clown","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for the Rubettes?","CorrectAnswer":"Sugar Baby Love","Answer2":"Brown Sugar","Answer3":"Sugar Me","Answer4":"Sugar Sugar","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Blondie scored their second number one hit in 1979. Which song?","CorrectAnswer":"Sunday Girl","Answer2":"Heart of Glass","Answer3":"Call Me","Answer4":"One Way or Another","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Jack Black and Kyle Gass make up which famous band?","CorrectAnswer":"Tenacious D","Answer2":"The White Stripes","Answer3":"Chas N Dave","Answer4":"Erasure","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What kind of opera singer was Enrico Caruso?","CorrectAnswer":"Tenor","Answer2":"Bass","Answer3":"Soprano","Answer4":"Baritone","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which film is a Blur album?","CorrectAnswer":"The Great Escape ","Answer2":"The Longest Day","Answer3":"The Dam Busters","Answer4":"Catch 22","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which dance was a hit for Little Eva?","CorrectAnswer":"The Loco Motion","Answer2":"The Watusi","Answer3":"The Twist","Answer4":"Mashed Potatoes","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who were Davey, Peter, Michael and Mickey? ","CorrectAnswer":"The Monkees","Answer2":"The Turtles","Answer3":"The Animals","Answer4":"The Chipmunks","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the Skiffle group that John Lennon formed in 1957?","CorrectAnswer":"The Quarrymen","Answer2":"The Beatles","Answer3":"Johnny and the Moondogs","Answer4":"Silver Beetles ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was David Bowie's nickname?","CorrectAnswer":"The Thin White Duke","Answer2":"Glimmer Twins","Answer3":"Lizard King","Answer4":"King of Pop","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a number one hit for Chubby Checker?","CorrectAnswer":"The Twist","Answer2":"Twistin The Night Away","Answer3":"Twist And Shout","Answer4":"Twistin USA","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Napoleon XIV ?","CorrectAnswer":"They're coming to take me away, Ha-Haa !","Answer2":"19th Nervous Breakdown","Answer3":"Lunatics have taken over the asylum","Answer4":"Acute schizophrenia paranoia blues","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'Thunderball'?","CorrectAnswer":"Tom Jones","Answer2":"Matt Munro","Answer3":"Shirley Bassey","Answer4":"Lulu","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which book title was a hit for the band Rush?","CorrectAnswer":"Tom Sawyer","Answer2":"1984","Answer3":"Catch 22","Answer4":"Animal Farm","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What did Elvis do before he became King?","CorrectAnswer":"Truck Driver","Answer2":"Hairdresser","Answer3":"Pilot","Answer4":"Disc Jockey","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which day was a hit for the Moody Blues?","CorrectAnswer":"Tuesday Afternoon","Answer2":"Wednesday Morning 3 am","Answer3":"Stormy Monday","Answer4":"Another Saturday Night","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was a top 10 song for Sam Cooke?","CorrectAnswer":"Twistin The Night Away","Answer2":"The Twist","Answer3":"Peppermint Twist","Answer4":"Let's Twist Again","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a hit with the song 'Hawaii Five-0'?","CorrectAnswer":"Ventures","Answer2":"Surfaris","Answer3":"Tornadoes","Answer4":"Daytonas  ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which actor covered the Beatles song 'Lucy In The Sky With Diamonds'?","CorrectAnswer":"William Shatner","Answer2":"Peter Sellers","Answer3":"George Burns","Answer4":"Telly Savalas","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Yellow Submarine","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Scrambled Eggs was the working title for which Beatles song?","CorrectAnswer":"Yesterday","Answer2":"Hello Goodbye","Answer3":"She Loves You","Answer4":"Revolution","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which sign is a Pearl Jam album?","CorrectAnswer":"Yield","Answer2":"Stop","Answer3":"Dead End","Answer4":"Slow","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Freddy Mercury was born in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Zanzibar","Answer2":"India","Answer3":"Germany","Answer4":"Brazil","Category":"Music","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How old was Chopin when he composed his first polonaise?","CorrectAnswer":"7","Answer2":"4","Answer3":"11","Answer4":"16","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many records are selected by each castaway on Desert Island Discs?","CorrectAnswer":"8","Answer2":"10","Answer3":"6","Answer4":"12","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"On which floor do ","CorrectAnswer":"1st","Answer2":"2nd","Answer3":"3rd","Answer4":"4th","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The Rolling Stones had a spacey hit with which song?","CorrectAnswer":"2000 Light Years From Home","Answer2":"Across the Universe","Answer3":"Space Oddity","Answer4":"Uranus Rock","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the Volkswagen license plate found on the Beatles Abbey Road album cover?","CorrectAnswer":"28IF","Answer2":"14U2","Answer3":"14ALL","Answer4":"22BE","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"A Hard Day's Night","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"Yellow Submarine","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"A Hard Day's Night","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"Yellow Submarine","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"A Hard Day's Night","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"Yellow Submarine","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"A Hard Day's Night","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"Yellow Submarine","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Abbey Road","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Yellow Submarine","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Abbey Road","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Yellow Submarine","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Abbey Road","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Yellow Submarine","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Abbey Road","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Yellow Submarine","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which artist was a David Bowie song?","CorrectAnswer":"Andy Warhol","Answer2":"Vincent Van Gogh","Answer3":"Da Vinci","Answer4":"Rembrandt","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Chris de Burgh was born in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Argentina","Answer2":"Germany","Answer3":"India","Answer4":"Canada","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which bands last concert was coined 'the rooftop' concert?","CorrectAnswer":"Beatles","Answer2":"Who","Answer3":"Take That","Answer4":"Wham","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who sang duett with Cher in the 1994 re release of 'I Got You Babe'?","CorrectAnswer":"Bevis and Butthead","Answer2":"Homer Simpson","Answer3":"Bruce Willis","Answer4":"Don Johnson","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What colour Christmas was it for Elvis?","CorrectAnswer":"Blue","Answer2":"White","Answer3":"Green","Answer4":"Silver","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"John and Tom Fogerty were brothers in which band?","CorrectAnswer":"CCR","Answer2":"Kinks","Answer3":"Dire Straits","Answer4":"ZZ Top","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor appeared in Paul Simon's music video 'You Can Call Me Al'?","CorrectAnswer":"Chevy Chase","Answer2":"Danny DeVito","Answer3":"George Clooney","Answer4":"Al Pacino","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"To a musician, what is a liquorice stick?","CorrectAnswer":"Clarinet","Answer2":"Drumstick","Answer3":"Conductor's Baton","Answer4":"Tuning Fork","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actress appeared in the Robbie Williams music video Feel?","CorrectAnswer":"Daryl Hannah","Answer2":"Michelle Pfeiffer","Answer3":"Diana Dors","Answer4":"Angelina Jolie","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Mark and David Knopfler were brothers in which band?","CorrectAnswer":"Dire Straits","Answer2":"Sparks","Answer3":"Small Faces","Answer4":"Kinks","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor appeared in the Kate Bush music video Cloudbursting?","CorrectAnswer":"Donald Sutherland","Answer2":"Danny DeVito","Answer3":"Jeremy Irons","Answer4":"Paul Newman","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor appeared in the Cranberries music video Ridiculous Thought?","CorrectAnswer":"Elijah Wood","Answer2":"Bruce Willis","Answer3":"Donald Sutherland","Answer4":"George Clooney","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the title of a U2 song?","CorrectAnswer":"Elvis and America","Answer2":"Nixon and America","Answer3":"Bush and America","Answer4":"Sinatra and America","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first person to sell one million records?","CorrectAnswer":"Enrico Caruso","Answer2":"Elvis","Answer3":"Frank Sinatra","Answer4":"Bing Crosby","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which way was a hit for Rod Stewart?","CorrectAnswer":"Gasoline Alley","Answer2":"Baker Street","Answer3":"Thunder Road","Answer4":"Penny Lane","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which band had a hit with 'Radar Love' in 1973?","CorrectAnswer":"Golden Earring","Answer2":"Silver Buckles","Answer3":"Shocking Blue","Answer4":"Rainbow","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the official march of the Royal Navy? ","CorrectAnswer":"Hearts of Oak","Answer2":"Rule Britannia","Answer3":"Blow Boys Blow","Answer4":"Spanish Ladiies ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first person to have their picture on the cover of the Rolling Stone magazine?","CorrectAnswer":"John Lennon","Answer2":"Dr Hook","Answer3":"Mick Jagger","Answer4":"Dolly Parton","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which city is not mentioned in the song 'Route 66'?","CorrectAnswer":"Kansas City","Answer2":"St. Louis","Answer3":"Flagstaff","Answer4":"Winona","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor covered the Beatles song 'Blackbird'?","CorrectAnswer":"Kevin Spacey","Answer2":"Peter Sellers","Answer3":"William Shatner","Answer4":"Bruce Willis","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Ray and Dave Davies were brothers in which band?","CorrectAnswer":"Kinks","Answer2":"Spencer Davis Group","Answer3":"Beach Boys","Answer4":"ZZ Top","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which city was the famous 'Roxy' music club?","CorrectAnswer":"L.A.","Answer2":"New York","Answer3":"Liverpool","Answer4":"London","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which city was the famous 'Whisky A Go Go' music club?","CorrectAnswer":"L.A.","Answer2":"New York","Answer3":"New Orleans","Answer4":"Hamburg","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which song begins with the words ","CorrectAnswer":"Last Train to London","Answer2":"Last Train to Clarksville","Answer3":"Morning Train (9 to 5)","Answer4":"Love Train","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which city was the famous 'Crawdaddy' music club?","CorrectAnswer":"London","Answer2":"Glasgow","Answer3":"Liverpool","Answer4":"Newcastle","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who had a hit with the Stones song 'As Tears Go By'?","CorrectAnswer":"Marianne Faithfull","Answer2":"Lulu","Answer3":"Mary Hopkin","Answer4":"Dusty Springfield","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who had a hit with 'Those were the Days'?","CorrectAnswer":"Mary Hopkin","Answer2":"Cilla Black","Answer3":"Dusty Springfield","Answer4":"Petula Clark","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was a hit for Gilbert O'Sullivan?","CorrectAnswer":"Matrimony","Answer2":"Love and Marriage","Answer3":"White Wedding","Answer4":"Wedding Bell Blues","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was a hit song for Gilbert O'Sullivan?","CorrectAnswer":"Matrimony","Answer2":"D.I.V.O.R.C.E.","Answer3":"Seperation","Answer4":"I do I do I do","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who sings along with Carly Simon in the song 'You're so vain'?","CorrectAnswer":"Mick Jagger","Answer2":"George Harrison","Answer3":"Peter  Gabriel","Answer4":"James Taylor  ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What time was a hit for Meatloaf?","CorrectAnswer":"Midnight at the lost and found","Answer2":"After Midnight","Answer3":"Midnite Dynamos","Answer4":"Midnight at the Oasis","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What time was a hit for Matchbox?","CorrectAnswer":"Midnite Dynamos","Answer2":"Down in the tube station at Midnight","Answer3":"Midnight at the lost and found","Answer4":"Midnight Lady","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which city is the world famous La Scala opera house?","CorrectAnswer":"Milan","Answer2":"Naples","Answer3":"New York","Answer4":"Madrid","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What man was a hit for the Eurythmics?","CorrectAnswer":"Missionary","Answer2":"Candy","Answer3":"Star","Answer4":"Soul","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which sound is a R.E.M. album?","CorrectAnswer":"Murmur","Answer2":"Grumble","Answer3":"Whisper","Answer4":"Mumble","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which metal band had a hit with 'This Flight Tonight'?","CorrectAnswer":"Nazareth","Answer2":"Deep Purple","Answer3":"Judas Priest","Answer4":"Led Zeppelin","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which city is not mentioned in the song 'Route 66'?","CorrectAnswer":"Odell","Answer2":"Barstow","Answer3":"Joplin","Answer4":"Kingman","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What time is it in the Genesis song I Know What I Like (In Your Wardrobe)?","CorrectAnswer":"One o'clock","Answer2":"Two o'clock","Answer3":"six o'clock","Answer4":"five o'clock","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which song begins with the words ","CorrectAnswer":"Orange Blossom Special","Answer2":"Lily the Pink","Answer3":"Desert Rose","Answer4":"Tip toe thru the Tulips","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatle is walking barefoot on the Abbey Road album?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul","Answer2":"Ringo","Answer3":"John","Answer4":"George","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which of the following is no longer a member of the band Oasis?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul McGuigan","Answer2":"Chris Sharrock","Answer3":"Andy Bell","Answer4":"Colin Archer","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatle was born in India?","CorrectAnswer":"Pete Best","Answer2":"George Harrison","Answer3":"John Lennon","Answer4":"Ringo Starr   ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor covered the Beatles song 'She Loves You'?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Sellers","Answer2":"Bruce Willis","Answer3":"Clint Eastwood","Answer4":"Telly Savalas","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Doris Day had a sleepy hit with which song?","CorrectAnswer":"Pillow Talk","Answer2":"Golden Slumbers","Answer3":"The Beds To Big Without You","Answer4":"Tears On My pillow","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Please, Please Me","Answer2":"Yellow Submarine","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Please, Please Me","Answer2":"Yellow Submarine","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Please, Please Me","Answer2":"Yellow Submarine","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"The song 'An Englishman in New York' was about which man?","CorrectAnswer":"Quentin Crisp","Answer2":"Sting","Answer3":"John Lennon","Answer4":"Gordon Sumner","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which girl was not a Rolling Stones song?","CorrectAnswer":"Ramblin Rose","Answer2":"Angie","Answer3":"Lady Jane","Answer4":"Miss Amanda Jones","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who had a summer hit in 2000 with 'Supergirl'?","CorrectAnswer":"Reamonn","Answer2":"Lou Bega","Answer3":"Shaggy","Answer4":"Gompie","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who sang the Bond theme song 'All Time High'?","CorrectAnswer":"Rita Coolidge","Answer2":"Sheena Easton","Answer3":"Lulu","Answer4":"Sheryl Crow","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who gave a live concert to a record 3.5 million fans in Rio de Janeiro?","CorrectAnswer":"Rod Stewart","Answer2":"Robbie Williams","Answer3":"Frank Sinatra","Answer4":"James Blunt","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Before joining the Beatles Ringo Starr was a member of which band?","CorrectAnswer":"Rory Storm and the Hurricanes","Answer2":"The Dave Clark 5","Answer3":"The Merseybeats","Answer4":"The Shadows","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Where did The Flowerpot Men want to go in 1967?","CorrectAnswer":"San Francisco","Answer2":"New York","Answer3":"Woodstock","Answer4":"Memphis","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which city is not mentioned in the song 'Route 66'?","CorrectAnswer":"Santa Fe","Answer2":"St. Louis","Answer3":"Winona","Answer4":"Barstow","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which singer once took a bite out of a Beach Boys record during a press conference?","CorrectAnswer":"Shane MacGowan","Answer2":"Robbie Williams","Answer3":"Engelbert Humperdinck","Answer4":"James Blunt","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who sang duett with Peter Sellers in 'Goodness Gracious Me'?","CorrectAnswer":"Sophia Loren","Answer2":"Rachel Welch","Answer3":"Gina Lollabrigida","Answer4":"Mae west","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Russell and Ron Mael were brothers in which band?","CorrectAnswer":"Sparks","Answer2":"ZZ Top","Answer3":"Doobie Brothers","Answer4":"CCR ","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Steve and Muff Winwood were brothers in which band?","CorrectAnswer":"Spencer Davis Group","Answer2":"ZZ Top","Answer3":"Small Faces","Answer4":"Kinks","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which city is not mentioned in the song 'Route 66'?","CorrectAnswer":"Springfield","Answer2":"Barstow","Answer3":"Oklahoma City","Answer4":"Kingman","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was a Prefab Sprout album?","CorrectAnswer":"Steve McQueen","Answer2":"Paul Newman","Answer3":"John Wayne","Answer4":"Hugh Grant","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which band was not from Liverpool?","CorrectAnswer":"Stone the crows","Answer2":"Searchers","Answer3":"A Flock of Seagulls","Answer4":"OMD","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the title of the first British song to reach number one in the USA?","CorrectAnswer":"Stranger on the shore","Answer2":"I want to hold your hand","Answer3":"Mrs. Brown, You've got a lovely daughter","Answer4":"House of the rising sun","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which fruit is a Led Zeppelin song?","CorrectAnswer":"Tangerine","Answer2":"Peach","Answer3":"Strawberry","Answer4":"Blackberry","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor covered the Beatles song 'Something'?","CorrectAnswer":"Telly Savalas","Answer2":"Peter Sellers","Answer3":"Robin Williams","Answer4":"Kevin Spacey","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"ZZ Top once toured with an elaborate stage set that was shaped like which US state?","CorrectAnswer":"Texas","Answer2":"California","Answer3":"New York","Answer4":"Iowa","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the name of Sting's first solo album?","CorrectAnswer":"The dream of the blue turtles","Answer2":"The dream of the white doves","Answer3":"The dream of the red dolphins","Answer4":"The dream of the painted dragons","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first band to appear on Top Of The Pops?","CorrectAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","Answer2":"The Animals","Answer3":"The Zombies","Answer4":"The Beatles","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who were the first band to play at the Cavern Club?","CorrectAnswer":"The Merseysippi","Answer2":"Beatles","Answer3":"Merseybeats","Answer4":"Swinging Blue Jeans","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which city is not mentioned in the song 'Route 66'?","CorrectAnswer":"Tucumcari","Answer2":"LA","Answer3":"Joplin","Answer4":"Amarillo","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who had a 1972 hit with 'Jackie Wilson Said'?","CorrectAnswer":"Van Morrison","Answer2":"The Animals","Answer3":"David Bowie","Answer4":"Don McLean","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which girl was not a Beatles song?","CorrectAnswer":"Victoria","Answer2":"Michelle","Answer3":"Julia","Answer4":"Anna","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What number was not a Boy Band?","CorrectAnswer":"West 17","Answer2":"All-4-One","Answer3":"112","Answer4":"O Town","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which pop duo were the first western band to play in The Peoples Republic of China?","CorrectAnswer":"Wham","Answer2":"Simon and Garfunkel","Answer3":"Chaz and Dave","Answer4":"Right Said Fred","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which animal was a hit for Jefferson Airplane?","CorrectAnswer":"White Rabbit","Answer2":"White Horses ","Answer3":"White Dove","Answer4":"Ride a white Swan","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is Smokey Robinson's real name?","CorrectAnswer":"William Robinson","Answer2":"Joe Robinson","Answer3":"Smokey Robinson","Answer4":"Samuel Robinson","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which band was fronted by a married couple?","CorrectAnswer":"Wings","Answer2":"America","Answer3":"ELP","Answer4":"Cream","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Yellow Submarine","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Yellow Submarine","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Beatles album featured the song ","CorrectAnswer":"Yellow Submarine","Answer2":"Please, Please Me","Answer3":"A Hard Day's Night ","Answer4":"Abbey Road","Category":"Music","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"A scrum half in rugby union would traditionally wear which number on his back?","CorrectAnswer":"9","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"15","Answer4":"11","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many players make a rugby union team?","CorrectAnswer":"15","Answer2":"11","Answer3":"10","Answer4":"14","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which famous football stadium is in Barcelona?","CorrectAnswer":"Nou Camp","Answer2":"Bernabeu","Answer3":"Aztec","Answer4":"Maracana","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In Show jumping, how many points are incurred for knocking a fence down? ","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"3","Answer3":"5","Answer4":"2","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many yards are there between each set of stumps in cricket?","CorrectAnswer":"22","Answer2":"25","Answer3":"30","Answer4":"32","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In what year was the first official international between Scotland and England in football?","CorrectAnswer":"1872","Answer2":"1892","Answer3":"1912","Answer4":"1922","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which team won the UEFA Champions League in the season 2006–07?","CorrectAnswer":"AC Milan","Answer2":"Liverpool","Answer3":"Chelsea","Answer4":"Barcelona","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which football club were once known as Dial Square FC?","CorrectAnswer":"Arsenal","Answer2":"Chelsea","Answer3":"Southampton","Answer4":"Sunderland","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which team won the UEFA Champions League in the season 2005–06?","CorrectAnswer":"Barcelona","Answer2":"Arsenal","Answer3":"Liverpool","Answer4":"AC Milan","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"England defeated which country 3-2 in extra time at the 1990 football world cup in Italy? ","CorrectAnswer":"Cameroon  ","Answer2":"Holland","Answer3":"Belguim","Answer4":"Germany","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country did boxer Lennox Lewis represent at the Olympics?","CorrectAnswer":"Canada","Answer2":"Great Britain","Answer3":"USA","Answer4":"Russia","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which sport takes place at The circus tavern?","CorrectAnswer":"Darts","Answer2":"Snooker","Answer3":"Show Jumping","Answer4":"Polo","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which country won the Six Nations Championship in 2003?","CorrectAnswer":"England","Answer2":"Wales","Answer3":"France","Answer4":"Ireland","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which German football club has won the most league titles?","CorrectAnswer":"FC Bayern Munich","Answer2":"HSV Hamburg","Answer3":"I FC Koln","Answer4":"Schalke 04","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What sport was banned in Scotland in 1457?","CorrectAnswer":"Golf","Answer2":"Football","Answer3":"Polo","Answer4":"Jousting","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which sport is played at The oxfordshire?","CorrectAnswer":"Golf","Answer2":"Tennis","Answer3":"Rugby","Answer4":"Cricket","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"With which sport do you associate the Scottish town of Carnoustie?","CorrectAnswer":"Golf","Answer2":"Highland Games","Answer3":"Rugby","Answer4":"Bowls","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Olga Korbett was a superstar in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"gymnastics","Answer2":"tennis","Answer3":"figure skating","Answer4":"weightlifting ","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who inflicted Uruguay’s first ever defeat in the world cup finals in 1954 at the semi final stage losing 4-2?","CorrectAnswer":"Hungary","Answer2":"Brazil","Answer3":"England","Answer4":"Argentina","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which country was snooker invented?","CorrectAnswer":"India","Answer2":"South Africa","Answer3":"Canada","Answer4":"Australia","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which team won the UEFA Champions League in the season 2004–05?","CorrectAnswer":"Liverpool","Answer2":"AC Milan","Answer3":"Barcelona","Answer4":"Porto","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who won six consecutive Wimbledon titles in the 1980's ?","CorrectAnswer":"Martina Navratilova","Answer2":"Bjorn Borg","Answer3":"Jimmy Connors","Answer4":"Chris Evert","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which European Footballer of the Year was nicknamed 'The Divine Pony Tail' ?","CorrectAnswer":"Roberto Baggio","Answer2":"Bobby Charlton","Answer3":"Ronaldino","Answer4":"Zidane","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who won the Golden Boot at the 2002 football world cup?","CorrectAnswer":"Ronaldo","Answer2":"Larson","Answer3":"Vieri","Answer4":"Ballack","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which sport is the subject of the 1963 film this sporting life?","CorrectAnswer":"Rugby","Answer2":"Football","Answer3":"Cricket","Answer4":"Polo","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which sport is the Webb Ellis Cup awarded to the winners of the World Cup?","CorrectAnswer":"Rugby Union","Answer2":"Rugby League","Answer3":"Cricket","Answer4":"Football","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"A Dolpholina is an elegant movement in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"synchronised swimming","Answer2":"elephant polo","Answer3":"water polo","Answer4":"diving","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"John Newcombe was a superstar in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"tennis","Answer2":"golf","Answer3":"snooker","Answer4":"cricket  ","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Rene Lacoste was a superstar in which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"tennis","Answer2":"rugby","Answer3":"football","Answer4":"boxing","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which sport is played at Devonshire park?","CorrectAnswer":"Tennis","Answer2":"Football","Answer3":"Rugby","Answer4":"Cricket","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who were the only team to lose a World Cup Final in the 1980s?","CorrectAnswer":"West Germany","Answer2":"France","Answer3":"Italy","Answer4":"Argentina","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Damon Hill was Formula 1 champion in 1996 in which car?","CorrectAnswer":"Williams-Renault","Answer2":"Benetton Ford","Answer3":"Ferrari","Answer4":"Lotus Ford","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the mascot at the 1966 football  world cup?","CorrectAnswer":"Willie","Answer2":"Wally","Answer3":"Wanda","Answer4":"Winnie","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Scottish football club is nicknamed 'The Blue Brazil'?","CorrectAnswer":"Cowdenbeath","Answer2":"Clyde","Answer3":"Dundee United","Answer4":"Rangers","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which sport is also called 'The Roaring Game'?","CorrectAnswer":"Curling","Answer2":"Darts","Answer3":"Rugby","Answer4":"Elephant Polo","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"France and which other nation were a losing semi-finalist at the 1960 European Football Championship?","CorrectAnswer":"Czechoslovakia","Answer2":"Yugoslavia","Answer3":"USSR","Answer4":"Germany","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which 'pearl' was the first man to win the European Golden Boot award in 1967?","CorrectAnswer":"Eusebio","Answer2":"Dennis Law","Answer3":"George Best","Answer4":"Charlie George","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who is the only Nobel Prize winner to have played first class cricket?","CorrectAnswer":"Samuel Beckett","Answer2":"Albert Einstein","Answer3":"Jean Paul Sartre","Answer4":"Mother Theresa","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which boxer twice defeated Nigel Benn in 1996?","CorrectAnswer":"Steve Collins","Answer2":"Thulani Malinga","Answer3":"Roy Jones ","Answer4":"Gerald McClellan ","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In the 2000 Sydney Olympics Paul Palmer represented Great Britain at which sport?","CorrectAnswer":"Swimming","Answer2":"Rowing","Answer3":"Archery","Answer4":"Athletics","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was formerly known as the 'Fairs Cities Cup'?","CorrectAnswer":"UEFA Cup","Answer2":"Davis Cup","Answer3":"Ryder Cup","Answer4":"Cup Winners Cup","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"England played its first cricket international against which country in 1859?","CorrectAnswer":"USA","Answer2":"India","Answer3":"Germany","Answer4":"Jamaica","Category":"Sport","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How Many Oscars Did The Film Shakespeare In Love Win?","CorrectAnswer":"7","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"1","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Cruella de Vil was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"101 Dalmatians","Answer2":"Aristocats","Answer3":"Monsters, Inc","Answer4":"Shrek","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which actor played John McClane in the ","CorrectAnswer":"Bruce Willis","Answer2":"Tom Cruise","Answer3":"Keanu Reeves","Answer4":"Harrison Ford","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"With which series of films do you associate with the phrase ","CorrectAnswer":"Carry On","Answer2":"Alien","Answer3":"Back to the Future","Answer4":"Waynes World","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"On television what was Flipper?","CorrectAnswer":"Dolphin","Answer2":"Whale","Answer3":"Seal","Answer4":"Walrus","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who had a dog named K9?","CorrectAnswer":"Dr. Who","Answer2":"Worzel Gummedge","Answer3":"Howling Mad Murdoch","Answer4":"Luke Skywalker","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was John Merrick's nickname?","CorrectAnswer":"Elephant Man","Answer2":"Superman","Answer3":"Iron Man","Answer4":"Danger Man","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is Agent Mulder's first name in TV's the X-Files?","CorrectAnswer":"Fox","Answer2":"Wolf","Answer3":"Bunny","Answer4":"Weasel","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What is the name of the woodworker in Pinocchio?","CorrectAnswer":"Geppetto","Answer2":"Luigi","Answer3":"Toni","Answer4":"Victorio","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which character did Bruce Willis play in the Die Hard series of movies?","CorrectAnswer":"John McClane","Answer2":"Bruce McClane","Answer3":"Paul McClane","Answer4":"Bud McClane","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who was dubbed the Elephant Man?","CorrectAnswer":"John Merrick","Answer2":"John McCririck ","Answer3":"John McEnroe","Answer4":"John Martin","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the name of Dr Who's dog?","CorrectAnswer":"K9","Answer2":"Wolf","Answer3":"Woof","Answer4":"Robodog","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was Skippy?","CorrectAnswer":"Kangaroo","Answer2":"Dolphin","Answer3":"Horse","Answer4":"Koala","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who fell head over heels in love with Anne Darrow?","CorrectAnswer":"King Kong","Answer2":"Sherlock Holmes","Answer3":"Spiderman","Answer4":"The Hulk","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who starred as the Six Million Dollar Man?","CorrectAnswer":"Lee Majors","Answer2":"Lee Minors","Answer3":"Major Lee","Answer4":"Minor Lee","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In which film would you find a cat called Orion?","CorrectAnswer":"Men In Black","Answer2":"Goldfinger","Answer3":"Toy Story","Answer4":"Shrek","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"In friends what is Ross’ profession?","CorrectAnswer":"Palaeontologist","Answer2":"Actor","Answer3":"Chef","Answer4":"Script Writer","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Nana is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Pan","Answer2":"101 Dalmatians","Answer3":"The Aristocats","Answer4":"Winnie the Pooh","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Jiminy Cricket is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Pinocchio","Answer2":"Dumbo","Answer3":"Monsters, Inc","Answer4":"A Bugs Life","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"The Blue Fairy is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Pinocchio","Answer2":"Cinderella","Answer3":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"What was the name of the blonde witch in Bewitched?","CorrectAnswer":"Samantha","Answer2":"Jeanie","Answer3":"Tabatha","Answer4":"Edna","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Which mans music kills the Martians in the film Mars Attacks?","CorrectAnswer":"Slim Whitman","Answer2":"Tom Jones","Answer3":"Barry Manilow","Answer4":"James Blunt ","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Old Fred was the captain of which type of vessel?","CorrectAnswer":"Submarine","Answer2":"Oil Tanker","Answer3":"Cruise Ship","Answer4":"Warship","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Who lives at Home Hill?","CorrectAnswer":"The Teletubbies","Answer2":"Bob the Builder","Answer3":"Thomas the Tank engine","Answer4":"Bagpuss","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Kanga is a character in which Disney film?","CorrectAnswer":"Winnie the Pooh","Answer2":"Tarzan","Answer3":"The Jungle Book","Answer4":"Monsters, Inc","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"Roo is a character in which Disney film?","CorrectAnswer":"Winnie the Pooh","Answer2":"Finding Nemo","Answer3":"The Incredibles","Answer4":"The Lion King","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":1},
{"Question":"How many Rambo films have been made?","CorrectAnswer":"4","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"3","Answer4":"6","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many 'Planet of the Apes' films were there?","CorrectAnswer":"5","Answer2":"6","Answer3":"4","Answer4":"7","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many Oscars did the film Ben Hur recieve?","CorrectAnswer":"11","Answer2":"7","Answer3":"5","Answer4":"15","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How many Dalmatians were there in the film 101 Dalmatians?","CorrectAnswer":"103","Answer2":"102","Answer3":"101","Answer4":"104","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the sequel to the sci-fi classic 2001 A Space Odyssey?","CorrectAnswer":"2010","Answer2":"2002","Answer3":"2050","Answer4":"3001","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Dipstick was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"101 Dalmatians","Answer2":"Monsters, Inc","Answer3":"Shrek","Answer4":"Toy Story","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Pongo is a dog in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"101 Dalmatians","Answer2":"Peter Pan","Answer3":"Dam Busters","Answer4":"The Wizard Of Oz","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Sergeant Tibbs is a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"101 Dalmatians","Answer2":"Aristocats","Answer3":"Lethal Weapon","Answer4":"Men In Black","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Stanley Kubrick film is based on a short story by Arthur C Clarke?","CorrectAnswer":"2001 A Space Odyssey","Answer2":"The Shining","Answer3":"Spartacus","Answer4":"Eyes Wide Shut","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Dr Heywood Floyd is a character in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"2001   ","Answer2":"Jurasic Park","Answer3":"MASH","Answer4":"Back to the future","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Heimlich was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"A Bugs Life","Answer2":"Aristocats","Answer3":"Monsters, Inc","Answer4":"Shrek","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Princess Atta was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"A Bugs Life","Answer2":"Aladdin","Answer3":"Sleeping Beauty","Answer4":"Aristocats","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Stanley Kubrick film is based on a novel by Anthony Burgess?","CorrectAnswer":"A Clockwork Orange","Answer2":"The Shining","Answer3":"Lolita","Answer4":"2001 A Space Odyssey","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Princess Jasmine was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Aladdin","Answer2":"Sleeping Beauty","Answer3":"Aristocats","Answer4":"Monsters, Inc","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Tweedledee was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Alice in Wonderland","Answer2":"Cars","Answer3":"A Bugs Life","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which sci-fi film would you find an android named ASH?","CorrectAnswer":"Alien","Answer2":"2010","Answer3":"Logans Run","Answer4":"Santa Claus Conquers The Martians","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which film does Dustin Hoffman play the frightened character Carl Bernstein?","CorrectAnswer":"All The Presidents Men","Answer2":"Papillon","Answer3":"Tootsie","Answer4":"Marathon Man","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What kills the aliens in the film Evolution?","CorrectAnswer":"anti-dandruff shampoo","Answer2":"Underarm deodorant","Answer3":"toothpaste","Answer4":"Mouthwash","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Puss in Boots in 'Shrek 2'?","CorrectAnswer":"Antonio Banderas","Answer2":"Anthony Quinn","Answer3":"George Clooney","Answer4":"Bruce Willis","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Duchess is a cat in which film ?","CorrectAnswer":"Aristocats","Answer2":"Lethal Weapon","Answer3":"101 Dalmatians","Answer4":"Men In Black","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Frou Frou was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Aristocats","Answer2":"101 Dalmations","Answer3":"Shrek","Answer4":"Dumbo","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Roquefort was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Aristocats","Answer2":"Shrek","Answer3":"Pinocchio","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Thomas O'Malley is a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Aristocats","Answer2":"Lethal Weapon","Answer3":"Die Hard","Answer4":"Dumbo","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following Dallas characters returned from the dead?","CorrectAnswer":"B. Ewing","Answer2":"J. R. Ewing","Answer3":"F. Ewing","Answer4":"C. Ewing","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Einstein is a dog in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Back To The Future","Answer2":"Men In Black","Answer3":"The Wizard Of Oz","Answer4":"Chitty Chitty Bang Bang","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Stanley Kubrick film is based on a novel by William Makepeace Thackeray?","CorrectAnswer":"Barry Lyndon","Answer2":"2001 A Space Odyssey","Answer3":"A Clockwork Orange","Answer4":"Lolita","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the title of the last 'Planet of the Apes' film?","CorrectAnswer":"Battle for the Planet of the Apes","Answer2":"Beneath the Planet of the Apes","Answer3":"Escape from the Planet of the Apes","Answer4":"Conquest of the Planet of the Apes","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Belle was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Beauty and the Beast","Answer2":"Aristocats","Answer3":"101 Dalmatians","Answer4":"Dumbo","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who directed the film 'Breakfast at Tiffanys'?","CorrectAnswer":"Blake Edwards","Answer2":"Alfred Hitchcock","Answer3":"Woody Allen","Answer4":"John Huston","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of Rhett Butler's daughter in Gone With The Wind?","CorrectAnswer":"Bonnie","Answer2":"Lucy","Answer3":"Theresa","Answer4":"Victoria","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Cheers is set in a bar called the bull and finch in which us city?","CorrectAnswer":"Boston","Answer2":"Washington DC","Answer3":"New York","Answer4":"Portland","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Putney is a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Breakfast At Tiffany's","Answer2":"Men In Black","Answer3":"The Aristocats","Answer4":"Pet Semetary","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a guest appearance as Joey's stalker in the TV series 'Friends'?","CorrectAnswer":"Brooke Shields","Answer2":"Isabella Rossellini","Answer3":"Reese Witherspoon","Answer4":"Julia Roberts","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The film The Bridge On The River Kwai takes place in which country?","CorrectAnswer":"Burma","Answer2":"China","Answer3":"Vietnam","Answer4":"Cambodia","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which worry prone film character was fluent in 6,000,000 forms of communication?","CorrectAnswer":"C3PO","Answer2":"Mavin the paranoid android","Answer3":"T-800","Answer4":"Gort","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Princess Fiona in 'Shrek'?","CorrectAnswer":"Cameron Diaz","Answer2":"Julie Andrews","Answer3":"Jodie Foster","Answer4":"Whoopee Goldberg","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following was not a character in Disney's Pirates of the Caribbean?","CorrectAnswer":"Captain Bluebeard","Answer2":"Bootstrap Bill Turner","Answer3":"Davy Jones","Answer4":"Captain Teague","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Lightning McQueen was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Cars","Answer2":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","Answer3":"The Incredibles","Answer4":"Monsters, Inc","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Sally Carrera was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Cars","Answer2":"Aristocats","Answer3":"Peter Pan","Answer4":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Le Chiffre was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"Casino Royale","Answer2":"Live and Let Die","Answer3":"Moonraker","Answer4":"Licence to Kill","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of Inspector Clouseau's man servant?","CorrectAnswer":"Cato","Answer2":"Giles","Answer3":"Wong","Answer4":"Hop Sing","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Edison is a dog in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Chitty Chitty Bang Bang","Answer2":"Back To The Future","Answer3":"Men In Black","Answer4":"Transformers","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Drizella was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Cinderalla","Answer2":"101 Dalmatians","Answer3":"Pinocchio","Answer4":"Aladdin","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who directed the film 'Unforgiven'?","CorrectAnswer":"Clint Eastwood","Answer2":"Johnathan Demme","Answer3":"Steven Spielberg","Answer4":"Martin Scorsese","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Sergeant Jimmy Beck was a character in which TV series?","CorrectAnswer":"Cracker","Answer2":"The Professionals","Answer3":"Shoestring","Answer4":"The Sweeney","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Corben did Bruce Willis play in The Fifth Element?","CorrectAnswer":"Dallas","Answer2":"Rio","Answer3":"Calcutta","Answer4":"Rome","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Bond actor tries to kill Her Majesty in the film Elizabeth?","CorrectAnswer":"Daniel Craig","Answer2":"Pearce Brosnan","Answer3":"Sean Connery","Answer4":"Roger Moore","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which film is Hans Gruber a bad guy?","CorrectAnswer":"Die Hard","Answer2":"Star Wars","Answer3":"Rocky Horror Picture Show","Answer4":"The Hulk","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which film does Peter Sellers play three different roles?","CorrectAnswer":"Dr Strangelove","Answer2":"The Pink Panther","Answer3":"Being There","Answer4":"Casino Royale","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Timothy Q was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Dumbo","Answer2":"Alice in Wonderland","Answer3":"101 Dalmatians","Answer4":"Pinocchio","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Doug Ross is a Dr. in which TV series?","CorrectAnswer":"E.R.","Answer2":"Greys Anatomy","Answer3":"Lost","Answer4":"Lost in Space","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of the donkey in 'Shrek'?","CorrectAnswer":"Eddie Murphy","Answer2":"Morgan Freeman","Answer3":"Rowan Atkinson","Answer4":"Woody Allen","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The film trainspotting is set in which city?","CorrectAnswer":"Edinburgh","Answer2":"Glasgow","Answer3":"Aberdeen","Answer4":"Dundee","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Bruce was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Finding Nemo","Answer2":"The Little Mermaid","Answer3":"Shrek","Answer4":"Cars","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Dory was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Finding Nemo","Answer2":"The Little Mermaid","Answer3":"Toy Story","Answer4":"Shrek","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Marlin was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Finding Nemo","Answer2":"The Jungle Book","Answer3":"The Little Mermaid","Answer4":"A Bugs Life","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which film does not star the academy award winning actress Jessica Lange?","CorrectAnswer":"Fried Green Tomatoes","Answer2":"King Kong","Answer3":"Tootsie","Answer4":"Rob Roy","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which cartoonist created Porky Pig?","CorrectAnswer":"Fritz  Frelang","Answer2":"Max Fleischer","Answer3":"Walter Lanz","Answer4":"Gary Larson","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which cartoonist created Sylvester and Tweety Bird?","CorrectAnswer":"Fritz Frelang","Answer2":"Tex Avery","Answer3":"Chuck Jones","Answer4":"Walt Disney?","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Rosa Klebb is an evil woman in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"From Russia with love","Answer2":"Love Story","Answer3":"Love Actually","Answer4":"To Sir with love","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which role was not played by Peter Sellers in the film 'Dr. Strangelove'?","CorrectAnswer":"Gen. Jack D Ripper","Answer2":"Capt Mandrake","Answer3":"Dr Strangelove","Answer4":"President Merkin Muffley","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a guest appearance as Dr Mitchell in the TV series 'Friends'?","CorrectAnswer":"George Clooney","Answer2":"Elliot Gould","Answer3":" Billy Crystal   ","Answer4":"Jay Leno","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of Drew Barrymore's character in E.T.?","CorrectAnswer":"Gertie","Answer2":"Charlie","Answer3":"Bertie","Answer4":"Dottie","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the first Part Two film to win the Oscar?","CorrectAnswer":"Godfather   II","Answer2":"Rocky II","Answer3":"Die Hard II","Answer4":"Rambo II","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which James Bond film featured Honor Blackman?","CorrectAnswer":"Goldfinger","Answer2":"A View to a Kill","Answer3":"On Her Majesty's Secret Service","Answer4":"You Only Live Twice","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following was not a character in Disney's Pocahontas?","CorrectAnswer":"Grandfather Willow","Answer2":"Wiggins","Answer3":"Percy","Answer4":"John Smith","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In Star Trek, what colour is Spock's blood?","CorrectAnswer":"Green","Answer2":"Red","Answer3":"Black","Answer4":"Blue","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What colour is Spock's blood?","CorrectAnswer":"Green","Answer2":"Red","Answer3":"Black","Answer4":"Blue","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which actor played the evil Nazi doctor Mengele in 'The Boys From Brazil'?","CorrectAnswer":"Gregory Peck","Answer2":"Laurence Olivier","Answer3":"Peter Sellers","Answer4":"Alec Guinness","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the film industry name for a helper?","CorrectAnswer":"Grip","Answer2":"Gaffer","Answer3":"Best Boy","Answer4":"Wrangler","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the name of the computer in 2001 A Space Odyssey?","CorrectAnswer":"HAL 9000","Answer2":"PAL 9000","Answer3":"GAL 9000","Answer4":"CAL 9000","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was Olive Oyl's boyfriend before Popeye?","CorrectAnswer":"Ham Gravy","Answer2":"Hammond Eggs","Answer3":"Bacon Butty","Answer4":"Fatty Bacon","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the first black actress to win an Oscar?","CorrectAnswer":"Hattie McDaniel ","Answer2":"Dorothy Dandridge","Answer3":"Ethel Waters","Answer4":"Angela Bassett","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which film is Kurgan a bad guy?","CorrectAnswer":"Highlander","Answer2":"Die Hard","Answer3":"Star Wars","Answer4":"Rocky Horror Picture Show","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Where do the Teletubbies live?","CorrectAnswer":"Home Hill","Answer2":"Dome Hill","Answer3":"Comb Hill","Answer4":"Phone Hill","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Diego was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Ice Age","Answer2":"Cars","Answer3":"Finding Nemo","Answer4":"The Jungle Book","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Scrat is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Ice Age","Answer2":"Finding Nemo","Answer3":"The Incredibles","Answer4":"The Jungle Book","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the country of origin of film star, Richard Harris?","CorrectAnswer":"Ireland","Answer2":"Wales","Answer3":"England","Answer4":"Australia","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What does Hannibal Lector drink with liver?","CorrectAnswer":"Italian Chianti ","Answer2":"German lager","Answer3":"French mineral water","Answer4":"Japanese Sake","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of the Fairy Godmother in 'Shrek 2'?","CorrectAnswer":"Jennifer Saunders","Answer2":"Mike Myers","Answer3":"Jodie Foster","Answer4":"Julie Andrews","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Scar in 'The Lion King'?","CorrectAnswer":"Jeremy Irons","Answer2":"Bruce Willis","Answer3":"Clint Eastwood","Answer4":"Tom Hanks","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of the King in 'Shrek 2'?","CorrectAnswer":"John Cleese","Answer2":"Clint Eastwood","Answer3":"Morgan Freeman","Answer4":"Bruce Willis","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who directed the film 'The Silence of the Lambs'?","CorrectAnswer":"Johnathan Demme","Answer2":"David Lynch","Answer3":"Tim Burton","Answer4":"James Cameron","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of the Queen in 'Shrek 2'?","CorrectAnswer":"Julie Andrews","Answer2":"Elizebeth Taylor","Answer3":"Farah Fawcett","Answer4":"Jennifer Saunders","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the evil organisation in 'Get Smart'?","CorrectAnswer":"KAOS","Answer2":"THRUSH","Answer3":"SPECTRE","Answer4":"SMERSH","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who played Frankenstein in the 1994 film of the same name?","CorrectAnswer":"Kenneth Branagh","Answer2":"Robert De Niro","Answer3":"Dustin Hoffman","Answer4":"Gene Wilder","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which film would you find the ship named Venture? ","CorrectAnswer":"King Kong","Answer2":"Master and Commander","Answer3":"Jaws","Answer4":"Mutiny on the Bounty","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What nationality was Oddjob in Goldfinger?","CorrectAnswer":"Korean","Answer2":"Chinese","Answer3":"Japanese","Answer4":"Burmese","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which actor played the evil Nazi doctor in 'Marathon Man'?","CorrectAnswer":"Laurence Olivier","Answer2":"Peter Sellers","Answer3":"Gregory Peck","Answer4":"Alec Guinness","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What Were Margo And Jerrys Surname In The Good Life On Tv?","CorrectAnswer":"Leadbetter","Answer2":"Good","Answer3":"Smith","Answer4":"Merryweather","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Burbank is a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Lethal Weapon","Answer2":"Men In Black","Answer3":"Pinochio","Answer4":"Pet Semetary","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What Sort Of Animal Was The Cartoon Character Snagglepuss?","CorrectAnswer":"Lion","Answer2":"Cat","Answer3":"Leopard","Answer4":"Tiger","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which film did Dustin Hoffman play the character Jack Crabb?","CorrectAnswer":"Little Big Man","Answer2":"The Graduate","Answer3":"Marathon Man","Answer4":"Rain Man","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mr Big was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"Live and Let Die","Answer2":"Tomorrow Never Dies","Answer3":"View to a Kill","Answer4":"Goldfinger","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which city did Starsky and Hutch fight crime?","CorrectAnswer":"Los Angeles","Answer2":"Dallas","Answer3":"New York","Answer4":"Seattle","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Jack Shepherd is a Dr. in which TV series?","CorrectAnswer":"Lost","Answer2":"Greys Anatomy","Answer3":"E.R.","Answer4":"Quincy","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Zachary Smith is a Dr. in which TV series?","CorrectAnswer":"Lost in space","Answer2":"Greys Anatomy","Answer3":"Lost","Answer4":"Deep Space Nine ","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Alex is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Madagascar","Answer2":"Finding Nemo","Answer3":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","Answer4":"The Lion King","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Melman is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Madagascar","Answer2":"The Aristocats","Answer3":"Finding Nemo","Answer4":"A Bugs Life","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which role was not played by Peter Sellers in the film 'Dr. Strangelove'?","CorrectAnswer":"Major King Kong","Answer2":"Dr. Strangelove","Answer3":"President Merkin Muffley","Answer4":"Capt Mandrake","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following was not a character in Disney's Pirates of the Caribbean?","CorrectAnswer":"Marcus","Answer2":"Jack Sparrow","Answer3":"Elizabeth Swann","Answer4":"Pintel","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Tom Jones plays himself in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Mars Attacks","Answer2":"Independance Day","Answer3":"E.T.","Answer4":"Evolution","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which French city did The French Connection II take place?","CorrectAnswer":"Marseille","Answer2":"Paris","Answer3":"Leon","Answer4":"Montreal","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Frank the Pug is a dog in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Men In Black","Answer2":"Transformers","Answer3":"Back To The Future","Answer4":"101 Dalmatians","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Orion is a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Men In Black","Answer2":"The Aristocats","Answer3":"Breakfast At Tiffany's","Answer4":"Pinocchio","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who played the role of Harry Palmer in film?","CorrectAnswer":"Michael Caine","Answer2":"John Travolta","Answer3":"Paul Newman","Answer4":"Peter Sellers","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Shrek in 'Shrek'?","CorrectAnswer":"Mike Myers","Answer2":"Tom Hanks","Answer3":"Billy Connolly   ","Answer4":"Sean Connery","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Boo is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Monsters, Inc","Answer2":"Tarzan","Answer3":"The Lion King","Answer4":"The Jungle Book","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Fungus is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Monsters, Inc","Answer2":"Shrek","Answer3":"The Jungle Book","Answer4":"A Bugs Life","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Yeti is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Monsters, Inc","Answer2":"Shrek","Answer3":"The Jungle Book","Answer4":"Aladdin","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following was not a character in Disney's Pocahontas?","CorrectAnswer":"Mooky","Answer2":"Flit","Answer3":"Chief Powhatan","Answer4":"Lon","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a guest appearance as Chandler's mother in the TV series 'Friends'?","CorrectAnswer":"Morgan Fairchild","Answer2":"Julia Roberts","Answer3":"Chrissie Hynde","Answer4":"Elizebeth Taylor","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was Simba's father in ","CorrectAnswer":"Mufasa","Answer2":"Sarabi","Answer3":"Scar","Answer4":"Timon","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who did Danger Man work for?","CorrectAnswer":"NATO","Answer2":"UNCLE","Answer3":"CIA","Answer4":"MI6","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"For his role in which film did Robert De Niro learn to play the saxaphone?","CorrectAnswer":"New York, New York","Answer2":"The Deer Hunter","Answer3":"Raging Bull ","Answer4":"Cape Fear","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the friendly vacuum cleaner in the 'Teletubbies' called?","CorrectAnswer":"Nunu","Answer2":"Vunu","Answer3":"Junu","Answer4":"Funu","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the captain of the Yellow Submarine?","CorrectAnswer":"Old Fred","Answer2":"Uncle Arthur","Answer3":"Admiral Halsey","Answer4":"Paul's Grandad","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who directed the film 'JFK'?","CorrectAnswer":"Oliver Stone","Answer2":"Kevin Costner","Answer3":"David Lynch","Answer4":"James Cameron","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which film was not directed by Stanley Kubrick?","CorrectAnswer":"One flew over the cuckoo's nest","Answer2":"The Shining","Answer3":"2001","Answer4":"Dr. Strangelove","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which land did the Blue Meanies invade?","CorrectAnswer":"Pepperland","Answer2":"Saltland","Answer3":"Sugarland","Answer4":"Vinegarland","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Church is a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Pet Semetary","Answer2":"Breakfast At Tiffany's","Answer3":"101 Dalmatians","Answer4":"Men In Black","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"George Darling is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Pan","Answer2":"101 Dalmatians","Answer3":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","Answer4":"Winnie the Pooh","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Nana is a dog in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Pan","Answer2":"The Wizard Of Oz","Answer3":"101 Dalmatians","Answer4":"Dam Busters","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Tiger Lily is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Pan","Answer2":"Pinocchio","Answer3":"Dumbo","Answer4":"101 Dalmatians","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Figaro is a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Pinocchio","Answer2":"Peter Pan","Answer3":"The Wizard Of Oz","Answer4":"Men In Black","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Foulfellow Fox is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Pinocchio","Answer2":"Monsters, Inc","Answer3":"Aristocats","Answer4":"Dumbo","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"When you wish upon a star is from which Disney film?","CorrectAnswer":"Pinocchio","Answer2":"Cinderella","Answer3":"Snow White","Answer4":"Beauty and the Beast","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"John Smith is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Pocahontas","Answer2":"Peter Pan","Answer3":"Tarzan","Answer4":"Dumbo","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of Dr Doolittle's parrot?","CorrectAnswer":"Polynesia","Answer2":"Tuvalu","Answer3":"Nauru","Answer4":"Fiji","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which cartoon character starred in nearly 200 short films between 1933 and 1957?","CorrectAnswer":"Popeye","Answer2":"Mickey Mouse","Answer3":"Sylvester Cat","Answer4":"Topcat","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Dominic Greene was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"Quantum of Solace","Answer2":"From Russia with Love","Answer3":"The Spy who loved me","Answer4":"Diamonds are Forever","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the dog in The Waltons?","CorrectAnswer":"Reckless","Answer2":"Breathless","Answer3":"Feckless","Answer4":"Old Bess","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a guest appearance as Rachel's sister in the TV series 'Friends'?","CorrectAnswer":"Reese Witherspoon","Answer2":"Julia Roberts","Answer3":"Elle Macpherson","Answer4":"Brooke Shields","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who directed the film 'Gladiator'?","CorrectAnswer":"Ridley Scott","Answer2":"James Cameron","Answer3":"George Lucas","Answer4":"Anthony Minghella","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Beatle is in danger of losing a finger in the film Help?","CorrectAnswer":"Ringo","Answer2":"John","Answer3":"Paul","Answer4":"George","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Riff Raff is a character in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Rocky Horror Picture Show","Answer2":"Oliver","Answer3":"Lock Stock and Two Smoking Barrels","Answer4":"Jungle Book","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who directed the Oscar winning film 'A Beautiful Mind'?","CorrectAnswer":"Ron Howard","Answer2":"Peter Jackson","Answer3":"Clint Eastwood","Answer4":"Mel Gibson","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Zazu the hornbill in 'The Lion King'?","CorrectAnswer":"Rowan Atkinson","Answer2":"Woody Allen","Answer3":"Tom Hanks","Answer4":"Mike Myers","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Prince Charming in 'Shrek 2'?","CorrectAnswer":"Rupert Everett","Answer2":"George Clooney","Answer3":"Johnny Depp","Answer4":"Bruce Willis","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Ray Bolger played who in The Wizard of Oz?","CorrectAnswer":"Scarecrow","Answer2":"Tinman","Answer3":"Lion","Answer4":"Wizard","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who lived in Waratah National Park?","CorrectAnswer":"Skippy","Answer2":"ALF","Answer3":"Lassie","Answer4":"Black Beauty","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which of the following is not a character in Disney's Ratatouille?","CorrectAnswer":"Stefanie","Answer2":"Alfredo Linguini","Answer3":"Colette","Answer4":"Emile","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was Norman Bates hobby in the film Psycho?","CorrectAnswer":"stuffing birds","Answer2":"stamp collecting","Answer3":"collecting womens shoes","Answer4":"coin collecting","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Kala is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Tarzan","Answer2":"The Jungle Book","Answer3":"Aladdin","Answer4":"101 Dalmatians","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"In which film do the words 'I love you' save the planet?","CorrectAnswer":"The Fifth Element","Answer2":"Independance Day","Answer3":"Mars Attacks","Answer4":"The Day the Earth Stood Still","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Claude Frollo was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Hunchback of Notre Dame","Answer2":"Jungle Book","Answer3":"Tarzan","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Esmeralda was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Hunchback of Notre Dame","Answer2":"Aristocats","Answer3":"The Little Mermaid","Answer4":"Aladdin","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Tao ia a cat in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Incredible Journey","Answer2":"Men In Black","Answer3":"Aristocats","Answer4":"101 Dalmatians","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Bomb Voyage was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Incredibles","Answer2":"Toy Story","Answer3":"Aladdin","Answer4":"Monsters, Inc","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Dash was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Incredibles","Answer2":"Shrek","Answer3":"Toy Story","Answer4":"Madagascar","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Elastigirl was a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Incredibles","Answer2":"Toy Story","Answer3":"Shrek","Answer4":"Monsters, Inc","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Grey Brother is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Jungle Book","Answer2":"Madagascar","Answer3":"Tarzan","Answer4":"The Lion King","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Kaa is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Jungle Book","Answer2":"Tarzan","Answer3":"Madagascar","Answer4":"The Lion King","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Shanti is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Jungle Book","Answer2":"Tarzan","Answer3":"Madagascar","Answer4":"The Lion King","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Shenzi is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Lion King","Answer2":"The Jungle Book","Answer3":"The Aristocats","Answer4":"Madagascar","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Zazu is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Lion King","Answer2":"Tarzan","Answer3":"Aladdin","Answer4":"The Incredibles","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Evil Manta is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Little Mermaid","Answer2":"Finding Nemo","Answer3":"A Bugs Life","Answer4":"Shrek","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Flotsam is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Little Mermaid","Answer2":"Finding Nemo","Answer3":"Toy Story","Answer4":"Shrek","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Undertow is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Little Mermaid","Answer2":"Finding Nemo","Answer3":"Cars","Answer4":"101 Dalmatians","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which monster role other than Frankenstein's monster was Boris Karloff famous for?","CorrectAnswer":"The Mummy","Answer2":"The Werewolf","Answer3":"Dracula","Answer4":"The Creature from the Black Lagoon","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Stanley Kubrick film is based on a  story by Stephan King?","CorrectAnswer":"The Shining","Answer2":"Eyes Wide Shut","Answer3":"The Killing","Answer4":"Full Metal Jacket","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Jennifer Melfi is a Dr. in which TV series?","CorrectAnswer":"The Sopranos","Answer2":"E.R.","Answer3":"Greys Anatomy","Answer4":"Quincy","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"The line ","CorrectAnswer":"The Wizard of Oz","Answer2":"The Great Escape","Answer3":"Home Alone","Answer4":"Shrek","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Toto is a dog in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"The Wizard Of Oz","Answer2":"Dam Busters","Answer3":"Back To The Future","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What was the name of the evil organisation in 'The man from UNCLE'?","CorrectAnswer":"THRUSH","Answer2":"KAOS","Answer3":"SMERSH","Answer4":"SPECTRE","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Woody in 'Toy Story'?","CorrectAnswer":"Tom Hanks","Answer2":"Bruce Willis","Answer3":"Eddie Murphy","Answer4":"George Clooney","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"What is the name of the Lt. in Star Trek Voyager?","CorrectAnswer":"Tom Paris","Answer2":"Tom Rome","Answer3":"Tom Washington","Answer4":"Tom Canberra","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who had a guest appearance as Dr Richard Burke in the TV series 'Friends'?","CorrectAnswer":"Tom Seeeck","Answer2":"Charlie Sheen","Answer3":"Robin Williams","Answer4":"Ben Stiller","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Mojo is a dog in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Transformers","Answer2":"Men In Black","Answer3":"The Wizard Of Oz","Answer4":"Peter Pan","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"According to advertising, what make of cars were ‘Tested by dummies, driven by the intelligent’?","CorrectAnswer":"Volvo","Answer2":"Ford","Answer3":"Saab","Answer4":"Mercedes","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Judge Doom is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","Answer2":"The Incredibles","Answer3":"Monsters, Inc","Answer4":"Toy Story","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Who was the voice of Shenzi the  female hyena in 'The Lion King'? ","CorrectAnswer":"Whoopee Goldberg","Answer2":"Elizebeth Taylor","Answer3":"Jodie Foster","Answer4":"Paris Hilton","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which film won the first Oscar for best picture ?","CorrectAnswer":"Wings","Answer2":"Mutiny on the Bounty","Answer3":"Grand Hotel","Answer4":"All quiet on the western front","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"Which Bond film does a white convertable Toyota 2000 GT play a high speed role?","CorrectAnswer":"You only live twice","Answer2":"Octopussy","Answer3":"Live and let die","Answer4":"Dr. No","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":2},
{"Question":"How Many Oscars Did The English Patient Win?","CorrectAnswer":"9","Answer2":"5","Answer3":"None","Answer4":"3","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many films did Elvis make?","CorrectAnswer":"33","Answer2":"13","Answer3":"63","Answer4":"7","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"How many people has Rambo liquidated in all four Rambo films?","CorrectAnswer":"220","Answer2":"77","Answer3":"460","Answer4":"1.221","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which year did Sesame Street have its US premiere?","CorrectAnswer":"1969","Answer2":"1974","Answer3":"1980","Answer4":"1962","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Max Zorin was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"A View to a Kill","Answer2":"The Spy who loved me","Answer3":"Quantum of Solace","Answer4":"Dr No","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Tom Jones plays himself in which film?","CorrectAnswer":"Agnes Brown","Answer2":"Erin Brockovich","Answer3":"Bridget Jones Diary","Answer4":"Tess of the d'Urbervilles","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the first feature length British cartoon?","CorrectAnswer":"Animal Farm","Answer2":"Lord of the Rings","Answer3":"When the wind blows","Answer4":"The curse of the Were Rabbit","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Where does the film The Thing take place?","CorrectAnswer":"Antarctic","Answer2":"Arctic","Answer3":"Greenland","Answer4":"Siberia","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who invaded Pepperland?","CorrectAnswer":"Blue Meanies","Answer2":"Green Meanies","Answer3":"Black Meanies","Answer4":"Grey Meanies","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"This is war. This is not a game of cricket","CorrectAnswer":"Bridge on the river Kwai","Answer2":"The Longest Day","Answer3":"The Hill","Answer4":"The Battle of Britain","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which brand of cigarette did James Bond smoke?","CorrectAnswer":"Chesterfield","Answer2":"Rothmans","Answer3":"Woodbine","Answer4":"Benson and Hedges","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"If one takes inflation into account, which 1960's film was the most expensive film ever made? ","CorrectAnswer":"Cleopatra","Answer2":"The Great Escape","Answer3":"The Sound of Music","Answer4":"Zulu","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was John Drake better known as?","CorrectAnswer":"Danger Man","Answer2":"Superman","Answer3":"6 million dollar man","Answer4":"Iron Man","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the name of the vehicle driven by the Munsters?","CorrectAnswer":"Dragula","Answer2":"Munster mobile","Answer3":"Christine","Answer4":"Go Gone mobile","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first actress to recieve 1 million dollars for a film?","CorrectAnswer":"Elizebeth Taylor","Answer2":"Katherine Hepburn","Answer3":"Audrey Hepburn","Answer4":"Kim Bassinger","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What kind of car did Starsky and Hutch drive?","CorrectAnswer":"Ford Torino","Answer2":"Ford Mustang","Answer3":"Ford Escort","Answer4":"Ford Capri","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Red Grant was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"From Russia with Love","Answer2":"Dr No","Answer3":"Thunderball","Answer4":"Casino Royale","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Rosa Klebb was a bad girl in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"From Russia with Love","Answer2":"Dr No","Answer3":"You only live twice","Answer4":"Quantum of Solace","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which British TV cook was once called ","CorrectAnswer":"Graham Kerr","Answer2":"Jamie Oliver","Answer3":"Gordon Ramsay","Answer4":"Ainsley Harriott","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor played the unhinged captain in the film 'The Caine Mutiny'?","CorrectAnswer":"Humphrey Bogart","Answer2":"Clark Gable","Answer3":"Spencer Tracy","Answer4":"James Cagney","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor gave his Porsche Spyder the appropriate nickname 'little bastard'?","CorrectAnswer":"James Dean","Answer2":"Paul Newman","Answer3":"Steve McQueen","Answer4":"Woody Allen","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the oldest woman to receive the Best Actress Oscar?","CorrectAnswer":"Jessica Tandy","Answer2":"Cher","Answer3":"Liz Taylor","Answer4":"Katherine Hepburn","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Franz Sanchez was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"Licence to Kill","Answer2":"Tomorrow Never Dies","Answer3":"Moonraker","Answer4":"Thunderball","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who is the only actress to have won an Oscar for playing a man?","CorrectAnswer":"Linda Hunt","Answer2":"Cate Blanchett","Answer3":"Maggie Smith","Answer4":"Liz Taylor","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which sci-fi film would you find a robot named BOX?","CorrectAnswer":"Logans RUN","Answer2":"Terminator","Answer3":"Alien","Answer4":"Hitchhikers Guide To The Galaxy","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which film does Dustin Hoffman play the frightened character Babe Levy?","CorrectAnswer":"Marathon Man","Answer2":"All The Presidents Men","Answer3":"Tootsie","Answer4":"Rain Man","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is the name of the robot in the sci-fi classic Metropolis?","CorrectAnswer":"Maria","Answer2":"Betty","Answer3":"Dot","Answer4":"Hazel","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Where is the spaceship from in the film Quatermass and Pit?","CorrectAnswer":"Mars","Answer2":"Venus","Answer3":"Neptune","Answer4":"Earth","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"'Goodbye Farewell and Amen' was the final episode of which TV series?","CorrectAnswer":"MASH","Answer2":"Dallas","Answer3":"Friends","Answer4":"The Muppet Show","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor has not played the role of Jack Ryan in film?","CorrectAnswer":"Matt Damon","Answer2":"Harrison Ford","Answer3":"Alec Baldwin","Answer4":"Ben Affleck","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the name of Daniel's indian friend in the TV series 'Daniel Boone'?","CorrectAnswer":"Mingo","Answer2":"Bingo","Answer3":"Ringo","Answer4":"Dingo","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Mickey Mouse started life with another name, what was it?","CorrectAnswer":"Mortimer","Answer2":"Martin","Answer3":"Klaus","Answer4":"Walter","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which movie did Jim Broadbent play the character Harold Zidler?","CorrectAnswer":"Moulin Rouge","Answer2":"We Were Soldiers","Answer3":"Fargo","Answer4":"Sorority Boys","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which cartoonist created Alfred E. Newman?","CorrectAnswer":"Norman Mingo","Answer2":"Tex Avery","Answer3":"Jim Davis","Answer4":"Fritz Frelang","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Kamal Khan was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"Octopussy","Answer2":"A View to a Kill","Answer3":"Live and Let Die","Answer4":"Licence to Kill","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which film does 007 marry Tracy di Vicenzo?","CorrectAnswer":"On Her Majesty's Secret Service","Answer2":"Goldfinger","Answer3":"Casino Royale","Answer4":"You Only Live Twice","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What is Briggs code number in The Top Secret Life of Edgar Briggs?","CorrectAnswer":"OO14","Answer2":"OO77","Answer3":"OO69","Answer4":"OOO7","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In the film A Hard Days Night, who has a 'very clean' grandad?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul","Answer2":"Ringo","Answer3":"John","Answer4":"George","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which actor did not play a captain in an 'Airport' film?","CorrectAnswer":"Paul Newman","Answer2":"Jack Lemmon","Answer3":"Dean Martin","Answer4":"Charlton Heston ","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Who was the first actor to receive a Best Actor Oscar posthumously?","CorrectAnswer":"Peter Finch","Answer2":"Marlon Brando","Answer3":"Paul Newman","Answer4":"Charlie Chaplin","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the name of the secret organisation in the TV series U.F.O. ?","CorrectAnswer":"SHADO","Answer2":"PHOENIX","Answer3":"KAOS","Answer4":"SPECTRE","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was Arthur Jefferson's stage name?","CorrectAnswer":"Stan Laurel","Answer2":"Harry Houdini","Answer3":"Boy George","Answer4":"Fred Astaire","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What was the name of 'Lucky Jack' Aubrey's ship in the film Master and Commander?","CorrectAnswer":"Surprise","Answer2":"Acheron","Answer3":"Mermaid","Answer4":"Eagle","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"In which film do the words ","CorrectAnswer":"The 5th Element","Answer2":"Mars Attacks","Answer3":"Independance Day","Answer4":"The Day After Tomorrow","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Emilio Largo was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"Thunderball","Answer2":"From Russia with Love","Answer3":"Dr No","Answer4":"The Man with the Golden Gun","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Elliot Carver was a bad guy in which Bond film?","CorrectAnswer":"Tomorrow Never Dies","Answer2":"Live and Let Die","Answer3":"Casino Royale","Answer4":"A View to a Kill","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Where was the Dracula actor Bela Lugosi born?","CorrectAnswer":"Transsylvania","Answer2":"Italy","Answer3":"Eygpt","Answer4":"Greenland","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"What kind of car did The Saint drive?","CorrectAnswer":"Volvo","Answer2":"Rolls Royce","Answer3":"MG","Answer4":"Triumph","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"James Bond was searching for what kind of airplane in 'Thunderball'?","CorrectAnswer":"Vulkan","Answer2":"B-52","Answer3":"707","Answer4":"Piper Cub","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which Paulie is a mafia gangster in The Sopranos?","CorrectAnswer":"Walnuts","Answer2":"Almonds","Answer3":"Peanuts","Answer4":"Pistachios","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Which cartoonist created Woody Woodpecker?","CorrectAnswer":"Walter Lanz","Answer2":"Fritz Frelang","Answer3":"Tex Avery","Answer4":"Steve Ditko","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3},
{"Question":"Eddie Valiant is a character in which animated film?","CorrectAnswer":"Who Framed Roger Rabbit","Answer2":"Peter Pan","Answer3":"Cinderella","Answer4":"Cars","Category":"TV & Film","Difficulty":3}]